<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>Visual Albums</title>
            <author xml:id="al.su">Sultan Aldabal</author>
            <date>October 7, 2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p><situation>Visual Albums such as Kanye West’s Runway and the Beatles’ A Hard Day
                        Night have put the music industry on it’s head.</situation>
                    <argument type="main">As a genre, Visual Albums brings the writer closer to the
                        reader in a way that exceeds other genres such as: music videos and songs.
                        This genre utilizes it’s uptakes, scenes, and situations to bring the two
                        together.</argument>
                </p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara><context>The values that this genre focuses on is to be the best in your
                    field, as most artists release a song by itself, others go the extra mile by
                    making a music video, and only a select few go even further and release a visual
                    album.</context> The scene and situation help us understand the story more
                through the genre that is being used. <scene>Using Beyoncé’s Lemonade as a well
                    established scene from this genre, you can see the impact of her choosing visual
                    albums as her platform.</scene>
                <participants>This genre helped Beyoncé reach out to her fans in a much more direct
                    way,</participants>
                <situation>which created a long discussion about some of the situations that were
                    exposed in Lemonade, such as the very famous lyrics from the song Sorry “He only
                    want me when I'm not there. He better call Becky with the good hair”.
                </situation></bodyPara>
            <bodyPara><participants>Singers, artists, poets, and public speakers are not the only
                    people who use this genre. There are also the directors and musical engineers
                    who in charge of development and upgrading the elements within the
                    genre.</participants> Going back to the previously mentioned situation, Lemonade
                featured the Somali-English poet Warsaw Shire in one of it’s chapters.
                    <context>Warsaw Shire uses the genre of Visual Albums to input her own personal
                    situation which many people including Beyoncé related to, this demonstrates how
                    she uses her own uptake of combining her poetry with the sub-genre of
                    video.</context> People who do not have the talent or ideas to make a visual
                albums can not use this genre, however they make up a vast majority of readers of
                this genre.</bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>Visual Albums invite many different uptakes that help the artist connect to as
                many people as possible. These uptakes include the use of song and video, the use of
                old tribal dances in a contemporary music video, and the combination of poetry and
                speech with visuals. <situation>The use of song and video together encompasses the
                    genres of visual albums and music videos, as both are very similar concepts.
                    Using this uptake offers a more in-depth story that the artist is trying to
                    convey to the audience.</situation>
                <scene>Going back to Lemonade, Beyoncé uses visuals eluding to a feelings of sadness
                    and betrayal in the song Pray You Catch Me to convey her situation of being
                    cheated on.</scene>
                <situation>The use of old tribal dances and contemporary music as an uptake gives
                    the artist a way to demonstrate their background and culture to a much bigger
                    platform of readers.</situation><scene>
                    <citation source=" #Ori">Beyoncé mixes the two together in the song Sorry by
                        performing an old tribal dance called The Sacred Art of Ori, which showed
                        her own culture and background</citation>.</scene>
                <situation>Last but not least, the use of spoken word and visuals gives a deeper
                    understanding of what the speaker is trying to convey, or the artists’
                    interpretation of the different speakers they use.</situation><scene>
                    <citation source="#Malclom">Beyoncé uses an excerpt from a speech given by
                        Malcolm X in May 22, 1962 with visuals of various black women to emphasize
                        the importance of the speech to the black community and especially to black
                        women. </citation></scene></bodyPara>
            <bodyPara><argument type="supporting">The roles of the writer and reader are very
                    important in the success of this genre. The writer’s main role is to create
                    something that will have a long lasting impact on the readers, the longer the
                    impact the more successful the artist becomes.</argument>
                <scene>Other roles that the writer has to keep in mind is making an album that talks
                    about the current social issues that are plaguing the writers’ life. Beyoncé
                    succeeded in fulfilling the roles twice, once in 2013 with the album BEYONCÉ and
                    the next in 2016 with Lemonade.</scene> Our roles as readers however is to
                appreciate the time and effort taken by the writer to complete their project and to
                express our views of what was read, weather it was negative or positive. </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara/>
            <concl>
                <p>
                    <argument type="supporting">Visual Albums as a genre brings the writer closer to
                        the reader in a way that exceeds other genres such as: music videos and
                        songs. This genre utilizes it’s uptakes, scenes, and situations to bring the
                        two together. The values that this genre articulates encourage the writers
                        to connect to their readers. The writers’ exclusivity and roles also put an
                        emphasis on trying to relate to the majority and connect with them as
                        well.</argument></p>
                <p/>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl xml:id="Ori">Embuscado, Rain. "Artist and Beyoncé Collaborator Laolu Senbanjo
                    Is an Overnight Media Sensation." Artnet News. N.p., 2016. Web. 07 Oct.
                    2016.</bibl>
                <bibl xml:id="Warsan">Hess, Amanda. "Warsan Shire, the Woman Who Gave Poetry to
                    Beyoncé’s ‘Lemonade’." The New York Times. N.p., 27 Apr. 2016. Web. 6 Oct.
                    2016..</bibl>
                <bibl xml:id="Malclom">Rodriguez, Mathew. "Here's the Malcolm X Speech About Black
                    Women Beyoncé Sampled in 'Lemonade'" Mic. N.p., 24 Apr. 2016. Web. 07 Oct.
                    2016.</bibl>

            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="mi.as"> Ashwin Misra</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Good, catchy start to the introduction to keep the reader engaged and interested in
                the analysis. It’s good that you provided some background to the topic. Slightly
                awkward layout of the introduction, should all be in one paragraph. Good referencing
                from a particular song and video, shows that you have knowledge in the topic. How does
                Beyoncé making a visual album help her connect with her fans in a more direct way?
                Explain (para 2 last sentence). Consider expanding on how the scene and situation
                helps us understand the story more through the genre that is being used. Maybe
                define uptake in terms of your genre and in light of your analysis for us to
                understand the concept better rather than its generic meaning. Valid use of genre in
                most of the essay. Would be a good idea if you briefly describe a music video so
                that the reader doesn’t have to watch it to understand what you mean by feelings of
                sadness and betrayal. I like how you mentioned that Beyoncé used old tribal dances
                and contemporary music as an uptake and explained it. Except for the introduction, I
                like how you’ve structured your paragraphs with new ideas/ topics in each paragraph.
                Good job in linking your new ideas to ideas mentioned previously. Valid points made
                throughout the essay. I like how you elaborated on the importance of the roles of
                both the reader and the writer. Good understanding of the deeper implications of her
                Visual Albums and song lyrics. Would be a good idea to replace “uses an excerpt
                from” to “alludes to” in the fourth paragraph. Another note, “eluding to a feelings”
                delete the “a”. Overall I enjoyed the essay as it is about a contemporary artist and
                her personal and profession life. Good use of literary terms and key terms such as
                genre and uptake (as discussed during class). Would like it if you considered
                changing the points mentioned above. .</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
