<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title/>
            <author xml:id=""/>
            <date/>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p>The discourse community <note type="peer"> Which discourse community? For what? The reader is likely to be confused if you simply start stating that a bunch of assertions about something without saying what the something is.</note>is made up of individuals or groups like bloggers, readers, the audience, fashion design students and designers that are interested in the subject. <note type="peer"> Again, what is the subject? Clarity needed.</note> The common goal is to share their love and passion in the industry of fashion. Fortunately, the specific genre of Question and Answer <note type="peer"> Question and answer? As in readers sending in letters? Interviews with celebrities or well known experts in the field?</note> fulfills this roll by taking the ideas expressed in the designs to a written text. This particular genre can fulfill the niche of being an informative resource to the discourse community. However, due to the exclusiveness of who may participate in this genre, it cannot be as an open communication. <note type="peer"> Who is allowed to participate? The reader doesn't know off-handedly.</note>The exclusiveness of the genre stems from the fact that designers are protective of their designs, ideas and inspirations so they only wish to interface <note type="peer"> Interface may not be the best choice of word here. Speak with? Discuss their designs with?</note> with official interviewers. <note type="peer">In regards to my previous note, stating that the designers only wish to speak to official interviewers first would be helpful for the reader to understand that the genre is only open to a few.</note> Often at times each question and answer will only reach a specific portion of the discourse community because of the place that they are published. <note type="peer">What is the argument you are trying to make? You've stated sonme assertions concerning the genre and the community. However, you have not stated an argument concerning either as of yet.</note></p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara>For example, the Question and Answer with Kiel James Patrick was published on a website tailored towards men’s interest. Hence, the members of the community that would end up accessing the article are young men. While fashion is the true expression of the designer’s voice that can transcend language barriers, the written contexts of the industry remains the Question and Answer, press releasing.<note type="peer"> Is the Question and Answer bit a segment? An official press release? Clarity is needed. It may be helpful to assume that the reader knows very little about the subject at hand.</note> The goal that this genre fills is to support the discourse community by producing ideas to common consumers. Question and Answer represents an efficient way to transfer these ideas to a lot of people in a short amount of time and space. The Question and Answer genre not only flexible and unique but also an efficient model that can spread information to a wide range of consumers of the discourse communities. <note type="peer"> Is this your main argument? Is this what you want to say about the genre?</note> </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>Bold, vibrant, and glamorous are three words that come to mind when describing a fashion magazine. The term Vogue and Elle are a staple in every fashionista's vocabulary, but what are the differences between the two magazines? They are both are synonymous of fashion in every detail. Although the similarities are quite obvious, the differences are arduous to observe. Elle is still known as the worlds best selling fashion magazine, despite the staggering age difference between the two. Vogue pitches its articles to an older audience, while Elle is accessible to a wider range of age groups. Of course, if you are a true fashionista or at least an aspiring one, you will buy Vogue. <note type="peer"> Where is the evidence for this? If you make a claim, it is helpful to have evidence from sources to back it up, or to exhaustively go through reasons as to why your claim is true yourself.</note>The editors of these fashion magazines are trying to introduce their target audience to the beauty of the world that fashion has to offer. They do this by using big catchy titles, lots of bright pictures, and famous celebrities that will hook the reader and reel them in. <note type="peer"> How does this connect to the Question and Answer genre? Or is the genre you are considering the fashion magazine? At this point, this analysis feels a little bit disjointed, since you have not made the connections between the Question and Answer genre and the women's fashion magazines.</note> </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>When creating a fashion magazine the editors are trying to appeal to a certain target audience. Each style of writing and topic has an audience that they are attempting to connect with. They use phrases and words that their readers can relate to. Fashion magazines have a very broad range of readers that they are trying to reach. Each fashion magazine strives to get the attention of a certain. Depending on the desired audience the magazine will cater its image to appeal to them. <note type="peer"> So far, this is all claims. Where is the evidence?</note></bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>One creates a fashion magazine with the intention to introduce new and up coming trends to their customers. In order to keep up with the trending world of fashion these editors must constantly be doing research. They fly across the world to see different cultures and designers and try to incorporate their style or combine it with two different cultures. Editors of fashion magazines must make sure they are always ahead of the curve. <note type="peer"> Again, more concrete evidence would make this much stronger. Maybe bring in a specific example, such as an interview with a well known fashion magazine editor talking about what working in the industry is like. </note> </bodyPara>
            <concl> <p>Once the editor has collected his or her data they must begin assembling the magazine in a way that will engage their customers. Their goal is to introduce their customers to the fashions all around the world, new trends, and classics. Fashion magazines aren’t trying to sell its audience everything in its magazine. Instead the editor is attempting to open the minds of its customers and expose them to new ideas. Some pieces in the magazine the customer may fall in love with, while others they wouldn’t be caught dead in. The editor typically writes a biased review of the clothes with maybe a little bit of their own opinion. <note type="peer"> What makes you say it is biased? How does this relate to, for example, the Question and Answer genre? Elle and Vogue magazines targeting different audiences?</note> The idea is not for them to make up the readers mind on the clothes but simply introduce the consumer to it. A fashion magazine is a mode that provides their customers an actual glimpse of what they are looking to purchase and how to best introduce them to the latest exciting styles that the fashion world has to offer. To help them do this they use colors, and article titles that would appeal to their customers, choosing products that will expand the style of their target audience.<note type="peer"> How does the life of an editor relate to the genre analysis? What is the genre being analysed?</note> <note type="peer">No citations? No sources? This analysis would me much stronger with proper sources. </note> <note type="peer"> As a conclusion, how does this tie the rest of this together? It doesn't quite effectively conclude the paper. </note></p>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>citation here</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="ch.an">Anders Chen</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="ch,an">
            <p> This paper talks about the Question and Answer genre and covers the differences between both Elle and Vogue magazines. Aditionally, it covers the life of an editor. To be truthful, I am not entirely sure what is being evaluated here. There doesn't seem to be a main focus of the piece, as it jumps from the Question and Answer genre to Elle and Vogue to editors, without tying each subject back to the rest. I'm not entirely sure why each section is relevant, even in relation to the rest. Personally, I would recommend focusing on either the effectiveness and uses of the Question and Answer genre using specific examples, or the differences between women's fashion magazines using specific examples. As it stands, there is no evidence being used to back up claims being made within the paper. Not a single paragraph has anything requiring sources. Your claims would be made much stronger with evidence. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
