<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>How Genres Work in the Gaming Community: What People Have to Say About
                Hearthstone</title>
            <author xml:id="bu.an">Andrew T. Burcham</author>
            <date>October 7th, 2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p><context>Video games have been an ever growing industry ever since the 1970's
                        with the release of Atari's <q>Atari 2600</q> in 1977. Ever since then,
                        video games have been rapidly advancing technology and supplying thousands
                        all around the world with an immeasurable source of entertainment. Today,
                        video games have finally begun to launch themselves into the public eye with
                        gamers being able to make a living off playing the games they love and
                        compete in massive competitions for millions of dollars in rewards. These
                        competitions, lovingly called <q>eSports</q> by many, have been the source
                        of serious debate amongst gamers for the past couple years for many
                        different games. One such game is an online collectable card game known as
                            <q>Hearthstone: Heroes of Warcraft</q></context>.</p>
                <p><context>Hearthstone is a game developed by Blizzard Entertainment, made to be an
                        easy to learn and simple card game for people to play.</context>
                    <scene>However, this design philosophy to appeal to a casual gaming audience has
                        spurred the more competitive players across the internet to speak out
                        against Blizzard's approach to the game, in favor for a more serious
                        competition to reward more skilled players. <situation>Those who have voiced
                            their concerns have done so using a very common genre in the gaming
                            community known as a</situation></scene>
                    <genre>gaming article</genre>. <argument type="main">When one analyzes this
                        genre, one can begin to see how their uptake affects both a video game's
                        community and the game they discuss as well.</argument>
                    <q>Three Years In And 'Hearthstone' Still Doesn't Nerf Cards Fast Enough</q> is
                    a gaming article by Paul Tassi which serves as an excellent example of how this
                    phenomena occurs.</p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara>Looking at Tassi's article, one immediately notice the author's perspective.
                    <participants>Because of the huge variety of video games available, it is very
                    typical for the author to be a very passionate player of said game, or of video
                    games in general, and to write alone.</participants> As such, it is very easy to
                see reoccurring patterns in many different gaming articles. <aesthetics>Most will be
                    formatted in a similar way: Simple black text with a white background on a
                    website available for anyone to read. Most use short paragraphs to quickly
                    articulate their points, and between these paragraphs are images of the cards or
                    the game-play being talked about, whether it be directly mentioned or just an
                    example of whatever topic is at hand.</aesthetics> Also, most will use the
                game's jargon, <participants>inviting fellow players of the game, meanwhile
                    excluding those who have never played. As such, they draw relatively the same
                    audience comprised of fellow competitive players who play and follow the
                    game.</participants> As with a lot of gaming articles, the article is an opinion
                piece; combining the personal beliefs of the author and his or her experiences with
                the game. Specifically, this article's subject is how the developers of Hearthstone,
                Blizzard, are not doing an adequate enough job with balancing their game. He
                expresses his frustration about Hearthstone's problems and Blizzard's pattern of
                changing the game. <q>Eventually, changes were made to specific cards to make those
                    dominating builds less viable, or destroy them completely, but it took forever
                    then, and it’s taking forever now, where the problems seem even more obvious
                    </q><citation source="#Tassi">("Three Years In And 'Hearthstone' Still Doesn't
                    Nerf Cards Fast Enough"</citation>). Tassi here is clearly quite tired of how
                Blizzard operates its game and is trying to appeal to the audience that Hearthstone
                is in desperate need of a change of management if it wishes to keep its player base. </bodyPara>

            <bodyPara>But the key to this, and other gaming articles, is the effect it has on the
                game's community. <situation>Due to the heavily subjective nature of the genre, its
                    uptake can radically shift between two very different outcomes. One is that the
                    readers will disagree and argue against what the author is saying. This does not
                    lead to much except discourse within the community, which varies on the
                    popularity of the second outcome. The second, and most important outcome, is
                    when the audience agrees with what the author is saying and goes out of their
                    way to inform others, including the original developers of the game.</situation>
                <argument type="supporting">By sharing the article around with friends and other
                    players, soon enough the article becomes a guideline for how the game should
                    continue to develop. This is especially effective during times where the players
                    are not deriving the much enjoyment from the game or the game has a few glaring
                    issues hampering it.</argument>
                <evidence>Hearthstone was at this very point at the time Tassi was writing his
                    article, as he explains, </evidence><q>I like Hearthstone, but I do not like
                    playing games, seeing a class, and knowing there’s about an 80% chance I’m going
                    to lose. I like Hearthstone, but I do not like playing or playing against a
                    single card that can often decide an entire game on a coin flip</q>
                <citation source="#Tassi">("Three Years In And 'Hearthstone' Still Doesn't Nerf
                    Cards Fast Enough")</citation>. <evidence>In his piece he offers some changes
                    that Blizzard could make in order to improve the issues, and soon enough the
                    entire competitive Hearthstone community was nearly rioting for these changes to
                    be made. Tassi certainly was not the first one to write about this issue,
                    however, but his article really demonstrates the mood and frustration of the
                    community at the time.</evidence> Finally, gaming articles also tie into several
                different genres, such as <genre>video game reviews, blog posts, forum discussions,
                    and so on</genre>, as its topics and format are so simple to use and understand.
                This pervasiveness is a big reason why it is so effective when it comes to reaching
                out to the audience.</bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p>Here is where video games, in recent years, make themselves completely different
                    from any other form of media. <argument type="supporting">At a certain point,
                        the developers will actually step in and make the changes the community
                        recommends. Improving the quality of the product so more and more people can
                        get enjoyment from it.</argument>
                    <evidence>After the massive fan outcry and onslaught of gaming articles,
                        including Tassi's own work, Blizzard finally decided to change a couple
                        cards within the game that were frequently protested against, many of which
                        were the same cards Tassi was displeased with. This re-balancing of the game
                        was the uptake of gaming articles</evidence>, which often influenced several
                    other genres related to Hearthstone such as <genre>community discussion, forum
                        posts, reviews, and videos on the subject.</genre> What these articles do in
                    the grand scheme of Hearthstone and many other game's development is that they
                    subtly shape what the game is to become. And after some time, more problems will
                    be found with the game, and the whole process will start over. This process of
                    community revision has been how many popular games have survived for so long. It
                    all comes back to a video game's primary purpose, to entertain the player. If a
                    large enough subset of players is not entertained, then something needs to be
                    done or else the game is not successful. Luckily, Hearthstone has a massive fan
                    base of creative and passionate players who push Blizzard to make Hearthstone
                    constantly better and better.</p>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl xml:id="Tassi">Tassi, Paul. "Three Years In And 'Hearthstone' Still Doesn't
                    Nerf Cards Fast Enough." Forbes.com, Forbes, 26 Sept. 2016,
                    http://www.forbes.com/sites/insertcoin/2016/09/21/its-been-three-years-and-hearthstone-still-doesnt-nerf-cards-fast-enough/#6b5d306f2634.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will go here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
