<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>How Genres Work in the Gaming Community: What People Have to Say About
                Hearthstone</title>
            <author xml:id="bu.an">Andrew T. Burcham</author>
            <date>October 7th, 2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p>Video games have been an ever growing industry ever since the 1970's with the
                    release of Atari's <q>Atari 2600</q> in 1977. Ever since then, video games have
                    been rapidly advancing technology and supplying thousands all around the world
                    with an immeasurable source of entertainment. Today, video games have finally
                    begun to launch themselves into the public eye with gamers being able to make a
                    living off playing the games they love and compete in massive competitions for
                    millions of dollars in rewards. These competitions, lovingly called
                        <q>eSports</q> by many, have been the source of serious debate amongst
                    gamers for the past couple years for many different games. One such game is an
                    online collectable card game known as <q>Hearthstone: Heroes of
                    Warcraft</q>.</p>
                <p>Hearthstone is a game developed by Blizzard Entertainment, made to be an easy to
                    learn and simple card game for people to play. However, this design philosophy
                    to appeal to a casual gaming audience has spurred the more competitive players
                    across the internet to speak out against Blizzard's approach to the game, in
                    favor for a more serious competition to reward more skilled players. Those who
                    have voiced their concerns have done so using a very common genre in the gaming
                    community known as a <genre>gaming article</genre>. <argument type="main">When
                        one analyzes this genre, one can begin to see how their uptake affects both
                        a video game's community and the game they discuss as well.</argument> For
                    this analysis, two such gaming articles have been chosen to analyze to
                    demonstrate how this genre can have such an effect: <q>Three Years In And
                        'Hearthstone' Still Doesn't Nerf Cards Fast Enough</q> by Paul Tassi and
                        <q>Blizzard Is Finally Making Hearthstone Less Random</q> by James
                    Duggan.</p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara><context>An important piece of information to note about these two articles is
                    that, in between their publishing dates, Blizzard released a significant change
                    to many of the problems talked about in them.</context>
                <situation>Tassi's article is an analysis of what needed to be changed, whereas
                    Duggan's article is a reaction to the changes made and what could be further
                    improved.</situation> Despite all this, it is still very easy to see the
                patterns and structure of this genre.<sim>
                    <aesthetics>The two articles are both very similar in how they are formatted.
                        Simple black text with a white background on a website available for anyone
                        to read. Both use short paragraphs to quickly articulate their points, and
                        between these paragraphs are images of the cards or the game being talked
                        about</aesthetics>, whether it be directly mentioned or just an example of
                    whatever topic is at hand. Both authors are very clearly passionate players of
                    Hearthstone and primarily use the game's jargon, inviting fellow players of
                    Hearthstone while excluding those who have never played. <participants>Because
                        of this, they draw relatively the same audience comprised of fellow
                        competitive players who play and follow the game.</participants> Finally,
                    both articles have the same subject: A critique of the health of the competitive
                    aspect of Hearthstone.</sim></bodyPara>
            <bodyPara><diff>What differs between these two articles is the perspective the author is
                    speaking from and the uptake these two articles take.</diff> In Tassi's piece,
                he speaks much more about his experiences playing Hearthstone recently. He expresses
                his frustration about Hearthstone's problems and Blizzard's pattern of changing the
                game. <q>Eventually, changes were made to specific cards to make those dominating
                    builds less viable, or destroy them completely, but it took forever then, and
                    it’s taking forever now, where the problems seem even more obvious</q>
                <citation source="#Tassi">("Three Years In And 'Hearthstone' Still Doesn't Nerf
                    Cards Fast Enough")</citation>. Tassi here is clearly quite tired of how
                Blizzard operates its game and is trying to appeal to the audience that Hearthstone
                is in desperate need of a change of management if it wishes to keep its player base.
                He lists several problem cards and decks that make the game not enjoyable in his
                eyes. <diff>Meanwhile, Duggan's article is much more optimistic</diff> since it was
                written after Blizzard did make some major changes. <q>The nerfs to Yogg Saron and
                    Tuskar Totemic could be much more than a simple reaction to player feedback,
                    they may in fact represent the start of a design precedent to reduce the impact
                    of random effects on competitive play</q>
                <citation source="#Duggan">("Blizzard Is Finally Making Hearthstone Less
                    Random")</citation>. <q>Nerf</q> here means a change made by the developers to
                lower the strength of a certain elements in the game. <diff>Instead of calling for
                    the audience to put Hearthstone's designer's heads on a pike, it boldly predicts
                    the managerial change Hearthstone needed.</diff> In a way, telling the
                competitively-minded audience to settle down. <diff>Unlike Tassi, who is speaking
                    from experience, Duggan speaks more about game design theory, and singles out
                    what he believes is specifically wrong with the game, randomness, and what the
                    designers are doing to curb it.</diff>
            </bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p><scene>What these articles do in the grand scheme of Hearthstone's development is
                        that they subtly shape what the game is to become. After the massive fan
                        outcry and onslaught of gaming articles, including Tassi's own work,
                        Blizzard finally decided to change a couple cards within the game that were
                        frequently protested against. This re-balancing of the game was the uptake
                        of gaming articles, which often influenced several other genres related to
                        Hearthstone such as community discussion, forum posts, reviews, and videos
                        on the subject.</scene> And now, Duggan's message of positivity has begun to
                    reach the frenzied community, making everyone excited to see what Blizzard has
                    to offer in the next expansion. This process of community revision has been how
                    many popular games have survived for so long. It all comes back to a video
                    game's primary purpose, to entertain the player. If a large enough subset of
                    players is not entertained, then something needs to be done or else the game is
                    not successful. Luckily, Hearthstone has a massive fan base of creative and
                    passionate players who push Blizzard to make Hearthstone constantly better and
                    better.</p>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl xml:id="Tassi">Tassi, Paul. "Three Years In And 'Hearthstone' Still Doesn't
                    Nerf Cards Fast Enough." Forbes.com, Forbes, 26 Sept. 2016,
                    http://www.forbes.com/sites/insertcoin/2016/09/21/its-been-three-years-and-hearthstone-still-doesnt-nerf-cards-fast-enough/#6b5d306f2634.</bibl>
                <bibl xml:id="Duggan">Duggan, James. "Blizzard Is Finally Making Hearthstone Less
                    Random." Ign.com, IGN, 29 Sept. 2016,
                    http://www.ign.com/articles/2016/09/29/blizzard-is-finally-making-hearthstone-less-random.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will go here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
