<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title></title>
            <author xml:id="Anders Chen"></author>
            <date></date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p>Much of what has been discussed within this class so far largely concerns rather serious genres. The choice of a song from a children’s show was, then, an attempt to break down something that I assumed would have a bit more levity to it. However, Here Comes a Thought, written and composed by Rebecca Sugar, surprised me in the fact that, despite my initial thoughts, it is rather serious in its purpose. It is a song that furthers the story, as well as character development, much like every other song produced for shows. Yet, it is also an effort to teach the audience something that can be very helpful to people of all ages.</p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara>Between the episode’s name, Mindful Education, as well as the lyrics of the song, urging the listener to “take a moment and find yourself”, the mentor figure of the series, Garnet, is seen teaching the technique of mindfulness, sometimes known as mindfulness meditation. Mindfulness, according to UC Berkeley, deals with acceptance through having <citation>“our thoughts tune into what we’re sensing in the present moment rather than rehashing the past or imagining the future”</citation>. This segment is designed to show that these techniques can help. Through this, for the first time in the episode, the young girl, Connie begins to accept and acknowledge her own emotions concerning her accidental injury of another student. The glowing butterflies within the scene, the thoughts, burst out of her bag as if through their own will. Although she has attempted to bottle up these emotions since the beginning of the episode, she is once again forced to relive her own memories and guilt. It is with Garnet’s reminder to, once again, “take a moment and ask yourself if this is how we fall apart”, as well as her own use of the repeated mantra “but it’s not”, that she begins to calm down and accept her own remorse over what happened, allowing herself to cry. Only after this strong moment of catharsis do the swarming, troubling thoughts blow away, signifying that taking the time to calmly examine your own thoughts can allow you to step back from the edge of panic and stop yourself from overreacting. This segment visually draws people in and, for older members of the audience perhaps, asks them to revisit their own similar experiences and reconsider how they handled it. For all, however, this teaches a very valuable life lesson regardless of whether the audience uses or does not use the specific techniques associated with mindfulness meditation.</bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>This message is further brought home to the audience through the way in which it is told. Through the first half of the song, Ruby and Sapphire, who physically and mentally combine to form the mentor, Garnet, are shown struggling with their own troubled thoughts and emotions. While those problems remain vague and aren’t shown, it lends credibility to the practice of mindfulness by demonstrating that it is something that a cherished and respected authority figure also uses. By demonstrating that these characters have managed to find greater peace with themselves and their past actions through mindfulness meditation, the episode very openly seems to suggest that it is something that the audience sitting at home could try, even if the technique wasn’t blatantly, specifically mentioned. By demonstrating the method and displaying it in a very positive light, the show attempts to convince others to do this themselves likely much more effectively than it would have had mindfulness meditation only been mentioned by name.</bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>Despite this show, Steven Universe, being primarily geared towards kids, it has a large following of all ages and is well known for exploring important themes, with the creator herself stating in an interview that she’d <citation>“really like to talk about identity and individuality, and self love”</citation>. As a result, people of all ages and demographics are invited to partake of the show itself and the messages it provides. However, what’s unusual about this specific show, which extends into some of its other songs, is that it while everyone is invited to watch and take part, it specifically seeks to include LGBTQ children and members of the audience, something that, frankly, could be considered rather revolutionary in the world of children’s television.</bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p>Although I initially made the assumption that songs from kid’s shows would mostly be lighthearted and educational, this particular song, in addition to a few of the others from the same show demonstrate that the two don’t necessarily go hand in hand. Additionally, this specific show at least, defied another of my expectations. Rather than strictly focus on the one audience you’d expect a kids’ show to focus on, namely, children, it eagerly welcomes people outside of the traditional audience for kids shows. Given that I don’t watch that many shows that kid’s shows however, it is hard for to say whether this is the norm or not within the genre.</p>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>Fuster, Jeremy. "‘Steven Universe’ Creator Rebecca Sugar Talks LGBT Themes and Season 3." <style type="italics">TheWrap.</style> N.p., 23 Aug. 2016. Web. 5 Oct. 2016. <http://www.thewrap.com/steven-universe-creator-rebecca-sugar-talks-lgbt-themes-teases-season-3/>.</bibl>
                <bibl>Lodge, Daniel. "SDCC '16: Rebecca Sugar on LGBTQ Themes in Steven Universe and What's to Come." <style type="italics">The Beat.</style> N.p., 25 July 2016. Web. 6 Oct. 2016. <http://www.comicsbeat.com/sdcc-16-rebecca-sugar-on-lgbtq-themes-in-steven-universe-and-whats-to-come/>. </bibl>
                <bibl>"What Is Mindfulness?" <style type="italics">Greater Good.</style> Ed. Leah Weiss and Steve Hickman. University of California, Berkeley, n.d. Web. 5 Oct. 2016. <http://greatergood.berkeley.edu/topic/mindfulness/definition>. </bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will go here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
