<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title></title>
            <author xml:id="Anders Chen"></author>
            <date></date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p>Much of what has been discussed within this class so far largely concerns rather serious genres. The choice of a song from a children’s show was, then, an attempt to break down something that would have a bit more levity to it. However, Here Comes a Thought, written and composed by Rebecca Sugar, is rather unusual, and, despite my original intentions, rather serious in its purpose. It is a song that furthers the story, as well as character development, much like every other song produced for the show. Yet, it is also an effort to indirectly teach the audience a method to focus on the present and by doing so, attempt to work through their own feelings of guilt and regret over the past.</p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara> Between the episode’s name, Mindful Education, as well as the lyrics of the song, urging the listener to “take a moment and find yourself”, the mentor figure of the series, Garnet, is seen teaching the technique of mindfulness, sometimes known as mindfulness meditation. Mindfulness, according to UC Berkeley, “involves acceptance” through having “our thoughts tune into what we’re sensing in the present moment rather than rehashing the past or imagining the future”. Through this, for the first time in the episode, Connie begins to accept and acknowledge her own emotions concerning her accidental injury of another student. The glowing butterflies within the scene, the thoughts, burst out of her bag as if through their own will. Although she has attempted to bottle up these emotions since the beginning of the episode, she is once again forced to relive her own memories and guilt. It is with Garnet’s reminder to, once again, “take a moment and ask yourself if this is how we fall apart”, as well as her own use of the repeated mantra “but it’s not”, that she begins to calm down and accept her own remorse over what happened, allowing herself to cry. It is only after she acknowledges this and experiences a strong moment of catharsis that the swarming, troubling thoughts are blown away, signifying that taking the time to calmly examine your own thoughts can allow you to step back from the edge of panic and stop yourself from overreacting. </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>This message is further brought home to the audience through the way in which it is told. Through the first half of the song, Ruby and Sapphire, who combine to form the mentor, Garnet, are shown struggling with their own troubled thoughts and emotions. While those problems remain vague and aren’t shown, it lends credibility to the practice of mindfulness by demonstrating that it is something that this cherished and respected figure also uses. Additionally, Stevonnie, a fusion of Connie herself and her best friend, Steven, the human girl and boy shown in the second half of the segment, also visibly grows less nervous and more confident as the song progresses and Connie comes to terms with what occurred. By demonstrating that all of these characters have managed to find greater peace with themselves and their past actions through mindfulness meditation, the episode very openly seems to suggest that it is something that the audience sitting at home could try, even if the technique wasn’t very blatantly, specifically mentioned. By demonstrating the method and displaying it in a very positive light, the show attempts to convince others to do this themselves likely much more effectively than it would have had it only been mentioned by name.</bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p>Despite Steven Universe being primarily geared towards kids, it has a large following of all ages and is well known for exploring important themes, with the creator herself stating in an interview that she’d “really like to talk about identity and individuality, and self love”. This episode, and this song in particular, focuses heavily on the theme of loving and accepting yourself by showing that it isn’t necessarily healthy to push down your feelings and that sometimes, you need to face your own fears. And perhaps, after seeing this episode, with their role models using mindfulness in front of them, some among the audience can learn to accept some of their own regrets and failings.</p>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>citation here</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will go here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
