<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>Volkswagen Beetle -The People's Car</title>
            <author xml:id="dh.mo">Mohit Dhinakaran</author>
            <date>October 2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p>The Volkswagen Beetle is a two door production car that was made from 1938 to
                    2003. With approximately 20 million produced, the beetle is the longest-running
                    and most-manufactured car of a single platform ever made. Under Adolf Hitler’s
                    orders, the car was designed by Ferdinand Porsche, who would later create the
                    Porsche brand of automobiles a few years later. <argument type="main">Considered
                        by many to be the most influential car of our time, this essay attempts to
                        be analyze the genres of historical, cultural and economical changes that
                        made the Volkswagen Beetle achieve its status of “the people’s car”.
                    </argument></p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara>Historically, this car is important not because of its age or its popularity,
                but because of the purpose it was created for. Circa Germany in early 1930s. Germany
                was devastated after the first world war, and the great depression in 1930 was the
                last nail in the coffin. Unemployment was high, and the economy was in shambles.
                This was the scene for the Beetle. Amidst political turmoil, economic collapse and
                war, the car was conceived. The political situation paved the way for creating a
                genre of automobiles that was more accessible to the people. It is important to note
                that Hitler did not have complete power in the early 1930s, so he wanted to prove to
                the German people that he wanted to make Germany great again by revamping the
                economy. So in April 1934, Adolf Hitler gave the order to Ferdinand Porsche to
                develop a ‘Volkswagen’, which literally meant peoples car. However, this was more of
                a political move for Hitler to boost the German economy, so that he could create
                millions of jobs in the manufacturing industry. He intended to reverse Germany’s
                poor economy by creating infrastructure projects which would require a lot of labor
                (hence jobs), machinery and resources. And for Hitler, his plan worked.<argument
                    type="main">He used Kairos to perfectly time his project. By definition, Kairos
                        <citation>“a time when conditions are right for the accomplishment of a
                        crucial action, the opportune and decisive moment”</citation>
                    (Merriam-Webster dictionary). Hitler analyzed the scene and realized that if he
                    proposed the idea at a different time the people would not have supported him.
                    The situation and scene were ideal for the car to be successful.</argument>
                Hitler saw the opportunity and timing, and decided that such a project would work
                wonders. Post war Germans had little money to spend on cars, and hence many could
                afford the affordable Beetle (costing 900 Marks). The car played a crucial role in
                the economic setting and sold in the millions that gave Germany the economic
                stability it needed, drastically improving the economic scene and situation for the
                country. </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara/>
            <bodyPara>Perhaps a different genre to analyze would be the cultural impact of the
                Beetle. To analyze the interaction of genres (uptake), it is important to represent
                the context and tone of the era. In the 1960s, the Beetle was famously associated
                with the hippie movement and surf culture. Because of its unique design and low
                price, it was truly a car for the masses. The media often portrayed the car in a
                good light, and the lemon advertisement was a fitting representation of the setting.
                The advertisement talks about the stringent quality checks in Volkswagen, and then
                says <citation>“we pick the lemons, you get the plums.”</citation> This is an
                important quote because it presents an interesting rhetorical situation. In the 60s,
                people were interested in thinking big. <mainargument>The American dream in the
                    1960s setting led people to believe that bigger is better, so people strived for
                    big houses and big, ostentatious cars like Cadillacs. Volkswagen intended to
                    compete with that mindset with a different tone. Volkswagen wanted people to
                    think small, to think Beetle. The lemon advertisement reflected the practical
                    and affordable persona that the Beetle represented.</mainargument> However, it
                was also a social statement, for those who could afford it in third world nations.
                For example, in India the Beetle was seen as a luxury vehicle, but in the U.S. it
                was seen as a symbol of German practicality over American decadence. This presented
                another interesting rhetorical situation. In the Indian context the car was seen as
                a representation of wealth, but in the global market it was seen as a cultural and
                artistic icon. It reflected the situation of the time. It featured in movies,
                paintings, music and other forms of media. Cars were spray painted with psychedelic
                designs, which created a new subgenre of street art. Spray painting was seen as a
                rebellious symbol for the hippies, and the car played a vital role in the genre of
                cultural expression. </bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p>In conclusion, by analyzing the interaction of genres (historical, economic and
                    cultural) we can understand that the Volkswagen Beetle is truly an iconic car
                    that has affected the lives of many people. Born from Hitler’s political
                    intentions, the car transformed its tone with ongoing situational changes and
                    redefined the genre of automotive production.</p>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>"A Brief History of the Beetle." - VW Type 1. N.p., n.d. Web. 9 Oct. 2016. </bibl>
                <bibl>"Ad Analysis: Volkswagen Think Small (Major Essay 2)." Connorjv2. Naydan, 05
                    Dec. 2013. Web. 9 Oct. 2016. </bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="li.em"> Emma Lindberg</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Summary: The Volkswagen Beetle embodies its name as the “People’s Car.” It was named
                by Adolf Hitler and designed to be an innovative car in order to boost Germany’s
                economy. From there, it took off and became the “People’s Car” for not only Germans,
                but for other countries and cultures around the world.</p>
            <p> Critique: This paper read more like a history of the Beetle rather than a genre
                analysis. I am not sure where the main argument or sub-arguments are. I saw that you
                bring in the term “kairos” to talk about the timing Hitler decided to order this car
                to be built, however you could elaborate on the implications/meaning if his timing
                to create solid analysis. You also talk about the car “being for the masses” and
                “popular with hippie culture,” however I do not see any analysis of the genre of the
                car. You said that its low price and design contribute to the idea that it is for
                the masses, yet there is no analysis about why or what the means in relation to the
                car as a genre. Overall, there are a few grammatical errors throughout which can be
                easily fixed. I also found some sections quit short and lacking context or
                explanations, such as the sudden introduction of Hitler in the intro. You made it
                seem like everyone knows Hitler ordered the creation the Beetle. Furthermore, when
                you are talking about how it is viewed in other nations, you could easily elaborate
                and analyze why in more than just a few sentences.</p>
            <p> Advise: There is definitely room to give more context/background info to set
                yourself up well to make a good claim and analysis. I would suggest taking time to
                answer each of the questions given in the prompt document to give yourself a jumping
                off point for adding in analysis. Make sure you have a clear, defined thesis that
                makes some sort of claim, and then build your sub-claims off of that. It would also
                be helpful to bring in more of the terms we have been using as a good signaler that
                you are analyzing, not just summarizing history. This is definitely an interesting
                topic, you just need to figure out exactly what your thesis will be so you can
                create a solid, synthesized analysis.</p>

        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
