<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>Volkswagen Beetle -The People's Car</title>
            <author xml:id="">Mohit Dhinakaran</author>
            <date>October 2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p>The Volkswagen Beetle is a two door <note>production</note> car that was made from 1938 to
                    2003. With approximately 20 million produced, the beetle is the longest-running
                    and most-manufactured car of a single platform ever made. Under Adolf Hitler’s
                    orders, the car was designed by Ferdinand Porsche, who would later create the
                    Porsche brand of automobiles a few years later. Considered by many to be the
                    most influential car of our time, this essay attempts to be a brief
                    representation of the historical, cultural and economical changes that made the
                    Volkswagen Beetle achieve its status of “the peoples car”. </p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara/>Historically, this car is important not because of its age or its popularity,
            but because of the purpose it was created for. Circa Germany in early 1930s. Germany was
            devastated after the first world war, and the great depression in 1930 was the last nail
            in the coffin. Unemployment was high, and the economy was in shambles. It is important
            to note that Hitler did not have complete power in the early 1930s, so he wanted to
            prove to the German people that he wanted to make Germany great again by revamping the
            economy. So In April 1934, Adolf Hitler gave the order to Ferdinand Porsche to develop a
            ‘Volkswagen’, which literally meant peoples car. The beetle included a lot of Hitlers
            unusual whims. For example the Beetle is airtight and can briefly float, and he wanted a
            powerful engine (40 hp was considered powerful at the time) that was very fuel efficient
            - revealing his unrealistic expectations from the car. <bodyPara/>
            <bodyPara>However, Porsche managed to build the car and by 1938 the car was off the
                assembly line. What was the purpose? Hitler intended to boost the German economy by
                starting projects like the Beetle, so that he could create millions of jobs in the
                manufacturing industry. He intended to reverse Germany’s poor economy by creating
                infrastructure projects which would require a lot of labour (hence jobs), machinery
                and resources. And for Hitler, his plan worked. He used Kairos to perfectly time his
                project. If he proposed the idea at a different time the people would not have
                supported him. The car sold in the millions and gave Germany the economic stability
                it needed. </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>Culturally, the car is an icon. In the 1960s, the Beetle was famously
                associated with the hippie movement and surf culture. Because of its unique design
                and low price, it was truly a car for the masses. Hippies often did aesthetic
                customizations to their Type Is and IIs and psychedelically painted ones were early
                examples of art cars.However, it was also a social statement, for those who could
                afford it in third world nations. For example in India, the Beetle was seen as a
                luxury vehicle, but in the U.S. it was seen as a symbol of German practicality over
                American decadence. This presented an interesting rhetorical situation. In the
                Indian context the car was seen as a representation of wealth, but in the global
                market it was seen as a cultural and artistic icon. It reflected the situation of
                the time. It featured in movies, paintings, music and other forms of media.
            </bodyPara>body <concl>
                <p/>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>citation here</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="li.em"> Emma Lindberg</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
                    <p>Summary: The Volkswagen Beetle embodies its name as the “People’s Car.” It was named
                by Adolf Hitler and designed to be an innovative car in order to boost Germany’s
                economy. From there, it took off and became the “People’s Car” for not only Germans,
                but for other countries and cultures around the world.</p> 
                <p> Critique: This paper read more like a history of the Beetle rather than a genre analysis. I am not sure where
                the main argument or sub-arguments are. I saw that you bring in the term “kairos” to
                talk about the timing Hitler decided to order this car to be built, however you
                could elaborate on the implications/meaning if his timing to create solid analysis.
                You also talk about the car “being for the masses” and “popular with hippie
                culture,” however I do not see any analysis of the genre of the car. You said that
                its low price and design contribute to the idea that it is for the masses, yet there
                is no analysis about why or what the means in relation to the car as a genre.
                Overall, there are a few grammatical errors throughout which can be easily fixed. I
                also found some sections quit short and lacking context or explanations, such as the
                sudden introduction of Hitler in the intro. You made it seem like everyone knows
                Hitler ordered the creation the Beetle. Furthermore, when you are talking about how
                it is viewed in other nations, you could easily elaborate and analyze why in more
                than just a few sentences.</p> 
                <p> Advise: There is definitely room to give more
                context/background info to set yourself up well to make a good claim and analysis. I
                would suggest taking time to answer each of the questions given in the prompt
                document to give yourself a jumping off point for adding in analysis. Make sure you
                have a clear, defined thesis that makes some sort of claim, and then build your
                sub-claims off of that. It would also be helpful to bring in more of the terms we
                have been using as a good signaler that you are analyzing, not just summarizing
                history. This is definitely an interesting topic, you just need to figure out
                exactly what your thesis will be so you can create a solid, synthesized analysis.</p>
            
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
