<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>Volkswagen Beetle -The People's Car</title>
            <author xml:id="dh.mo">Mohit Dhinakaran</author>
            <date>October 2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p>The Volkswagen Beetle is a two door production car that was made from 1938 to
                    2003. With approximately 20 million produced, the beetle is the longest-running
                    and most-manufactured car of a single platform ever made. Under Adolf Hitler’s
                    orders, the car was designed by Ferdinand Porsche, who would later create the
                    Porsche brand of automobiles a few years later. <argument type="main">Considered
                        by many to be the most influential car of our time, this essay attempts to
                        be analyze the very flexible genres of historical, cultural and economical
                        changes that made the Volkswagen Beetle achieve its status of “the people’s
                        car”.This essay also attempts to reveal the <note type="instructor">I'm not
                            entirely sure how you're using "genre" here. And do you have evidence
                            that the Beetle is "the people's car?" Or is that your formulation based
                            on its popularity?</note>
                    </argument></p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara>Historically, this car is important not because of its age or its popularity,
                but because of the purpose it was created for. Picture Germany in early 1930s, with
                its crippled economy after the great depression.<note type="instructor">this is a
                    fragment, consider making it a dependent clause with the previous
                    sentence</note> Germany was devastated after the First World War,<note
                    type="instructor">generally capitalized, I think</note> and the great depression
                in 1930 was the last nail in the coffin. Unemployment was high, and the economy was
                in shambles. This was the scene for the Beetle. Amidst political turmoil, economic
                collapse and war, the car was conceived. The political situation paved the way for
                creating a genre of automobiles that was more accessible to the people.<note
                    type="instructor">you use both scene and situation here to refer to the same
                    thing, as I read it. I think that you are right in thinking that it is a
                    situation, and that the situation opened the door for a genre of
                    vehicle...</note> It is important to note that Hitler did not have complete
                power in the early 1930s, so he wanted to prove to the German people that he wanted
                to make Germany great again by revamping the economy. So in April 1934, Adolf Hitler
                gave the order to Ferdinand Porsche to develop a ‘Volkswagen’, which literally meant
                peoples car.<note type="instructor">oh, that's interesting. Where are you getting
                    all of this historical information? I would expect to see in-text citations
                    throughout the essay.</note> However, this was more of a political move for
                Hitler to boost the German economy, so that he could create millions of jobs in the
                manufacturing industry. He intended to reverse Germany’s poor economy by creating
                infrastructure projects which would require a lot of labor (hence jobs), machinery
                and resources. And for Hitler, his plan worked.<argument type="main">He used Kairos
                    to perfectly time his project. By definition, Kairos <citation>“a time when
                        conditions are right for the accomplishment of a crucial action, the
                        opportune and decisive moment”</citation> (Merriam-Webster dictionary).
                    Hitler analyzed the scene and realized that if he proposed the idea at a
                    different time the people would not have supported him. The situation and scene
                    were ideal for the car to be successful.</argument><note type="instructor"
                    >alright, but is this the same as your main argument?</note> Hitler saw the
                opportunity and timing, and decided that such a project would work wonders. Post war
                Germans had little money to spend on cars, and hence many could afford the
                affordable Beetle (costing 900 Marks). The car played a crucial role in the economic
                setting and sold in the millions that gave Germany the economic stability it needed,
                drastically improving the economic scene and situation for the country. These
                results corresponded with the situation the preceded it. In this complex political
                mess, the idea of reaching out to the people with an affordable car seemed to be the
                most appropriate response. <note type="instructor">relate this back to the idea that
                    the genre of the affordable car was an appropriate response to this complex
                    historical/political situation (obviously not the only response, but one of many
                    coordinated responses)</note>
            </bodyPara>

            <bodyPara>Perhaps a different perspective would be the cultural impact in the
                international setting of the Beetle, focusing on its impact in the US<note
                    type="instructor">again, not sure how you're using genre here. A genre is a
                    typified response to a recurrent rhetorical situation within a scene. Also, why
                    this shift? What is the goal in looking forward from the kairos of its
                    creation?</note> To analyze the interaction of genres (uptake), it is important
                to represent the context and tone of the era. In the 1960s, the Beetle was famously
                associated with the hippie movement and surf culture. Because of its unique design
                and low price, it was truly a car for the masses.<note type="instructor">are we
                    still talking Germany here?</note> The media<note type="instructor">I think you
                    need to make clear that we are shifting to the US here</note> often portrayed
                the car in a good light, and the lemon advertisement<note type="instructor">explain
                    what you mean</note> was a fitting representation of the setting. The
                advertisement talks about the stringent quality checks in Volkswagen, and then says
                    <citation>“we pick the lemons, you get the plums.”</citation> This is an
                important quote because it presents an interesting rhetorical situation. In the 60s,
                people were interested in thinking big. <argument type="supporting ">The American
                    dream in the 1960s setting led people to believe that bigger is better, so
                    people strived for big houses and big, ostentatious cars like Cadillacs.
                    Volkswagen intended to compete with that mindset with a different tone.
                    Volkswagen wanted people to think small, to think Beetle. The lemon
                    advertisement reflected the practical and affordable persona that the Beetle
                    represented.</argument><note type="instructor">One way to frame this in terms of
                    a genre analysis would be to say that it represented an alternative response to
                    American consumers, one that went against the prevailing US car scene at the
                    time</note><note type="instructor">should be an "argument" tag, probably of
                    @type supporting</note> However, it was also a social statement, for those who
                could afford it in third world nations. For example, in India the Beetle was seen as
                a luxury vehicle, but in the U.S. it was seen as a symbol of German practicality
                over American decadence.<note type="instructor">Same genre, different rhetorical
                    situations. So maybe the argument here is that the Volkwagen was able to embody
                    an appropriate response to a range of rhetorical situations, ranging from
                    Germany in the 1930's, to the big and bold 1960s US, to third world
                    countries.</note> This presented another interesting rhetorical situation. In
                the Indian context the car was seen as a representation of wealth, but in the global
                market it was seen as a cultural and artistic icon. It reflected the situation of
                the time. It featured in movies, paintings, music and other forms of media. Cars
                were spray painted with psychedelic designs, which created a new subgenre of street
                art. Spray painting was seen as a rebellious symbol for the hippies, and the car
                played a vital role in the genre of cultural expression.<note type="instructor">this
                    is all interesting, but lacking evidence (in the form or citation, examples,
                    etc.)</note>
            </bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p>In conclusion, by analyzing the interaction of genres (historical, economic and
                    cultural) we can understand that the Volkswagen Beetle is truly an iconic car
                    that has affected the lives of many people.Its birth from a political situation
                    gave rise to multiple genres that in many ways shaped the way we look at motor
                    cars today. In a nutshell, the Beetle's incredible flexibility gave rise to
                    interesting rhetorical situations, and created the genres analysed in this
                        essay.<note type="instructor">affecting lives isn't the point though, is it?
                        I think your point is that the genre of the Beetle is so successful because
                        of its flexibility--to be able to shift its semiotic meaning in different
                        rhetorical situations.</note> Born from Hitler’s political intentions, the
                    car consistently transformed its persona starting from an affordable runabout,
                    to a blank canvas adored by artists and enthusiasts. <note type="instructor"
                        >you're so close here, but I don't think 'tone' is the right term. And the
                        car didn't shit its tone, people took it up to respond in different ways to
                        different rhetorical situations.</note> with ongoing situational changes and
                    redefined the genre of automotive production.</p>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>"A Brief History of the Beetle." - VW Type 1. N.p., n.d. Web. 9 Oct. 2016. </bibl>
                <bibl>"Ad Analysis: Volkswagen Think Small (Major Essay 2)." Connorjv2. Naydan, 05
                    Dec. 2013. Web. 9 Oct. 2016. </bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="li.em"> Emma Lindberg</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Summary: The Volkswagen Beetle embodies its name as the “People’s Car.” It was named
                by Adolf Hitler and designed to be an innovative car in order to boost Germany’s
                economy. From there, it took off and became the “People’s Car” for not only Germans,
                but for other countries and cultures around the world.</p>
            <p> Critique: This paper read more like a history of the Beetle rather than a genre
                analysis. I am not sure where the main argument or sub-arguments are. I saw that you
                bring in the term “kairos” to talk about the timing Hitler decided to order this car
                to be built, however you could elaborate on the implications/meaning if his timing
                to create solid analysis. You also talk about the car “being for the masses” and
                “popular with hippie culture,” however I do not see any analysis of the genre of the
                car. You said that its low price and design contribute to the idea that it is for
                the masses, yet there is no analysis about why or what the means in relation to the
                car as a genre. Overall, there are a few grammatical errors throughout which can be
                easily fixed. I also found some sections quit short and lacking context or
                explanations, such as the sudden introduction of Hitler in the intro. You made it
                seem like everyone knows Hitler ordered the creation the Beetle. Furthermore, when
                you are talking about how it is viewed in other nations, you could easily elaborate
                and analyze why in more than just a few sentences.</p>
            <p> Advise: There is definitely room to give more context/background info to set
                yourself up well to make a good claim and analysis. I would suggest taking time to
                answer each of the questions given in the prompt document to give yourself a jumping
                off point for adding in analysis. Make sure you have a clear, defined thesis that
                makes some sort of claim, and then build your sub-claims off of that. It would also
                be helpful to bring in more of the terms we have been using as a good signaler that
                you are analyzing, not just summarizing history. This is definitely an interesting
                topic, you just need to figure out exactly what your thesis will be so you can
                create a solid, synthesized analysis.</p>

        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>What an interesting topic. I encourage you to revise this, because the initial idea
                is so fruitful and interesting, but I think it just needs a bit more work tightening
                up the argument and bolstering the evidence and analysis. My read of your essay
                would call for a clearer framing of your structure. As I understand it, what you are
                trying to do is to first analyse the kairos of the Beetle by describing the complex
                historical/political/economic situation to which the genre of the small, affordable,
                mass produced car was an appropriate response. Then, you analyze the uptakes of the
                Beetle (i.e. why it endured as a particularly popular car), by looking at how the
                Beetle shifted meaning according to a range of historical/economic/political
                rhetorical situations (US mainstream, India/international developing countries,
                hippie movement). To me, the argument is not that the car *shifted* meanings, but
                rather that if we use genre analysis to look at how a car has endured, we see how a
                genre is exceedingly flexible--it can be taken up as a whole range of different,
                sometimes completely contrary, responses to different rhetorical situations. All the
                while, the car barely changed at all for like 50 years. You are close to making that
                argument in spots, but you need to frame it in a much clearer way from the outset.
                It would also help if you 1) Used the vocabulary of genre analysis in more precise
                ways; and 2) provided evidence (pictures, quotes, citations, examples, etc.)
                througout your essay. This really has the makings of an awesome essay, it just needs
                a bit more work.</p>
            <p><style type="italics">Note: Grading Citeria</style>. A successful genre analysis
                should: <list>
                    <item>Address one (or more) of the questions posed on the prompt: yes</item>
                    <item>Contain a clearly stated main argument: needs to be much clearer and more
                        comprehensive at the outset</item>
                    <item>Emphasize evidence in support of claims (textual evidence or otherwise):
                        this was lacking in specificity </item>
                    <item>Use a few of the terms from the vocabulary list: at times, use of
                        terminology was inconsistent/confusing; consider using other tags (and their
                        definitions) to help you use these terms more accurately</item>
                    <item>Provide an overview of genre broadly (beyond an individual text):
                        okay</item>
                    <item>Be detailed and focused: sometimes the topic felt too big for the length
                        of the essay, contributing to a bit of a superficial analysis</item>
                    <item>Contain citations (in-text and works cited): no in-text citations affected
                        the credibility of evidence/claims</item>
                    <item>Be structured as an essay: okay</item>
                </list></p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
