<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title> Draft: Genere Analysis of a Cosmology Textbook </title>
            <author xml:id="ga.ar"/>
            <date> October 3, 2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p> The textbook genre is a well-known, largely tolerated and divisive genre that
                    exist perpetually as an entity in itself as well as thematic element in college
                    education. Genre is defined by scenes and the underlying experiences that we, as
                    individuals attribute and expect from an element such as a textbook
                        <citation>(Devitt, Reiff and Bawarshi)</citation>. However, genres feed of
                    each other just like memories feed of each other to create patterns that allow
                    us to experience intelligence<citation>(Bawarshi)</citation>. The textbook is a
                    genre that stems from the college, pedagogical, educational genres that
                    interplay to give it its meanings. The current, most widely accepted view of the
                    textbook among college <participants>students</participants> is that of the
                    necessary evil. The method of updating textbooks to maintain a no resale value
                    and increase demand for widely similar bodies of knowledge is what drives the
                    divisive force behind the ill received understanding of textbooks. <argument
                        type="main">The modern cosmology book as compared to a book from the 1980's
                        might be different in it's way that treats the reader, and the genres that
                        surround itself. The differences could be in the presentation of information
                        or even the choices to write the textbook in the first place.</argument>
                    <note type="peer">Which claim is your main argument? You might want to focus on
                        just one, and use the other as a supporting argument.</note>
                    <note type="peer">Also take another look at your xml tags. There are a lot of
                        errors that can be fixed pretty quickly.</note></p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara> Cosmology, The Science of The Universe by Edward Harrison is an introductory
                cosmology textbook published in the 1980s, a time where science was beginning to
                compound exponentially upwards. Steven Weinberg, the author of ,"Cosmology" was
                published in 2008 in Europe. Europeans would take up the genre of textbook very
                differently from the readers of the United States. However, since the point of
                reference is now 2016 from a <participants>student</participants> studying in
                America, from a climate where the genre of textbook is uptaken differently from what
                the authors first imagined, some error will be introduced. The intended audience in
                Europe during 2008 were the <participants>students</participants> of physics, whom
                were already presently acquainted with the developments of the modern world in
                physics and cosmology. The American counterparts in the 1980's still had a
                substantial part of the universe in a fog of uncertainty, and they would be the
                pioneers in cosmology and the study of the universe. <note type="peer">You may want
                    to explain who the original intended audience was and why an American outlook is
                    so different.</note> The modern, most recent view of the genre of textbook is
                that of a body of knowledge written for the consumption of an
                    <participants>educator</participants> or <participants>student</participants>,
                whom both are expected to read with similar efficiencies. The knowledge is expected
                to be introduced in higher and higher degrees of competency since the book builds on
                the knowledge previously written. A textbook carries with it the idea of homework,
                the genre of note-taking and the genre of educational quizzing and testing. This
                epicenter of modern education should be presented differently in these two books,
                since the time periods are vastly different. Focusing on the presentation of the
                book itself, the covers offer little color, except for the streak of the color
                spectrum on the 2008 book <citation>(Weinberg)</citation>. Both black, suggest to
                the reader the emptiness and blackness of space. However the 1980 book, also has
                within it a circular patterns resembling galaxies suggest a fill of space. Both play
                to the era's interested <participants>educators</participants> and
                    <participants>students</participants>. This could suggest that the expectation
                of the 80's, a time of fantastic breakthroughs in Space Travel were vastly concerned
                with the possibilities and would have been taken as possibilities, where the science
                saturated era of 2008 would have been most focused with the limits and
                understandings of science. Both eras are contributing to the authors understandings
                of their textbook genre and the expectation of the audience differs in that regard. </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>It is self evident that the 2008 textbook on Cosmology took a mathematics
                heavy approach starting as early as page 2, <q>"The coordinate transformations that
                    leave this invariant are here simply ordinary three-dimensional rotations and
                    translation"</q>
                <citation>(Weinberg)</citation> with little room for discussion or hypothetical such
                as the 1980 book by Dr. Witten . Taking The 1980's book also focused on the creative
                thought that inspired the study of space, with fantastical images spanning the
                entire history of human history as seen in the illustrations that dot the pages and
                the quotes that begin the chapters; "He has ventured far beyond the flaming ramparts
                of the world and in mind and spirit traversed the boundless universe- Lucretiues
                (99-55 B.C.)" <citation>(Harrison)</citation>. The presence of quotes, of depictions
                of early cosmology reveal the inspiration beyond writing a textbook on cosmology,
                and the authors interest in providing curiosity in the search for knowledge. The
                genre most likely influencing the writer of that textbook was most likely not money,
                or pride, but simplifying the lives of college freshmen. While the most likely genre
                that influenced the Oxford Writer in 2008 was most likely money, in an ever
                competitive science world.<note type="peer">I think this this is a fantastic claim
                    with which you can write an entire paper on. Try and explore this a little
                    more.</note> The education genre in the northeast, during the 80's was that of
                unbridled imagination urged on by the space race, and the content of this textbook
                is set to inspire confidence in the young entering freshmen about the beauty of
                space. In 2008 however, with cosmology becoming more theoretical and less inspired
                by novelty, the textbook reflected the dramatic shift in the genre of space and how
                to present it.<note type="peer">Try throwing in some specific examples from each
                    book to demonstrate your point. It will help the reader understand what exactly
                    you mean by "took a mathematics heavy approach" versus "discussion or
                    hypothetical". In text citations are also required on the project
                    assesment.</note></bodyPara>
            <bodyPara> Finally, having discussed how two different cosmology books present the study
                of cosmology, the next logical jump would be to discuss why the textbook genre
                existed then and continues to exist now. The purpose of the textbook has not changed
                since the three decades of publishing in between them. The <scene>academic
                    scene</scene> still requires that textbooks are the primary method of teaching.
                One of these reasons could be that the condensation of knowledge is universally
                regarded as the best means of transmitting information. Books usually have physical
                material that they quote from in regards to their knowledge, and this is what
                    a<participants> student</participants> or <participants>educator</participants>
                can expect from a <genre>textbook</genre>, knowing that the knowledge is sound. For
                example "Cosmology" contains references at the bottom of the page of information
                    <citation>(Weinberg 30) or at the end of the chapter (Harrison 68). Perhaps then
                    only the uptake of information from the <genre>textbook</genre> has made the
                    transition in this millennium, moving away from focusing on the understanding
                    but more to the practice of the craft of science. </citation><note type="peer"
                    >It feels like you are making a lot of claims about text books as an idustry,
                    but not a lot of evidence ot back it up. You should use the differences you
                    found in your analysis to explain how the text book genre has changed over time
                    to better support your main argument.</note><note type="peer">You are very light
                    on xml tags over all. I'd suggest taking the time and matching up some of the
                    vocab you used with the element list and tagging them.</note>
            </bodyPara>

            <concl>
                <p>In conclusion, the <participants>student</participants> plays the part in the
                    academic scene, by interacting in a set pattern with a <genre>textbook</genre>.
                    In the cosmology textbooks listed above, the role the
                        <participants>student</participants> assumes is that of a "tabula rasa"
                        <note type="peer">Give a quick definition of that term in case someone
                        doesn't know what it is.</note> and its up to the way their previous
                    experiences with <genre>textbooks</genre> to synthesize the material. Depending
                    on what textbook a <participants>student</participants> opens, the expected way
                    of approach will be governed by the <participants>student's</participants>
                    experiences with the humanities and the sciences. Cosmology, The Science of the
                    Universe, takes the responsibility to present the material so that
                        <participants>students</participants> do not have to assume a role based on
                    their expectations of the material. The <participants>student</participants> can
                    open the textbook and find a blend of history, science, culture and art, that
                    makes the education just much more enjoyable. A mathematical approach left much
                    to be desired. The textbook genre however way it is addressed cannot and will
                    not be replaced as the primary source of consolidated information, and it is a
                    staple of modern education. </p>
            </concl>

        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>Bawarshi, Anis S. Genre And The Invention Of The Writer. Logan: Utah State
                    University Press, 2003. Print.</bibl>
                <bibl>Devitt, Amy J, Mary Jo Reiff, and Anis S Bawarshi. Scenes Of Writing. New
                    York: Pearson/Longman, 2004. Print.Devitt, Amy J, Mary Jo Reiff, and Anis S
                    Bawarshi. Scenes Of Writing. New York: Pearson/Longman, 2004. Print.</bibl>
                <bibl>Harrison, Edward Robert. Cosmology, The Science Of The Universe. Cambridge:
                    Cambridge University Press, 1981. Print.</bibl>
                <bibl>Weinberg, Steven. Cosmology. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2008.
                    Print.</bibl>

            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="bu.an">Andrew Burcham</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#bu.an">
            <p>This essay is a genre analysis of the text book genre, which specifically refers to
                two different cosmology text books from two very different periods of time. As such,
                the main argument is that due to their differences in publication dates, they have
                very different styles despite containing the same material and appealing to the same
                audience. Personally, I felt the language and prose used was very well done, and
                many of the vocab terms we have studied were used very well. The problems start to
                arise however, when referring to the essays main argument, and the evidence
                supporting it. It feels as though from the thesis statement, that there are two main
                claims being made, but it really feels like only one is being addressed throughout
                the piece. Take another look at the main claim and try to refocus it a little so
                that the reader can understand what you’ll be talking about. Similarly, I’d supply a
                little more direct evidence from the two text books to support your claim. There are
                no in text citations (Which is one of the requirements on the assessment criteria)
                and a few claims made in the last body paragraph with little evidence. The analysis
                you did do was well done, I just thought it could be weaved into your argument a
                little better. “Different universities may favor different books based on university
                prestige, that is, a book written by the universities professor, creates the scene
                and uptake of believing that the education from that professor is superior to the
                education received by a professor using an unaffiliated book.” While I completely
                agree with you, statements like this one don’t have anything to back them up in your
                paper. You might want to cut it and refocus some of your body paragraphs to really
                hone in on your main claim. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
