<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>Ebay Listings Genre Analysis</title>
            <note type="instructor">Make sure you use the template file provided for you based on
                your id (in student_xml folder). If you don't then the course schema is not
                associated with your document or the formatting stylesheet for testing. As a result,
                there were several validation errors in your essay. You also then miss out on the
                prompting and auto-complete functions that make Oxygen helpful for composing with
                our schema.</note>
            <author xml:id="ho.jo">John Hoyt</author>
            <date>10/10/2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>Ebay is an online marketplace where users can buy and sell various items. Buyers
                and sellers make accounts on the website, and can either auction off their
                belongings or purchase products from others. <context>Ebay is unique in that anyone
                    is allowed to sell products, as long as they create an account and pay a small
                    fee. Secure payment methods allow consumers and vendors to be confident that
                    they get their product and their money respectively. </context> Today there are
                over 150 million users on Ebay <citation source="#Smith">(Smith).</citation>
                <argument type="main">In the genre of Ebay listings, recurring language and actions
                    are a determining factor in what ends up happening. If a seller wants to attract
                    attention to their product and have more bidders, they need to use generic
                    conventions and predictable language to describe their product. A buyer must
                    know the ways the genre can be taken up, and how to ask questions about a
                    product. Buyers and sellers have the same goals of wanting fair and fast
                    exchanges of products and money, so naturally Ebay listings have common
                    rhetorical actions and language. </argument>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara>Two of the most popular items currently on Ebay are GoPro cameras and Michael
                Kors handbags <citation source="#Ebay">(“What’s Selling Hot on Ebay”).</citation>
                Searching for a GoPro camera leads to a listing for a camera with some of the most
                active bidders. Despite the product being pre-owned, there is significant interest
                in it, demonstrated by the number of bids. This can be credited in part due to the
                seller’s understanding of the genre of Ebay listings. <claim>The seller recognizes
                    that the person that’s viewing their listing is likely interested in a fast and
                    cheap way to acquire the camera. The language and descriptions used to inform
                    the reader of the product are concise, while still communicating the necessary
                    details.</claim> This is representative of the communication used throughout the
                genre. The language is similarly clear and simple in most listings, regardless of
                what product it is. <pattern>Customers use these same rhetorical ways of
                    communicating, where simplicity and minimalism is valued above all.</pattern>
                This common language is a result of the shared intentions of all of the participants
                in the genre. <evidence>For example, one listing of a Michael Kors bag simply says
                    "10/10 NWT" in the description. In Ebay, this common rhetorical phrase signifies
                    that an item is in perfect condition and comes "new with tags".</evidence> Both
                <participants>buyers and sellers</participants> are interested in doing business
                as quickly and easily as possible, and are interested in getting the best deal for
                themselves. In the buyer’s case, this means understanding all of the information
                about the product, and the seller wants to get as many people as possible interested
                in buying their product so the auction price will increase. These similar, shared
                goals shape the whole genre of Ebay listings, as well as the resulting interactions
                and uptake. </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>The casing of the camera is scratched and the plastic is fading, but the
                seller has pictures of all of the imperfections, and explains that the functionality
                hasn’t been affected. Because of the condition of the product, the auction price is
                much lower than new versions of the GoPro camera that can be found on Ebay, which is
                likely one of the reasons for this listing’s popularity. <claim>This is an example
                    of kairos, where the seller understands what to say in the right situation to
                    turn a flaw into something advantageous.></claim>
                <evidence>The seller highlights the comparatively low price of the camera, and
                    explains that it functions exactly the same as one without the aesthetic
                    flaws.</evidence>
                <situation>When a bidder finally wins, the genre changes, and only two specific
                    participants are involved. The user that won the bid or purchased the product
                    will convey specific information to the seller. Often a buyer first sends out
                    their payment along with their address and any other specific requests, and the
                    seller will send a tracking number for the package soon after.</situation> This
                is one example of uptake being invited from the genre of an Ebay listing. This
                process will not be taken up by the listing genre for the bidders that don’t win;
                they’ll likely try to bid on the same product being sold by a different seller.
                Failing to win a bid and seeking other similar items to bid on can even be viewed as
                another uptake of the genre. </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>After scrolling through “buy it now” listings when searching for Michael Kors
                handbags, numerous almost identical listings can be found. Upon clicking on one, it
                can be seen that the listing hasn’t garnered much interest, <claim>likely because of
                    the seller’s lack of understanding of the genre.</claim>
                <evidence>The item description contains no words at all, and the image is a stock
                    photo from the internet, not a real picture of the specific item that will be
                    shipped.</evidence> It could be inferred that the seller isn’t aware of the
                rhetorical conventions, or they might not value the interest of the customers, which
                results in a less popular listing. <analysis>This seller has a similar purpose to
                    any other seller on the site, which is to get someone to buy their product.
                    However, in this situation the seller might not have a full grasp on what will
                    interest possible buyers, and thus their inadequate communication of the
                    information surrounding the product results in no interest.</analysis>
            </bodyPara>
            <concl>Because of the intentions of the buyers and sellers on Ebay, typified rhetorical
                actions can be seen in every listing. The use of language to better advertise
                products is the most common occurrence, but consumers also use their own rhetorical
                language to benefit themselves and others. Uptake occurs when the possible buyers
                ask questions publicly to the seller, or when someone chooses to purchase the
                product and the genre of negotiating information takes place. The constant
                interaction between buyers and sellers that is necessary because of their shared
                objectives as users results in a genre where participants make distinct rhetorical
                choices. </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl xml:id="Smith">Smith, Craig. "45 Amazing EBay Stats." <style type="italics"
                    >DMR.</style> Expanded Ramblings, 13 Aug. 2016. Web. 4 Oct. 2016. </bibl>
                <bibl xml:id="Ebay">What's Selling Hot on Ebay." <style type="italics">Ebay.</style>
                    Ebay, 4 Oct. 2016. Web. 4 Oct. 2016. </bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="sm.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will go here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>NOTE: Make sure you use the template file provided for you based on your id (in
                student_xml folder). If you don't then the course schema is not associated with your
                document or the formatting stylesheet for testing. As a result, there were several
                validation errors in your essay. You also then miss out on the prompting and
                auto-complete functions that make Oxygen helpful for composing with our schema.</p>
            <p/>
            <p>There is a lot going well here: your sub-claims are interesting, you do a good job
                explaining the conventions and then providing an example the shows what happens when
                someone violates these conventions, and your conclusion is great. There are some
                errors in your XMl (because of the above issue with the schema), that also may have
                contributed to your sometimes confusing use of tags (e.g. genre, evidence). Finally,
                be sure to be as specific and detailed as possible, especially when making an
                argument and presenting evidence. </p>
            <p><style type="italics">Note: Grading Citeria</style>. A successful genre analysis
                should: <list>
                    <item>Address one (or more) of the questions posed on the prompt: yes</item>
                    <item>Contain a clearly stated main argument: see comments above </item>
                    <item>Emphasize evidence in support of claims (textual evidence or otherwise):
                        okay, could be more specific at times </item>
                    <item>Use a few of the terms from the vocabulary list: okay, see comments above </item>
                    <item>Provide an overview of genre broadly (beyond an individual text): yes </item>
                    <item>Be detailed and focused: see comments above about specificity </item>
                    <item>Contain citations (in-text and works cited): yes</item>
                    <item>Be structured as an essay: yes </item>
                </list></p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>