<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title> Exploring how Mc Donald's use menu(s) as a genre </title>
            <author xml:id="koradia.d"/>
            <date>7th October 2015</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p>In the restaurant industry, menu(s) play a very important role. They are the
                    single most important piece of document that help acquire a potential customer,
                    which is why restaurants spend a massive amount of time perfecting their
                    menu(s). <argument type="main">One such example is Mc Donald’s; who have over
                        the past few decades not only been dominating the fast food industry with
                        their delicious and cheap eateries but have also been a major influence in
                        the establishment of menu as a genre.</argument></p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara>Genre refers to the typical rhetorical way of responding to a situation that
                repeatedly occurs within a scene. <genre>For example, Mc Donald’s was the first to
                    respond to the needs of an affordable yet tasty menu. They analysed a particular
                    scene and came to the conclusion of creating a menu such that it serves the
                    prime purpose of offering delicious meals for a dollar or under. By doing so,
                    they responded to a rhetorical situation by creating a new type of sub-genre
                    under the menu genre i.e. the dollar menu. Soon most of the fast food chains
                    came out with their own version of the dollar menu.</genre>
            </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara><figure url="https://b.zmtcdn.com/data/menus/343/65343/1724f7fffcad546ad26a17c40a11ff25.png">Indian Menu</figure>
                <figure url="https://akbrodie.files.wordpress.com/2014/12/mcd3.jpg">USA Menu</figure>
            </bodyPara>
            
            <bodyPara>McDonald's is the world's largest chain of hamburger fast food restaurants,
                serving around 68 million customers daily in 119 countries. The key to their success
                is creating a customized menu for almost every country on the basis of an extensive
                market research. They achieve this by factoring in the situation and participants
                (customers) that are involved in the scene. <diff>A Mc Donald’s menu in the United
                    States of America is starkly different from that in India and this is because of
                    the differences found in both the countries. For instance, India has a higher
                    vegetarian oriented population as compared to USA which is why on the Indian
                    menu of Mc Donald’s one can find a larger array of vegetarian friendly burgers.
                    On the other hand, due to higher meat eating population in the USA, Mc Donald’s
                    offer a greater ranger of non-vegetarian burgers. Moreover, both the menus have
                    country exclusive burgers. In the Indian menu you will find burgers such as
                    McVeggie and McSpicy, something that is not even remotely mentioned in the USA
                    menu. Also the naming scheme on both the menus are very different. Burgers in
                    the USA menu are named after famous state names such as the New York classic and
                    California Chicken. Au contraire, Mc Donald’s has used Hinglish to name their
                    Indian burgers. Instead of calling a burger McPotato they named it McAloo,
                    wherein the word “aloo” means potato in Hindi. People in the U.S. are more
                    health conscious, hence, the U.S. menu contains a calorie count next to each of
                    its burger.</diff> By designing these differences, Mc Donald’s has taken up the
                culture and situation of a particular country and reflected it in their menu. Their
                objective <q>is to adapt their menu to reflect different tastes and local traditions
                    for every country in which they have restaurants. They are keen to respect
                    cultural differences and so every country has its own policy of developing menu
                    items.</q>
            </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>In the lights of all these differences, there are some vivid similarities in
                both the menus which overall help maintain the brand image of Mc Donald’s across the
                world. <sim>Both the menus have a very structured layout with starters, mains and
                    dessert being displayed in different columns. Both menus have a variety of text
                    sizes, bolded and non-bolded words to make them easy to follow. Each menus
                    offers various meal options and often seem to have two different sizes for all
                    their products. The menus are also loaded with delicious imageries of their
                    products and have a very bright colour scheme that will without fail catch an
                    onlookers’ attention. Lastly, both the menus somehow manage to portray the ever
                    famous Mc Donald logo, hence, constantly reminding the customer where they are.
                </sim></bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p>Imagine walking into a restaurant and asking the waiter questions regarding the
                    type of cuisine they serve, what dishes do they have on offer, the prices of
                    that dishes, etc. A menu puts an end to all of this questioning by simply
                    offering you a cohesive summary of what the eating establishment is all about.
                    Mc Donald’s have made great advancements in the fields of menu which has not
                    only reflected in their sales but in the menu(s) itself. One can say that menus,
                    in their own way, significantly contribute to not only the success of the
                    company they represent, but also to the success of the food service industry
                    they are a part of.</p>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>"Why Is the McDonald's Menu Different in Different Countries?" What Makes
                    McDonald's. N.p., n.d. Web. 10 Oct. 2016. </bibl>
                <bibl>"Welcome to the Purdue OWL." Purdue OWL: The Rhetorical Situation. N.p., n.d.
                    Web. 11 Oct. 2016.</bibl>
                <bibl>"McDonald's." Wikipedia. Wikimedia Foundation, n.d. Web. 11 Oct. 2016.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here">Sa.Jh </reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Your comparison among this genre becomes very interesting. It pulls the reader more
                into understanding what exactly makes this genre important and why it exist. The
                Genre of Menu seems to be a topic that one can go deep into as you have already
                demonstrated. Not only that, but it makes it even more interesting when you bring
                the history of it to your paper. One thing I would consider looking over is your
                main argument. Your argument should flow more instead of you telling the reader what
                you plan on doing. I would advise that you revise your main argument since you are
                not really expressing your argument, instead you are expressing your strategies to
                complete this piece of writing. It is a great aspect to cover, since the comparison
                and contrast is a very important factor to your paper, but it would be best if you
                include that as a different element. Also remember that your main argument is to be
                on your intro, this way the reader has a feel of what to expect. So far your paper
                is great, it just needs some final touches and for you to explain further your main
                argument and back it up. I would suggest not telling the reader what you plan on
                doing, but instead just do it. This way the reader will be more intrigued since one
                does not know what to expect. Since this is a genre that in some way affect a lot of
                people, it would be a good idea for you to include pros and cons of this genre
                "Dollar Menu" Since we know that this genre brings a lot of advantages as well as
                disadvantages. Overall, this is a great genre to consider and it would be great to
                continue reading it based on what you have so far.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
