<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title/>
            <author xml:id="koradia.d"/>
            <date>7th October 2015</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p><note type="peer"/>The arrival of fast foods in the 1950s has revolutionized the
                    food industry and one cannot but thank the king of this domain, Mc Donald’s, for
                    doing so. Over the past few decades not only have Mc Donald’s dominated the fast
                    food industry with its delicious and cheap eateries but have also been a major
                    influence in the establishment of menus as a genre. </p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara>Genre refers to the typical rhetorical way of responding to a situation that
                repeatedly occurs within a scene. For example, Mc Donald’s was the first to respond
                to the needs of an affordable yet tasty menu. They analysed a particular scene and
                came to the conclusion of creating a menu such that it serves the prime purpose of
                modifying ones’ perspective (in their case attracting new/old customers). To put it
                in more literal terms, they responded to a rhetorical situation by creating a new
                type of genre i.e. the dollar menu. Soon most of the fast food chains came out with
                their own version of the dollar menu. </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>Mc Donald’s is the world's largest chain of hamburger fast food restaurants,
                serving around 68 million customers daily in 119 countries across 36,538 outlets. It
                is considered that their method of coming up with a different menu for almost every
                country on the basis of an extensive market research has given them an edge over
                their rivals.<argument type="main"> For my genre analysis paper, <note type="peer">
                        I am going to compare two separate Mc Donald’s menus and will be analysing
                        their similarities and differences on the basis of scene</note>, situation
                    and participants.</argument>. I will conclude by explaining how is that they
                have created a new genre called menu, which has indirectly help them be succesful. </bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p/>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>citation here</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here">Sa.Jh </reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Your comparison among this genre becomes very interesting. It pulls the reader more
                into understanding what exactly makes this genre important and why it exist. The
                Genre of Menu seems to be a topic that one can go deep into as you have already
                demonstrated. Not only that, but it makes it even more interesting when you bring
                the history of it to your paper. One thing I would consider looking over is your
                main argument. Your argument should flow more instead of you telling the reader what
                you plan on doing. I would advise that you revise your main argument since you are
                not really expressing your argument, instead you are expressing your strategies to
                complete this piece of writing. It is a great aspect to cover, since the comparison
                and contrast is a very important factor to your paper, but it would be best if you
                include that as a different element. Also remember that your main argument is to be
                on your intro, this way the reader has a feel of what to expect. So far your paper
                is great, it just needs some final touches and for you to explain further your main
                argument and back it up. I would suggest not telling the reader what you plan on
                doing, but instead just do it. This way the reader will be more intrigued since one
                does not know what to expect. Since this is a genre that in some way affect a lot of
                people, it would be a good idea for you to include pros and cons of this genre
                "Dollar Menu" Since we know that this genre brings a lot of advantages as well as
                disadvantages. Overall, this is a great genre to consider and it would be great to
                continue reading it based on what you have so far.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
