<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title/>
            <author xml:id="koradia.d"/>
            <date>7th October 2015</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p>The arrival of fast foods in the 1950s has revolutionized the food industry and
                    one cannot but thank the king of this domain, Mc Donald’s, for doing so. Over
                    the past few decades not only have Mc Donald’s dominated the fast food industry
                    with its delicious and cheap eateries but have also been a major influence in
                    the establishment of menus as a genre. </p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara>Genre refers to the typical rhetorical way of responding to a situation that
                repeatedly occurs within a scene. For example, Mc Donald’s was the first to respond
                to the needs of an affordable yet tasty menu. They analysed a particular scene and
                came to the conclusion of creating a menu such that it serves the prime purpose of
                modifying ones’ perspective (in their case attracting new/old customers). To put it
                in more literal terms, they responded to a rhetorical situation by creating a new
                type of genre i.e. the dollar menu. Soon most of the fast food chains came out with
                their own version of the dollar menu. </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>Mc Donald’s is the world's largest chain of hamburger fast food restaurants,
                serving around 68 million customers daily in 119 countries across 36,538 outlets. It
                is considered that their method of coming up with a different menu for almost every
                country on the basis of an extensive market research has given them an edge over
                their rivals.<argument type="main"> For my genre analysis paper, I am going to
                    compare two separate Mc Donald’s menus and will be analysing their similarities
                    and differences on the basis of scene, situation and participants</argument>. I
                will conclude by explaining how is that they have created a new genre called menu,
                which has indirectly help them be succesfull. </bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p/>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>citation here</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will go here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
