<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>They're Magically...Nutritious?</title>
            <author xml:id="li.em"/>
            <date>10 October 2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p>General Mills created Lucky Charms in 1964 as the perfect children's cereal:
                    “toasted oats” for a healthful breakfast with marshmallow “charms” to appeal to
                    a child’s taste buds <citation>(General Mills)</citation>. Today, their targeted
                    consumers have flip-flopped-- or better worded, they are still the same
                    consumers, who are now adults. Lucky Charm’s targeted consumers have two roles:
                    one as parents of young children, and the other as sentimental adults who
                    remember the joy of eating the sugary cereal. <argument type="main"
                    > </argument></p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara>Lucky charms are aimed at adults as parents, but more importantly as
                consumers. Lucky charms uptakes as a sentimental piece of childhood for adults to
                enjoy again. <argument type="supporting"/> To begin with, the cereal’s outward
                appearance looks mostly unchanged from the original box. There is still the bright
                red color of the box and the large yellow Lucky Charms logo. Lucky the Leprechaun is
                still overtaken with joy as he presents his charms and a rainbow. This unwavering
                appearance will immediately take an adult back to pouring cereal out of the same box
                as a kid. The appearance is hence, uptaken positively, and hopefully enough to make
                a former consumer a current consumer, as it may drive those to ‘relive’ a positive
                experience.</bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>If adults are not moved to buy Lucky Charms for themselves, then they are
                buying for their children. Lucky charms have managed to still be relevant in a
                health-crazed 2016 through the rhetorical choice of using health buzzwords on every
                panel of the cereal box. <argument type="supporting"/> To stay on trend with food in
                America today, Lucky Charms happily announce that the cereal is gluten free
                    <citation>(Luckycharms.com)</citation>. They changed the way they process the
                cereal so no gluten gets mixed in, just to be able to label their cereal as
                pseudo-healthy. "Gluten-free" has become an attention-grabbing label for food
                products, that has somehow been automatically been associated with ‘healthy.’ Of
                course, there are people, such as Celiac Disease sufferers (1% of the population),
                who legitimately cannot consume gluten, but many Americans have fallen victim to
                marketing glamorizing being <q>“gluten-free.”</q> Furthermore, whole grains are
                another idolized phrase in the food industry. Lucky Charms assures parents that the
                cereal has <q>“11 grams of whole grains per serving”</q>
                <citation>(Lucky Charms)</citation>. Even though there is 10 grams of sugar per ¾ of
                a cup, which is about half the total daily sugar allowance for an eight year old
                child, , Lucky Charms and General Mills wants parents to believe the cereal is a
                nutritious breakfast <citation>(Family Education)</citation>. These words create a
                smoke screen which allow parents to believe, whether they truly do or not, that
                Lucky Charms are not as unhealthy as common sense would lead one to believe. This
                allows parents to feel better about allowing their children to eat the cereal, and
                for them to maybe grab a bowl as well. </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara> Finally, Lucky Charms aims to cast parents in the role of a responsible
                consumer, which would make them feel good about purchasing Lucky Charms. <argument
                    type="supporting"/> On one side panel of the cereal box, General Mills outlines
                all the ways it is benefiting the world. General Mills, the company that produces
                Lucky Charms, says they are “committed to sustainably source 100% of our cereal
                boxes by 2020.” As nice as this sounds, it is quite vague, and they offer no further
                reading on the topic. They also printed on the back that they are “giving back”
                through the Box Tops for Education™. Again, this sounds nice and wholesome, and it
                is. However, everything from office supplies to frozen meals also participate in
                this program, making it an industry norm, not setting General Mills apart. The most
                deceptive part of the cereal box is where they tote that Lucky Charms has 10 grams
                of sugar per serving, as if that is healthy. As mentioned before, 10 grams of sugar
                is almost half the allotment for kids aged 2-18 <citation>(American Heart
                    Association)</citation>. And, most kids (or adults) will eat more than the ¾ cup
                serving size. These true yet deceptive claims made on the side of the cereal box are
                not to fill up space, they are to convince consumers (parents) that buying Lucky
                Charms is a good choice not only for the health of you and your child, but also for
                the environment.</bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p>The genre of Lucky Charms is a cereal that is being targeted at adults-- but not
                    parents, adult consumers. A cereal as explicitly unhealthy as Lucky Charms, it
                    is still relevant in a health crazed 2016 America because General Mills has
                    focussed on eliciting wholesome and sentimental feelings from adults to drive
                    sales. Lucky Charms has managed to exploit common “buzzwords” of health to mask
                    the fact that the cereal is still sugar-coated, processed oar and marshmallows.
                    Yet, they are still admittedly quite magically delicious. </p>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>“General Mills: Lucky Charms.” General Mills: Lucky Charms,
                    https://www.generalmills.com/en/brands/cereals/lucky-charms. Baxalta. 
                    
                    “Need Luck? Here's a Spoonful.” Lucky Charms, http://www.luckycharms.com/original.
                    Hutton, Lindsay. “Are We Too Sweet? Our Kids' Addiction to Sugar.” 
                    
                    AHA
                    Guidelines and Recommended Sugar Intake for Kids, Family Education,
                    http://www.familyeducation.com/life/sugar/are-we-too-sweet-our-kids-addiction-sugar.
                    
                    “Children Should Eat Less than 25 Grams of Added Sugars Daily.” Welcome to the
                    AHA/ASA Newsroom, American Heart Association, 22 Aug. 2016,
                    http://newsroom.heart.org/news/children-should-eat-less-than-25-grams-of-added-sugars-daily?preview=df05.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>The author focuses the essay on talking about the success of Lucky Charms cereal and
                presents an argument showing the somewhat unethical side of the company. The author
                explains that Lucky charms were wildly popular in the past, and is still very
                popular today. The author understands and effectively demonstrates the use of ethos,
                pathos and logos. She says that the company appealed to the ethos side of people by
                ingeniously designing the box of the cereal. She said that “the cereal’s outward
                appearance looks mostly unchanged from the original box. There is still the bright
                red color of the box and the large yellow Lucky Charms logo”. This is an example of
                the author demonstrating a solid understanding of ethos, because she says that the
                one of the reasons why the the cereal was successful because the box was attractive.
                The author also touches on the pathos of the situation, by saying that “ Lucky
                charms uptakes as a sentimental piece of childhood for adults to enjoy again”. She
                reveals that the company appealed to the pathos of older people who ate the cereal
                when they were younger, by maintaining the same design and taste. The author has the
                appropriate tone, and she maintained and unbiased perspective on the topic by
                showing both sides of coin. For example, her diction represents her tone and
                perspective on the topic. When she says “These words create a smoke screen which
                allow parents to believe, whether they truly do or not, that Lucky Charms are not as
                unhealthy as common sense would lead one to believe”, she presents a skeptical
                viewpoint of the cereal. The author demonstrates that with false advertising, Lucky
                charms were able to convince people that the cereal was healthy. She develops the
                argument by saying that Lucky charms used Logos to further appeal to the people. By
                stating that “Lucky Charms assures parents that the cereal has 11 grams of whole
                grains per serving”, the author effectively analyzed the effect of logos on the
                human mind. With the positives of the written piece covered, there still may be a
                little room for improvement. Perhaps the author can expand on the language employed
                by lucky charms on their boxes, and analyze the effect of advertising language on
                this genre. In conclusion, this piece is an effective attempt at analyzing the genre
                of cereal boxes.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
