<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>Genre Analysis Paper: Reveiw: 'A Little Life' Hanya Yanigahara's Traumatic Tale
                of Male Friendship, New York Times</title>
            <author xml:id="lo.va"/>
            <date>10.07.16</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p><genre>A book review serves primarily as an informational resource, an assessment
                        and description of a work of fiction or non-fiction.</genre> Janet Maslin
                    begins her review of <citation source="#Book">“A Little Life”</citation> by
                    giving a general overview of the book she will be discussing, with details such
                    as when the book was published, size of the novel, and her first impressions.
                    Most noteably she writes: <q>"It’s a big, emotional, trauma-packed read with a
                        voluptuous prose style that wavers between the exquisite and the
                        overdone.</q>" <citation source="#Review">(Review, Janet Maslin NYT
                        2015)</citation> She also mentions that the book is shortlisted for a prize.
                    Her introductory paragraph is almost a review within the actual review itself,
                    as it gives a quick overview of the book’s timeline, and a brief description of
                    her thoughts and first impressions. In this paper, I aim to analyze how a book
                    review performs its function. <note type="peer" who="#to.fr"> What is your main
                        argument?</note><argument type="main">This particular genre of book reviews
                        exists to help potential readers decide whether they want to read the book
                        themselves.</argument><note type="instructor">my question in how you are
                        articulating your argument would be: how does your analysis specifically
                        facilitate this understanding of the genre?</note></p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara><argument type="supporting">A book review helps identify the main idea/plot of
                    the book</argument>, and gives the reader an indication of the writer’s style,
                and then give a general evaluation so the reader can then decide whether or not the
                book appeals to them. One rhetorical pattern that book reviews typically use is
                description. Every book review needs to accurately describe what type of book it is,
                what makes it worth reading, and what the plotline entails. Though a book review is
                principally written about the novel itself, an important element to include is some
                information about the author, which Maslin also includes in her piece. Including
                this biographical paragraph on Yanigahara is a tactical rhetorical choice made by
                Maslin to broaden the reader’s view of the book as a whole, instead of just focusing
                on the plotline, as some reviews do. However, Maslin includes some critical opinions
                of some areas in the book, for example; <q>“her mixing of metaphors makes for a
                    mess. The phantoms that haunt Jude can be hyenas with “snapping, foaming jaws”
                    at one moment, “banshees demanding his attention, snatching and tearing at him
                    with their long, needley fingers” the next.”</q>
                <citation source="#Review">(Review, Janet Maslin NYT 2015).</citation>
            </bodyPara>

            <bodyPara><situation>Something to consider in this genre is the difference between
                    fiction and non-fiction books being reviewed, as the genre can change
                    significantly depending on what type of book it is.</situation> The reader and
                reviewer pay attention to different things, for example with fiction, more of the
                review is dedicated to discussing the plot, characters, setting, and use of
                language. An interesting sentence that Maslin includes in her review in relation to
                character analysis reads: <q>"This is not a happy story. At its heart is Jude’s
                    secret suffering, and Malcolm and J. B. soon fade into minor characters as race
                    becomes a nonissue."</q>
                <citation source="#Review">(Review, Janet Maslin NYT 2015)</citation> This quote is
                very telling, as it gives you a sense of what the book's tone is. It's not a
                description of the story, it's an analysis of a part of the story from the
                reviewer's point of view. When discussing non-fiction, more focus is given to an
                author’s main argument and sources. <argument type="supporting">The role for the
                    reader in this genre is to read with a purpose, to decide whether to read the
                    book discussed or not. As for the writer of the review, he/she needs to write
                    with the purpose of identifying the author’s main plotlines, assessing the
                    quality and style of the writer’s work, also trying to compare the book to
                    another, or compare the writer with another to give an idea of what sort of
                    reading/writing it is.</argument> The writer should also put emphasis on the
                writer’s organization and style, and finally give a conclusion and a recommendation
                to readers. In Maslin's review, to conclude she writes: <q>"Ms. Yanagihara is still
                    capable of introducing great shock value into her story to override its
                    predictability."</q>
                <citation source="#Review">(Review, Janet Maslin NYT 2015)</citation> Another reader
                role is aimed at giving a librarian a description of a book. These reviews are
                generally shorter, and only give a description of the book and a short evaluation.
                    <participants>The main groups invited to participate in this genre are writers
                    and readers. Writers are generally employed by a newspaper or magazine, and it's
                    their job to review books so that the public can
                    read a general overview before the decide to buy the book in question. For
                    readers, those that want to get a better idea of what a book is about, in other
                    words something more than the blurb on the back of the book
                    itself.</participants></bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>This genre appears in many different forms of print, most often newspapers,
                magazines, journals, and specialized review publications. The most noteworthy review
                section in a newspaper is probably the <citation source="#Times">'Books of the
                    Times'</citation> section in the New York Times, which appears both in print and
                on their website. A review published in a famous or well-known newpaper can create
                'buzz' around a book, which helps the writer promote his/her work, and this is one
                of the principal methods of doing this, as there aren't any trailers like there are
                with a movie, so often a book review can help an author sell copies. Today most of
                these are available online, so you could say that the book review’s main platform
                today is the internet. Websites have been created with the sole purpose of posting
                book reviews, the most noteworthy being <citation source="#GR"
                    >'goodreads.com'</citation> and <citation source="#Kirkus"
                    >'kirkusreviews.com'</citation> However, print is not dead, and book reviews are
                still a huge part of publications such as the New York Times and the Guardian. Even
                though they are receiving a smaller audience because of the increase in digital
                media, they are still being printed and are still being read. </bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p><argument type="supporting">In summary, book reviews are an incredibly useful
                        tool for the modern reader, it saves time so you don't read something you
                        don't enjoy,</argument> and is <argument type="main">also useful for the
                        writer of the book as mostly constructive criticism, and help the author
                        promote the book.</argument> In my opinion, a book review definitely fulfils
                    its purpose of informing potential readers about the chosen book, and I think
                    that the genre is a very interesting one to anaylze, as book reviews essentially
                    analyze books. These days, less people have the time to go and peruse a book
                    shop for a few hours, this way you can find a book to read while you're reading
                    the paper, and then order it online, download it on a tablet, or make a much
                    quicker trip to the book shop. </p>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl xml:id="Book">Book: 'A Little Life', Hanya Yanigahara, published 2015,
                    DoubleDay Publishers </bibl>
                <bibl xml:id="Review">Review: ‘A Little Life,’ Hanya Yanagihara’s Traumatic Tale of
                    Male Friendship – Janet Maslin 30th September 2015 The New York Times, Books
                    Section http://www.nytimes.com/2015/10/01/books/review-a-little-life-
                    hanya-yanagiharas-traumatic-tale-of-male-friendship.html?_r=0</bibl>
                <bibl xml:id="Times">Books of The Times Section, New York Times Newspaper, New York
                    Times Online </bibl>
                <bibl xml:id="Kirkus">Kirkus Reviews-https://www.kirkusreviews.com/</bibl>
                <bibl xml:id="GR">Good Reads-https://www.goodreads.com/</bibl>

            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="to.fr"> Francheska Torres</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#to.fr">
            <p>In this paper, you are analyzing the genre of book reviews and is focusing
                specifically on 'A Little Life' by Hanya Yanigahara. You start off by introducing
                book reviews as a genre, then go on to explain their purpose, and the difference
                between book review for nonfiction and fiction work. It is clear to me that you are
                answering the questions of “Why does this genre exist?” and “Who is invited to use
                this genre? Who is not? How can you tell?” I do not however see a clearly stated
                main argument, so I don’t really know what your essay is trying to convey. Using
                tags might have been helpful for understanding what the main argument is. Also the
                lack of transitions from paragraph to paragraph makes the paper be separate chunks
                of text rather than a flowing essay. I feel like you should probably use more
                examples to support your claims (even though I don’t know what the claims are). It
                looks like the only piece of evidence you have is at the beginning where you wrote
                “her mixing metaphors…the next”. Even still with that evidence, I don’t know what
                they add to the review. I think that you should probably clean up the bottom of your
                second body paragraph, it was just very confusing to understand what you were
                saying. I know that that’s more of a grammar critique, but it would just be helpful.
                Finally, I thought your organization was really good! Your last body paragraph is
                also really nice. It is concise and makes sense and I can understand what you are
                trying to say very easily. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>There are a lot of things going well here. I think in particular you do a nice job of
                identifying evidence in the form of conventions. What needs some attention is your
                paragraph structure--at times you introduce multiple claims/arguments in a single
                body paragraph, other times is is unclear what your claim in a bady paragraph is. If
                restructuring, think about introducing one sub-claim for each body paragraph in the
                topic sentnce, then providing evidence, then analyzing that evidence to connect it
                back to your claim (as we discussed in class). I was also a little confused about
                where your main argument first appeared--it made your overall argument a bit hard to
                pin down. </p>
            <p><style type="italics">Note: Grading Citeria</style>. A successful genre analysis
                should: <list>
                    <item>Address one (or more) of the questions posed on the prompt: yes</item>
                    <item>Contain a clearly stated main argument: could be stated more clearly and
                        structured differently for better effectiveness </item>
                    <item>Emphasize evidence in support of claims (textual evidence or otherwise):
                        there are moments where evidence goes unanalyzed (i.e. it is unclear how
                        that evidence relates to your sub-claim or overall argument) </item>
                    <item>Use a few of the terms from the vocabulary list: yes, well done </item>
                    <item>Provide an overview of genre broadly (beyond an individual text): yes </item>
                    <item>Be detailed and focused: could be more focused--structural revision would
                        help this a great deal </item>
                    <item>Contain citations (in-text and works cited): yes</item>
                    <item>Be structured as an essay: yes </item>
                </list></p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
