<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>News Articles</title>
            <author xml:id="mi.as">Ashwin Misra</author>
            <date>October 7th, 2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p> World news articles serve a specific purpose in a newspaper. These articles are
                    written to inform the audience of events that are going on and that the audience
                    has an interest in. News networks and journals today are extremely detailed and
                    in-depth, covering relevant news from all over the World. <genre>CNN, one of the
                        most accredited and widely recognized news networks has adopted different
                        genres when responding to global news in the past compared to today. In this
                        essay I will be looking at the various differences in genres between the
                        year 2000, and the present, 2016.</genre><argument type="main">These
                        differences in genres will be explored with regards to scope of content and
                        language used to evaluate a situation– both between two news articles
                        published more than a decade and a half apart.</argument> I will also be
                    discussing the uptakes between the two genres and how the genres interact with
                    one another given the difference in the years published.</p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara><context>As a genre, news websites/ journals perform a unique task which is to
                    inform the public of current events that occur in the World around
                    them.</context><scene>Every news article from CNN (or any other news source, for
                    that matter) involves at least 1 scene and situation. Each CNN article contains
                    at least one scene as news is constantly packed with interactions between
                    different entities. For example, currently, the majority of articles and the
                    scenes developed within them involve politics as there is an election between
                    two presidential candidates coming up.</scene><situation>The situations built
                    within those scenes involve the actions of the participants. With regard to the
                    example given before, the situations built upon today’s political scene (in news
                    journals) reflect the actions of the presidential candidates.</situation>The
                rest of this genre analysis will analyze the differences in scenes and situations
                between CNN articles published online in 2000 and in 2016 with particular focus on
                language and scope of content to ultimately determine the changes in value of news
                writers and journalists <figure url="http://imgur.com/a/UGpLI"/></bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>Looking at the CNN page above from August 15, 2000, we can spot several
                articles surrounding the main article in the center, similar to how one could
                imagine modern-day online news articles to look like. However, the one contrasting
                aspect about the genre in the news in 2000 (above picture) is that the principle
                news is US news and not foreign news. <situation>Although regional news may also be
                    noteworthy, it is debatable whether “Clinton says Democrats hold keys to
                    future”, an article discussing Bill Clinton’s praise for the Democratic Party,
                    is more important that the reunion of families from North and South Korea who
                    have been estranged for decades</situation><citation>(CNN, 09/15/00)</citation>
                (which is seen in the “In Other News” section). CNN is “a 24-hour global
                multi-platform network”, which means that although it is an American news network,
                it is responsible for covering substantial global news. <participants>The fact that
                    World news is located in the “In Other News” section speaks a fair amount about
                    the values of the readers of news articles in the 2000s. It implies that the
                    target audience who read CNN news articles in the 2000s were Americans– not
                    global readers. The content of news from the 2000s suggests that American
                    audiences at the time were interested in scenes and the situations built within
                    those scenes for articles regarding the United
                States.</participants>Specifically, there is more mention of political news in
                newspapers in the 2000s. This means that news articles particularly valued political
                agendas and scenes and situations regarding politicians.<figure
                    url="http://imgur.com/a/wXQPM"/><note type="instructor">I fixed your figure
                    elements (the url for the image should be the attribute value for the @url
                    attribute)</note></bodyPara>
            <bodyPara><argument type="supporting">CNN adopts a contrasting view on online news
                    articles, as seen in the photo above (taken on October 6th, 2016).</argument>
                The breaking news is regarding Hurricane Matthew which is responsible for major
                damage in much of the North America region. “Matthew slams Haiti with 145-mph winds
                and heavy rain” is a global headline which suggests that the breaking news, the news
                which is the most essential for readers to be aware of, is in fact global and isn’t
                focused on America. <genre>This suggests a shift in genre and values to a global
                    scope rather than focusing purely on news from the United States, which may not
                    be as important.</genre> Furthermore, there seems to be restructure in the
                layout of the CNN website where “Top News” now consists of a mix of local and global
                news. CNN shifted their focus to global scenes which are more essential to audiences
                in the modern day. </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara><genre>There are some uptakes that help intertwine the changes in genre from
                    American-focused news articles in 2000 to global news articles in
                2016.</genre>One example of uptake which has persisted over the years is the use of
                photos. In 2000, photos of various scenes and the situations within them are shown
                in almost every news article. As shown in the CNN website in 2016, photos are still
                very useful as an uptake to help enhance articles. Of course, the photos in the
                modern day are more detailed and specific compared to those in 2000. Videos are more
                newly developed uptakes which, in a way, marked the transition from local to global
                news. Videos are a more expressive form of communication which can replace words.
                Videos tend to attract more audiences, which is why almost every news article in CNN
                today has at least one video included. </bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p>News articles on CNN, one of the leading news networks in America, have shifted
                    their genre focus from 2000 to 2016 from reporting more local-based news to
                    reporting breaking news from all over the world. CNN now reports on various
                    global scenes and develops on their respective situations and the parties which
                    are involved in those situations. As for the website itself, it has adopted a
                    more comprehensive layout which puts local news into focus just as much as it
                    does global news. CNN also integrates more videos into their news articles for
                    viewers who choose not wish to read the entire article.</p>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>"Internet Archive Wayback Machine." Internet Archive Wayback Machine.
                    WayBackMachine, n.d. Web. 6 Oct. 2016."CNN - Breaking News, Latest News and
                    Videos." CNN. Cable News Network, n.d. Web. 6 Oct. 2016.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="al.su"> Sultan ALdabal </reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Good essay in general. From what I understood, the essay focuses on two different
                genres relating to news articles, one focused in the past and one on the present. In
                my opinion, I think you should make your thesis statement more detailed to mention
                the complete overview of what you are going to write. Also, mentioning the uptakes
                that will be discussed might also help with guiding your essay in a more flow-like
                manner. The essay seems to be going in the direction of solving the prompt mentioned
                during class. However, stating the main argument in a clearer way would be more
                effective because it is slightly difficult to identify it. One thing you can improve
                on is mentioning what the genre actually is to help the people who are reading it
                for the first time understand what the essay is about. The body paragraphs are very
                detailed and well organized. I think you should also mention the genre itself in the
                introduction as it helps the reader know what the main idea of the essay is. I liked
                the examples you used in the body paragraphs, they were very descriptive. However, I
                think you should organize the sentences a bit differently, because they seem to go
                from topic to topic with a slightly hard to follow flow. Overall I liked the topic
                of the essay and the ideas you presented. Would appreciate it if you looked over my
                review.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
