<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>News Articles</title>
            <author xml:id="mi.as">Ashwin Misra</author>
            <date>October 7th, 2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p/>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara/>
            <bodyPara> A world news article serves a specific purpose in a newspaper. These articles
                are written to inform the audience of events that are going on and that the audience
                has an interest in. News networks and journals today are extremely detailed and
                in-depth, covering relevant news from all over the World. CNN, one of the most
                accredited and widely recognized news channels has adopted different genres when
                responding to global news in the past compared to today. In this essay I will be
                looking at the various differences in genre between the year 2000, and the present,
                2016. These differences in genre will be explored with regards to language used to
                evaluate a situation (between two news articles published in different years). I
                will also be discussing the uptakes between the two genres of the news
                articles</bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>The focus on the first news journal is on US news as global news and exposure
                to global events wasn’t as essential to the US population as news regarding their
                own country. The main body section has news about Bill Clinton, Hillary Clinton and
                Al Gore. The focus is much more political. The small ‘Other News’ section on the
                right has brief summaries on current affairs in other parts of the World. </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>In the 2016 CNN article, the breaking news is about Hurricane Matthew which is
                damaging the environment and threatening lives in countries in the Caribbean. As it
                is seen, it is international news which is in the front page rather than local news.
                The section on the left has an equal amount of US and global news, suggesting that
                there is a shift in genre toward current global current events. </bodyPara>

            <concl>
                <p/>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>citation here</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="al.su"> Sultan ALdabal </reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Good introduction in general. From what I understood, the essay focuses on two
                different genres relating to news articles, one focused in the past and one on the
                present. In my opinion, I think you should make your thesis statement more detailed
                to mention the complete overview of what you are going to write. Also, mentioning
                the uptakes that will be discussed might also help with guiding your essay in a more
                flow-like manner. The essay seems to be going in the direction of solving the prompt
                mentioned during class. However, stating the main argument in a clearer way would be
                more effective because it is slightly difficult to identify it. One thing you can
                improve on is mentioning what the genre actually is to help the people who are
                reading it for the first time understand what the essay is about. The body
                paragraphs are very detailed and well organized. I think you should also mention the
                genre itself in the introduction as it helps the reader know what the main idea of
                the essay is. I liked the examples you used in the body paragraphs, they were very
                descriptive. However, I think you should organize the sentences a bit differently,
                because they seem to go from topic to topic with a slightly hard to follow flow.
                Overall I liked the topic of the essay and the ideas you presented. Would appreciate
                it if you looked over my review.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
