<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>The Movie Review Genre</title>
            <author xml:id="ro.dy">Dylan Robinson</author>
            <date>7 October, 2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p>Movie reviews help many people decide on whether or not they should go see a
                    movie that they are interested in. <genre>They are a part of the larger review
                        genre which exists because people enjoy sharing their opinions on products
                        and many find it helpful to know other’s opinions when deciding on
                        something. Professional reviews still have the personal opinion of the
                        reviewer, but they also give an objective view on the product in an attempt
                        to not have the review be completely bias. Movie reviews generally go over
                        the plot, the actors’ performances, the soundtrack, and the visuals.</genre>
                    Many times if those aspects of the movie are good, the reviewer’s personal
                    opinion of the movie will be positive and vice versa. Traditionally reviews are
                    written, but with websites such as YouTube there are now many reviews that are
                    recorded and posted as videos. <argument type="main">These written reviews and
                        video reviews are both very similar, being part of the same genre, but they
                        have a few key differences that separate them. Video reviews almost feel
                        like a conversation with the reviewer due to the viewer being able to see
                        and hear the reviewer, although it is a one-way conversation. Written
                        reviews do not have this luxury and so they go into more detail about the
                        different aspects of the movie and how well the reviewer believes they
                        worked.</argument>
                    <situation>One way to see these similarities and differences is to look at two
                        positive reviews of the movie “Star Wars: The Force Awakens”, one written by
                        Anthony Lane and the other a video created by Chris Stuckmann. “Star Wars:
                        The Force Awakens” was a highly anticipated movie due to the popularity of
                        the franchise, so a lot of work went into the many reviews made about it.
                        These two reviews also try to look at the movie objectively while still
                        giving personal opinions.</situation></p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara><sim>Both the written review and the video review follow the movie review
                    genre.</sim>
                <genre>They talk about the general plot of the movie and how it was interesting. The
                    reviews go over how the effects and CGI look great while not being the focus and
                    how the sounds were great.</genre> With the newest entry in the Star Wars
                franchise having many new faces in its cast, both reviews talk a lot about the
                actors and how well they performed. <sim>Both reviewers loved the main protagonist
                    Rey</sim>, played by Daisy Ridley. “She straps herself in, swats aside any
                vestige of Mark Hamill, and takes command of the movie” <citation>(Lane)</citation>.
                Stuckmann said that “she steals the entire film”. <sim>They both liked many of the
                    new actors as well as the actors from the original Star Wars trilogy, namely
                    Harrison Ford in the role of Han Solo. Both reviews mention the soundtrack and
                    visuals being gorgeous. They mention that the movie “feels young”
                        <citation>(Lane)</citation>, that it is modern and fast paced in contrast to
                    slower pace of past Star Wars movies. Lane mentions one scene being “a feast for
                    the ears as well as the eyes, for it unfolds in a wintry forest. In addition to
                    the usual throbbing hum of the weapons, you can hear the sizzle of sabre on
                    snow, and the slicing hiss as the fighters miss their target and fell
                    surrounding pine trees by mistake”. He calls this “genuine cinematic texture”
                    that he says was missing from previous films <citation>(Lane)</citation>.
                    Stuckmann goes over this same point when he mentions that the movie “actually
                    feels like a movie” <citation>(Stuckmann)</citation>. The reviewers also go over
                    the director of the movie, J.J. Abrams, and how he did a great job with the
                    movie reassuring fans that the franchise is in good hands. <genre>Both reviews
                        talk about it all; the plot, the director, the cast, the soundtrack, the
                        visuals and more. They go over everything that the movie review genre calls
                        for in a review.</genre> That is how they are similar.</sim> But these two
                reviews still have differences, mainly the obvious one. <diff>One is a video of
                    someone talking about the movie and the other is just text.</diff> The written
                review has everything it needs to be in the movie review genre and that is all. The
                video review has a lot more. <diff>With the viewer being able to see and hear the
                    reviewer talk, a video review feels a lot more personal than just reading words.
                    Seeing their face and hearing their voice, the viewer can feel like they
                    actually know the reviewer as a person. In Stuckmann’s video review, the viewers
                    can hear how excited he is to be talking about the movie. His friendly tone of
                    voice being able to see his facial expressions also help the viewer trust his
                    opinion more. It is incredibly easy to tell that Stuckmann loved the movie and
                    is excited to talk about it. Watching his video review is almost like hearing a
                    trusted friend’s opinion instead of the opinion of some faceless movie
                    critic.</diff></bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p><sim>There are many similarities between the written and video movie reviews.
                        They are both perfect examples of the movie review genre.</sim>
                    <diff>But the video review is more approachable because of the fact that it is a
                        video that lets the viewer see who the reviewer is.</diff>
                    <genre>The movie review genre is clearly defined by these two reviews. It is
                        also easy to see how they fit in the overarching review genre. Despite the
                        differences between the written review and the video review, they are still
                        both a part of both the movie review genre and the review genre.</genre></p>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>Lane, Anthony. "“Star Wars: The Force Awakens” Reviewed - The New Yorker". The
                    New Yorker. N.p., 2015. Web. 7 Oct. 2016.</bibl>
                <bibl>Stuckmann, Chris. "Star Wars: The Force Awakens - Movie Review". YouTube.
                    N.p., 2016. Web. 7 Oct. 2016.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="we.sp">Spencer Webb</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#ro.dy">
            <p>This essay is about the genre of movie reviews, specifically focusing on two
                different forms of reviews of the same movie: Star Wars: The Force Awakens. You go
                into the similarities and differences of a written review and a video review. Early
                on, you said the movie reviews were objective, but the basis of a review is that it
                is subjective and based on personal opinion. In the first paragraph you write a lot
                about what the reviewers say in their reviews, but you don't talk much about what
                the content of the reviews say about the genre of reviews in general, whether it's
                online or written. You could speak more to what the reader/watcher of the review
                might take away from specific portions of the review, and maybe talk about how they
                might be getting other forms of input on the movie from other sources like word of
                mouth. Would you be more likely to see a movie if a good friend told you to go see
                it, or if some reviewer who you had no connection to told you to go see it. It's all
                about reliability of who you're talking to and whose opinions you trust. You might
                want to give some background on the Star Wars series and which actors play which
                characters instead of assuming that the reader is familiar with the movie. This
                could help the reader to be more impacted by the quotes you pull from the reviewers.
                You could maybe also talk about the irony of you not being able to convey your
                message as clearly as if you were making a video talking about these genres, because
                you argued that the video review had an easier time getting his message across
                without needing to use any "fancy language". I think it would be valuable to compare
                the genre of movie reviews to the over-arching genre of reviews in general in the
                conclusion. You should also add citations in the bibliography of the reviews you
                did, and anything else you drew from.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
