<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>Types of Movie Reviews</title>
            <author xml:id="">Dylan Robinson</author>
            <date>7 October, 2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p>Movie reviews help many people decide on whether or not they should go see a movie 
                   that they are interested in. With many movies coming out around the same time and the theater 
                   costing a fair amount of money, many people need to decide on one movie out of a few that they would like to 
                   go see. Movie reviews help out with this, and with the internet there are now more ways to find 
                   out if a movie is worth seeing or not. There are still written reviews, but now there are many people 
                   on websites such as YouTube who create video reviews for movies. <argument type="main">The written review 
                   and the video review are both part of the same movie review genre, but they have a few key differences 
                   that separate them.</argument> Video reviews allow the viewer to see exactly how the reviewer 
                   feels about a movie while written reviews rely on just text to convey the reviewer’s feelings 
                   about a movie. One way to see these similarities and differences is to look at two reviews of 
                   the movie “Star Wars: The Force Awakens”, one written by Anthony Lane and a video 
                   created by Chris Stuckmann. “Star Wars: The Force Awakens” was a highly anticipated movie, 
                   so a lot of work went into the many reviews made about it.</p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara><sim>Both the written movie review and the video movie review are a part of the <genre>movie review genre and the 
                even larger review genre which exists because people enjoy sharing their opinions and others like to hear 
                about those opinions to help them decide if they want the product or not.</genre></sim> <genre>A movie review has one main goal, 
                to help the reader decide if they want to see the reviewed movie or not. It does this by giving the reviewer’s 
                personal opinion of the movie and then having the reviewer look at the movie objectively to tell the reader if 
                it is a well made and well thought out movie or not. The review goes over the actors’ performances, the plot, 
                the effects and other aspects found in all movies.</genre> Lane talks about how Daisy Ridley <citation source="Lane">“straps 
                    herself in, swats aside any vestige of Mark Hamill, and takes command of the movie”(Lane)</citation>. These 
                reviews for “Star Wars: The Force Awakens” also compare the movie to its predecessors. For example, 
                <citation source="Lane">Anthony Lane compares a scene in the movie where a character uses the Force to pull 
                    a lightsaber towards them to the scene in “The Empire Strikes Back” when Luke Skywalker does the same 
                    thing (Lane)</citation>. The movies are also compared in the video review. <citation source="Stuckmann">Stuckmann 
                        talks about how he loved the movie as much as the original “Star Wars” and more 
                        than “Return of the Jedi” (Stuckmann)</citation>. 
                All of this is what the written review and the video review have in common because they are part of the movie 
                review genre.
            </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>While the written review and the video review both discuss the same topics, they do it in very different ways. 
                <diff>In the video review, <evidence><citation source="Stuckmann">Stuckmann talks as if he is having a conversation with you. Since you can see him in the video, 
                you see his facial expressions and can hear his tone of voice as he talks about the movie. It is easy to tell that 
                he loved the movie and is excited to talk about it, even when he is talking about its flaws. Pictures also show up 
                in the video to help show what he is talking about during the review (Stuckmann)</citation></evidence>.</diff> With the written review, <diff>Lane 
                needs to work harder to get his point across. He does not have luxury of his audience being able to hear and see 
                him talk about the movie, so he need to be much  more descriptive in what he says than Stuckmann needs to in the 
                video review.</diff> This can be seen when he talks about Adam Driver’s performance. <citation source="Lane">“So well is Driver cast against type 
                here that evil may turn out to be his type, and so extraordinary are his features, long and quiveringly gaunt, 
                that even when he removes his headpiece you still believe that you’re gazing at some form of advanced alien” (Lane)</citation>. 
                Another example is when Lane uses imagery to talk about how cinematic a scene in the movie was. <citation source="Lane">“One battle, in 
                particular, is a feast for the ears as well as the eyes, for it unfolds in a wintry forest. In addition to the usual 
                throbbing hum of the weapons, (jazzed up a little for this movie, I fancy), you can hear the sizzle of sabre on 
                snow, and the slicing hiss as the fighters miss their target and fell surrounding pine trees by mistake” (Lane)</citation>. 
                <diff>This shows how Lane must resort to using descriptive words and specially structured sentences to convey his feelings 
                about the movie. He cannot just simply say he loved the movie, that the actors were phenomenal and that the director 
                did a great job like Stuckmann can get away with in his video review. While Stuckmann just talks about how well 
                actors performed and how great the film looked, Lane needs to describe what the actors did and exactly what the 
                film looked like and how cinematic scenes were.</diff>
            </bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p><diff>The written review and the video review have big differences. The video review just tells the audience about 
                    the movie and how the reviewer feels about it while the written review describes how good the movie was to 
                    convey how the reviewer feels about it.</diff> <sim>But they still both have many similarities. They talk about the same 
                    topics and try to help their audience decide if they want to see the movie or not.</sim> <genre>Despite their differences, 
                    both the written review and the video review fit clearly in the movie review genre.</genre></p>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>citation here</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="we.sp">Spencer Webb</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#ro.dy">
            <p>This essay is about the genre of movie reviews, specifically focusing on two different
            forms of reviews of the same movie: Star Wars: The Force Awakens. You go into the
            similarities and differences of a written review and a video review. Early on, you said 
            the movie reviews were objective, but the basis of a review is that it is subjective and 
            based on personal opinion. In the first paragraph you write a lot about what the reviewers 
            say in their reviews, but you don't talk much about what the content of the reviews say 
            about the genre of reviews in general, whether it's online or written. You could speak 
            more to what the reader/watcher of the review might take away from specific portions of 
            the review, and maybe talk about how they might be getting other forms of input on the 
            movie from other sources like word of mouth. Would you be more likely to see a movie if a 
            good friend told you to go see it, or if some reviewer who you had no connection to told 
            you to go see it. It's all about reliability of who you're talking to and whose opinions 
            you trust. You might want to give some background on the Star Wars series and which actors
            play which characters instead of assuming that the reader is familiar with the movie. This
            could help the reader to be more impacted by the quotes you pull from the reviewers. You 
            could maybe also talk about the irony of you not being able to convey your message as
            clearly as if you were making a video talking about these genres, because you argued that
            the video review had an easier time getting his message across without needing to use any
            "fancy language". I think it would be valuable to compare the genre of movie reviews to
            the over-arching genre of reviews in general in the conclusion. You should also add 
            citations in the bibliography of the reviews you did, and anything else you drew from.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
