<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>BPS Protest</title>
            <author>Jhadley Sanchez</author>
            <date>09/04/2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p>A lot of people use many genres when it comes to communicate their dissagremet
                    with those who make the decisions for the public. Many of there genres can
                    include advocacy, letters, newspaper articles, etc. One particular genre that
                    comes to be very broad is <genre>protest</genre>. <argument type="main"
                        >Throughout our history we have seen people uptake the genre of protest and
                        the most interesting part is that there is never the same outcome since not
                        every event plays out the same exact way every time around.This makes this
                        genre very complex when looked from a greater point of view.</argument>
                    <scene>One particular event that can be looked at when it comes to this genre is
                        the series protest that occured throughout the district of the Boston Public
                        Schools</scene>. These protest were held by students and parents throughout
                    the city who refused to accept the reforms that the city was trying to bring up
                    to the system. Each and every protest leading to a different outcome </p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara>The new plan to cut the budget from the Boston Public Schools system sparked
                different concern in students, parents and teachers; since this meant that student's
                education could be affected as well as job among other things. The matter was taken
                into students' hands who quickly came up with ways to communicate their concerns
                with this new system that was bound to affect the lives of those whose education
                depends on the public system. What exactly makes students take up this genre of
                protest to convey the message they are trying to deliver<note type="peer"
                    who="#ko.di"> Is the last sentence a question?</note>. As we have seen before,
                throughout the history of this country people have found that protest can lead to
                people understanding that the voices of the underdog are indeed important. What
                exactly makes protest this element that people decide to uptake and created
                different outcomes depending on the type of situation they see themselves and those
                around them in.<note type="peer" who="ko.di"> The last sentence seems a little
                    unclear to me. Could you elaborate or refine it a little?</note>
            </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara><evidence>“We are the future of this country,” one student speaker said. “How
                    dare they take away our education when they want us to be well-rounded
                    students.”</evidence> was stated by a student in an article that was published
                proceeding the protest. Students, like this one, found themselves concerned about
                not only their education, but the country as a whole, which is why people decided
                that protest would be the one way to address the issues. Protest are the one thing
                that are not foreseen by the media and those in power, which makes this genre
                useful. But what exactly makes protest a complex genre when it comes to this
                specific issue is different situations that play out relatively different every time
                around. How can people use this genre if there is no way of predicting what exactly
                will happen when people use protest to express their concern to the public. </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>This genre, just like other genres, becomes more complex in the aspect of
                analyzing, simply because the genres shift into new genres in a given situation.
                Example being, a protest could shift to a whole new genre which is violence. Now,
                this is what it is meant when we talk about genres being complex. </bodyPara>
            <bodyPara>Going back to the particular protest that occurred in Boston due to the budget
                cut in the education system, different genres arose; public hearings among others
                    <note type="peer" who="#ko.di"> Could you possibly show evidence of the public
                    hearing?</note>. The most important part about this issue is how this genre of
                protest becomes so important in this particular situation and in other situations in
                general. People, in this case students, needed to find a particular action that
                could lead to the change of the situation that was in play. This is why, not only
                this genre but many others become very important. Since they help people when it
                comes to a given situation. </bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p>In a lot of cases, people use different types of genre to approach their given
                    situation. Since students in the Boston Public School system saw that there was
                    a new decision being brought forward that they had to change, they understood
                    that this genre made the most sense. And even though they could not exactly
                    predict what outcomes this genre would bring up, it still confirmed the fact
                    that using genres do not bring out the same outcome since situations are not
                    played the same way when people look at it. It also depends on the perspective
                    that it is being looked at from and how people decide to uptake this genre. In
                    this particular event, people analyzed previous situations when this genre was
                    put in play, and they went for it. With the understanding that new genres could
                    possibly also come up. </p>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Boston Student Walk Out</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl> Fox, By Jeremy C. "Boston Students Walk out over Cuts." Boston Students Walk
                    out over Cuts. Globe, n.d. Web. 06 Oct. 2016. </bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="ko.di"> Divit Koradia </reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="ko.di">
            <p> In the above genre analysis paper, Jhadley is talking about how students, parents
                and teachers used protest as a genre to voice their opinions on the new plan to cut
                the budget from the Boston Public Schools. In my opinion, you do a very thorough job
                in describing the genre and how it is related to your topic. You give a very brief
                yet proper explanation of the situation in which the genre, protest, is being used
                by the students which helps the reader thoroughly understand your paper. I feel you
                should add a couple more evidences to solidify your argument. You could perhaps take
                a small quote which describes how the budget cut would affect the management of the
                publics schools. This would add a different standpoint in your paper which would
                help the readers’ asses the gratitude of this situation much better. Also you could,
                if you want, elaborate the motif behind the government cutting down the budget from
                Boston Public Schools. This would add another element to your paper which you could
                somehow interlink with your main genre. Overall I find your paper very fascinating.
                I feel like you have covered all the assessment criteria. A couple of sentence need
                to be reframed! </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
