<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>BPS Protest</title>
            <author>Jhadley Sanchez</author>
            <date>09/04/2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p>A lot of people use many genres when it comes to communicate their dissagremet
                    with those who make the decisions for the public. Many of there genres can
                    include advocacy, letters, newspaper articles, etc. One particular genre that
                    comes to be very broad is protest. Throughout our history we have seen people
                    uptake the genre of protest and the most interesting part is that there is never
                    the same outcome since not every event plays out the same exact way every time
                    around.This makes this genre very complex when looked from a greater point of
                    view. <scene>One particular event that can be looked at when it comes to this genre is
                    the series protest that occured throughout the district of the Boston Public
                    Schools</scene>. These protest were held by students and parents throughout the city who
                    refused to accept the reforms that the city was trying to bring up to the
                    system. Each and every protest leading to a different outcome </p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara>The new plan to cut the budget from the Boston Public Schools system sparked
                different concern in students, parents and teachers; since this meant that student's
                education could be affected as wel as job among other things. The matter was taken
                into students' hands who quickly cam eup with ways to communicate their concerns
                with this new system that was bound to affect the lives of those whose education
                depends on the public system.</bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p/>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>citation here</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will go here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
