<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>Similarities, Differences, and Uptake within Theatres Programs</title>
            <author xml:id="to.fr">Francheska Torres</author>
            <date>10/07/16</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
                <p>
                    <scene>The theatre is a place of magic, a place where you go to listen to stories told by the best story tellers you know. </scene>
                    <situation>Milling around <setting>the theatre's many rooms </setting>you would find many different types of people: <participants>excited playgoers, the reluctant spouses and families they drag along, 
                        nervous actors getting ready for the show, and stony faced attendants handing out programs to name a few.</participants></situation> <genre>Theatre playbills and
                    programs come in many shapes and forms: from the glossy standard Playbills we receive at professional theatres to the paper- cut
                    inducing booklets of school productions</genre>. Playbills and programs are an intrinsic part of a theatregoer’s experience: as soon as 
                    they walk in the door to the auditorium they expect to be handed a program. <context>They allow us, the audience, to know a bit more about
                    the show we are about to watch as well as to be more informed about upcoming shows. They also act as souvenirs, allowing us to look 
                    back fondly at the night of the show.</context> <argument type="main">Not only do playbills and programs provide a record of past performances they also provide an 
                        avenue through which we can explore the history of the time during which play was performed</argument>.
                </p>
            </intro>
            
            <bodyPara>
              Early playbills from the early 1800s were <aesthetics>single sheets of paper, usually printed in black and white, handed out in the theatre or posted in public places as broadsides  <citation source="#citation2">(Higgins).</citation></aesthetics> 
             They provided the public with basic information about a particular show: name, date, place, and time. Additionally, they contained the name of the author, a list of the actors and 
             the characters that they portrayed and an advertisement of future performances. Very often, the name of the most popular performer was often printed in bigger, more pronounced fonts 
             in order to catch the public’s attention; this is evident in the playbill for Henry A. Jones’ <style type="italics">Whitewashing Julia</style> <citation source="#citation1">(“1904 Fay Davis Broadside”)</citation>. As time went on these single sheet 
              playbills became bigger and bigger, eventually reaching poster-size. Because of their size, they became too cumbersome to handle and lead to the need for our modern day programs. 
                
                <figure url="http://i.imgur.com/9Up9tYl.png"> Whitewashing Julia Playbill</figure>
    
            </bodyPara>
            
            <bodyPara>
                Modern programs are more visually pleasing and offer more in depth information than early playbills did. They usually include cast biographies, 
                pictures of the cast, a list of songs and who sings them (if the show is a musical). Additionally, inside the booklet, there are short articles 
                focusing on the artists as well as considerable advertising from other businesses. <aesthetics>They come in the form of colorful booklets, with the title of 
                the show, and a related picture, on the outside in bold black letters right underneath “PLAYBILL” at the top of the page in a yellow rectangle.</aesthetics> 
                The standard layout for these modern playbills can be traced back all the way back to before the 1960s. The similarities between the playbills for 
                Sweet Bird of Youth <citation source="#citation5">(“Playbill for Sweet Bird of Youth.”)</citation> and Hamilton <citation source="#citation4">(“Playbill for Hamilton.”)</citation>, which are separated by almost six decades, show
                how powerful effective communication aesthetics can be. 
                
                <figure url="http://i.imgur.com/Fq0JCxT.png"> Hamilton Playbill</figure>
                <figure url="http://i.imgur.com/j7hHxXZ.png"> Sweet Bird of Youth Playbill</figure>
            
            </bodyPara>
            
            <bodyPara> 
          
                Much of the information from the early playbills was taken up by modern theatre programs. <sim>Both tell the audience what the name of the show is, 
                where and when it will be shown, who is in the show and what they play, as well as advertise upcoming plays.</sim> <diff>Some elements from early playbills 
                evolved, rather than being cut out completely. For example, instead of getting rid of the descriptions of what happens in each act, modern playbills 
                expanded on the idea and now involve a list of scenes in the show. Additionally, instead of getting rid of advertising for other shows in the playbills, 
                modern programs also include advertisements for different types of businesses. </diff>
                
            </bodyPara>
            
            <bodyPara>
                <evidence>
                A lot can be learned about the history of the time from reading a theatre playbill. For example, during the time of early playbills, there was no television, 
                there were no movies, and there certainly wasn’t such a thing as Netflix. Theatre was the only popular form of entertainment, therefore printing all of the 
                playbills was necessary in order to inform the public about shows to see. In modern times, we have endless avenues of communication: from radio shows, to TV
                commercials, to billboards by highways. Additionally, with the rise in popularity of Netflix, people tend to stay in to watch shows, rather than putting in
                the time and effort it takes to go to a show at the Theatre. This was not an option in the late 19th and early 20th centuries. Printing technology was also
                not as advanced then as it is today. This means that even the cheapest playbills and programs were of high quality when compared to those of today because 
                they were more low tech and didn’t have our quick laser printing technology. Finally, during the time of early theatre programs, paid commercial advertising
                was not very popular, contributing to the lack of outside advertisement in playbills <citation source="#citation3">(Jewett)</citation>.  
                </evidence>
            </bodyPara>
            
            <bodyPara>
                <evidence>
                With the boom in printed advertisement came the realization that theatre programs could become literary goldmines. 
                By the early 1900s, businessman Frank Strauss was the first to become the first to specialize in programmed printing. By assuring 
                business owners that their companies would get lots of circulation among more “upstanding” theatergoers and they would gain large 
                profits by paying for ads, Strauss secured his fortune and forever changed the design and layout of programs <citation source="#citation6">(“Variety Stage: Theater
                    Playbills and Programs”)</citation>. The success of this specific marketing strategy tells us much about the scene of theatre at that time. It shows
                us that going to the theatre was a more of a way of flaunting status than of having fun for some people, specifically the upper class patrons 
                of different theatres. It also shows us that whether we are in the late 19th century or in the early 21st century, the more “cultured” parts 
                of life will always be catered more towards the rich and wealthy rather than the common man. 
                </evidence>
            </bodyPara>

            <concl>
                <p>
                    To conclude, the genre of playbills and programs does more than just inform the public about a show or to inform the audience about the specifics 
                    of the show they are about to see. They offer a great way to see how history has changed the world around us in the specific context of the world of 
                    theatre. Without playbills, the popularity and awareness of theatre would have decreased significantly and the concept of going to the theatre to watch
                    a show could possibly be obsolete.
                    
                </p>
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl xml:id="citation1">“1904 Fay Davis Broadside.” Ebay.com, Ebay, 31 July 2016, http://www.ebay.com/itm/1904-park-theatre-boston-massachusetts-fay-davis-broadside-/390670654882?hash=item5af5c91da2.
                </bibl>
                
                <bibl xml:id="citation2">Higgins, Sydney. “A History of Playbills and Theatre Programs.” A History of Playbills and Theatre Programs, Camerino Players, 2009, http://www.the-camerino-players.com/playbills/index.html.
                </bibl>
                
                <bibl xml:id="citation3"> Jewett, Rebecca. “Playbills Collection.” Playbills Collection, Jerome Lawrence and Robert E. Lee Theatre Research Institute, 10 May 2016, https://library.osu.edu/find/collections/theatre-research-institute/ephemera/playbills-collection/.
                </bibl>
                
                <bibl xml:id="citation4">“Playbill for Hamilton.” Playbill Vault, Playbill, http://www.playbill.com/production/hamilton-richard-rodgers-theatre-vault-0000014104.
                </bibl>
                
                <bibl xml:id="citation5">“Playbill for Sweet Bird of Youth.” Playbill Vault, Playbill, http://www.playbill.com/production/sweet-bird-of-youth-martin-beck-theatre-vault-0000008261.
                </bibl>
                
                <bibl xml:id="citation6"> “Variety Stage: Theater Playbills and Programs.” Variety Stage: Theater Playbills and Programs, Library of Congress, 
                    http://memory.loc.gov/ammem/vshtml/vsprge.html.
                    
                </bibl>
                
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="lo.va"> Valentina Longcroft</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Summary: Playbills have been, and still are, an integral part of the theatre. They serve as an
            informational resource, providing actor's names and details of the play, and also serve as 
            memorabilia and historical artefacts as before the rise of technology, they were the only records of
            the play, and people used to keep them as souvenirs, as they still do today sometimes.</p>
            <p>Critique: Though this paper is a very well rounded analysis on playbills, I think that maybe
            a few examples of certain playbills/plays and how they fulfilled their purpose may be a good addition,
            as there are no sources/citations at the moment. You also haven't used too many words from the element
            list, even though your tags are well placed, it would be nice to see you write about the scene or situation
            as well as tagging it in your text. This was very interesting to read, and I think the topic of 
            playbills is fascinating, but I think there is definitely room to expand your arguments and sub arguments.</p> 
            <p>Advice: You could use images very effectively in this paper, 
            maybe one of an older playbill and one of a more modern one, to give the reader a visual., as you've chosen a 
            genre with a visual aspect, I think it would be wise to take advantage of this. Though I think that
            your point about modern/historical playbills is really interesting, I think you maybe need another point or argument, 
            maybe you could write about who writes the playbills and the format used with them? It would be interesting to hear about
            the order which the playbills are written in, and also a bit more about the history of advertising with playbills, and when
            they started to use it. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
