<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>Similarities, Differences, and Uptake within Theatres Programs</title>
            <author xml:id="to.fr">Francheska Torres</author>
            <date>10/07/16</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
            <intro>
<<<<<<< Updated upstream
                <p></p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara></bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p></p>
=======
                <genre>Theatre playbills and programs come in many shapes and forms, from the glossy standard Playbills we receive at professional theatres, to the black and white booklets of school plays.</genre> 
                Playbills and programs are an intrinsic part of a <setting>Theatre</setting> goer's experience: as soon as you walk in the door you expect to be handed a program. 
                They allow us, <participants>the audience</participants>, to know a bit more about the show we are about to see as well as to be more informed about upcoming shows. 
                They also act as souvenirs, allowing us to look back fondly at the night of the show. 
                <mainArgument>Not only do playbills and programs a record of theatrical performances and practices, as a whole they are also a good way to explore the culture and history of the time</mainArgument> 
            </intro>
            
            <bodyPara>
                <aesthetics>Early playbills were single sheets, usually printed in black and white, handed out in the theatre or posted in public places as broadsides.</aesthetics>
                They provided the public information about a particular show: date, place, and time; a list of the actors and the characters that they portrayed and an advertisement of future performances. 
                <context>As time went on these single sheet playbills became bigger and bigger, eventually reaching poster-size; they became too cumbersome to handle and this lead to the need for our modern day programs.</context> 
            </bodyPara>
            
            <bodyPara>
                Modern playbills offer the same basic information as early playbills did, but also go more in depth. 
                They usually include cast biographies, pictures of the cast, a list of songs and who sings them (if the show is a musical).  
                <aesthetics>They are in the form of colorful booklets, with the title of the show on the outside in bold black letters right underneath “PLAYBILL” at the top of the page in a yellow rectangle.</aesthetics> 
                Inside the booklet, there are short articles focusing on the artists as well as considerable advertising from other businesses. 
                .</bodyPara>
            
            <bodyPara>
                <sim>Many of the same information from the early playbills was taken up by modern theatre programs. 
                    They all tell the audience what the name of the show is, where and when it will be shown, who is in the show and what they play, as well as advertise upcoming plays. </sim>
                <diff>Some elements from early playbills evolved, rather than being cut out completely. 
                For example, instead of getting rid of the descriptions of what happens in each act, modern playbills expanded on the idea and now involve a list of scenes in the show. 
                Additionally, instead of getting rid of advertising in the playbills, modern programs also include advertisements from businesses. </diff>  
            </bodyPara>
            
            <bodyPara>
                A lot can be learned about the history of the time from reading a theatre playbill. 
                For example, in the time of early playbills, there was no TV, there were no movies, and there certainly wasn’t any Netflix.
                Theatre was the only popular form of entertainment, so they had to print out the playbills individually because people couldn’t carry posters. 
                In modern times, if something wasn’t convenient we would most likely forget about it and move on to the next best more convenient thing. 
                Printing technology was also not as advanced as it is today. This means that even the cheapest programs were pretty high quality compared to 
                now because they were more low tech and didn’t have our quick laser printing technology. Finally, during the time of early theatre programs, paid 
                commercial advertising was not very popular, and that’s why we did not see many advertisements for other businesses in the playbills. 
                Obviously, that is not the case in our present day playbills.    
            </bodyPara>
            
            <concl>
                In conlusion, playbills and programs are more than just a way to inform the public about a show or to inform the audience about the specifics of the show they are about to see. 
                Playbills and programs are a great way to see how history has changed the world around us in the specific context of the world of Theatre. 
            </concl>
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>citation here</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will go here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
