<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title>Rhyming to Popularity</title>
            <author xml:id="we.sp">Spencer Webb</author>
            <date>October 7th, 2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>

            <intro>
                <p>There are two types of listeners when its comes to rap music. There are those who
                    strictly care about the melody, beat, and flow of the music, and those who pay
                    closer attention to the lyrics and message of the music.<note type="instructor"
                        >why not both??</note> For a long time, I found myself as being the former
                    type of listener, glazing over the lyrics as I knew the words, but never
                    considering the content. However, I recently started paying attention to the
                    message, and sometimes the idea is simple and self-promoting, but sometimes it
                    isn't. Often times artists have the ability tell a story that can draw you in
                    just as much as the melody and beat itself. Because of this, the most successful
                    artists are ones that can combine both a powerful or relatable message with an
                    enticing beat. <genre>The hip hop/rap genre <note type="peer" who="#ro.dy">Is
                            there a difference between rap and hip hop?</note> is unique in that
                        there is no specific route that rappers will take to become a rapper.
                        Rappers are not often born following an engineering degree.<note
                            type="instructor">you mean sound engineering?</note> Because of this,
                        much of the style of rap is based on era and what is taken up over
                        decades.</genre> There is successful and unsuccessful rap music from all
                    sub-genres of rap, but generally we are only exposed to those who were the most
                    successful in targeting what people wanted to hear.<argument type="main">Thus we
                        can observe how <note type="instructor">the</note> hip hop scene has shifted
                        in recent years, and from this, make claims about how hip hop fits in the
                        grander scheme of music as a cultural element.<note type="instructor">well
                            stated argument, interested in how you support it</note></argument></p>
            </intro>

            <bodyPara>When thinking of early influential rap artists, two groups immediately come to
                mind: N.W.A. and the Wu-Tang Clan. <sim>These two groups released two of the most
                    popular albums of the late 80's/early 90's: "Straight Outta Compton" (1988) and
                    "Enter the Wu-Tang (36 Chambers)" (1993). These two groups also possessed a
                    quality that is not often seen in the spotlight today: they were groups. They
                    were groups of individual talent that shared both a common background and a
                    common goal.</sim>
                <diff>N.W.A. set out primarily to send a message, while the Wu-Tang Clan set out to
                    establish themselves as the best, combining progressive beats, dark humor and
                    inventive sounds. Because of this, the groups became popular for drastically
                    different reasons. N.W.A.'s message was anti-establishment and worked to fight
                    police racism, specifically in areas closer to the members' homes.<note
                        type="instructor">yeah, does it matter that Wu-Tang is from NY and NWA is
                        from Comptom? Especially in an era when the internet didn't really exist, it
                        seems like these might actually be two separate scenes</note>
                    <context>At the time of release, the message was extremely relevant, and their
                        local popularity soared, allowing them to spread propaganda through their
                        music.</context> However, as time passed and the culture shifted, along with
                    other extenuating circumstances, the group disbanded. They didn't have a
                    sustainable game plan. After N.W.A was around the time that rap music became a
                    genre of music that appealed to a larger audience outside strictly
                    African-American culture (as evidenced by the fact that I am a white male
                    writing this essay).<note type="instructor">a good thing to address</note> The
                    Wu-Tang Clan arose from the ashes of N.W.A to bump beats and bash heads (or at
                    least rap about doing so).</diff> They took over the market that was now well
                established. They developed a sound that became recognizable very quickly. It was
                music that all fans of rap music could enjoy whether they agreed with what was being
                said or not.<note type="instructor">why is that the case? couldn't someone just not
                    be that into Wu-Tang?</note> For this reason they have maintained a presence in
                rap culture as a group, <evidence>making releases even over 21 years later such as
                    "A Better Tomorrow" released in 2014</evidence>; <note type="peer" who="#ro.dy"
                    >Maybe mention one of their newer releases as an example</note>the beats don't
                lose relevance like content does. <diff>However, solo work has almost completely
                    taken over group hip hop in today's culture, as with the rise of media and
                    broadcasting, solo work is much more fruitful.<note type="instructor">what do
                        you mean by 'fruitful' here? financially? in terms of circulation?
                        artistically?</note></diff> It's much easier to present yourself as a solo
                artist in terms of interviews, awards, putting on shows, and even just giving
                listeners one person to listen to and one face to look at.<note type="instructor"
                    >okay</note>
                <diff>The idea of a relatable message garnering popularity quickly still exists, but
                    in a different way.</diff> A perfect example of a solo artist who has gained
                massive popularity recently is Drake. <setting>Drake has helped to integrate hip hop
                    music into America's music culture instead of hip hop being primarily culturally
                    African- American.</setting> Drake captures such a large audience because the
                content of his music targets such a wide array of people. <evidence>Much of Drake's
                    music is about relationship problems, insecurities, and social media, all things
                    that listeners can relate to without much difficulty. Now exists behind the
                    scenes employees working day in, day out crafting beats and melodies that will
                    be stuck in listener's ears. This, the content, and showmanship all wrapped up
                    in one package gives <note type="peer" who="#ro.dy">"gives" instead of
                        "give"</note> consumers almost the ideal pop/rap icon. This is evident when
                    considering that Drake's most recent album "Views" spent over 12 weeks topping
                    the Billboard 200 Chart.</evidence>
                <evidence>With a transforming culture shifting towards a greater appreciation of rap
                    music, it's no wonder that the 2015 movie named after N.W.A's biggest hit
                    "Straight Outta Compton" was such a hit. This movie was also influential in
                    re-demonstrating the value of spreading messages through rap, using the N.W.A.'s
                    formation and destruction as one of the most significant examples of the power
                    of music.</evidence>
            </bodyPara>

            <concl>
                <p>Rap music has been culturally significant for decades now, and it’s fairly easy
                    to point fingers at who to thank. The N.W.A. and Wu-Tang Clan truly paved the
                    way to influence rap music in a way that other artists couldn’t. We can see how
                    artists have drawn inspiration from the achievements of these groups, and the
                    changing appreciation of rap music in American culture has allowed a greater
                    flourishing of rap music today. Successful rap music has been shown to be music
                    that can catch your ear, make you bob your head, and also offer something a
                    little more for those who care to delve deeper into the content of the music.
                </p>
            </concl>

        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl xml:id="Connor">Connor, Martin. "Rapper's Flow Encyclopedia - Earl
                    Sweatshirt." Genius. Genius Media Group Inc., n.d. Web. Oct. 2016.</bibl>
                <bibl xml:id="Ballard">Ballard, Mary E., Doris G. Bazzini, and Alan R. Dodson.
                    "Genre of Music and Lyrical Content: Expectation Effects." Taylor ampersand
                    Francis, Dec. 1999. Web. Oct. 2016.</bibl>
                <bibl xml:id="Wyner">Wyner, Andrew I. "How Hip-Hop Flourished in America." The
                    Harvard Crimson. The Harvard Crimson, Inc., 29 Apr. 2014. Web. Oct. 2016.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="ro.dy">Dylan Robinson</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#ro.dy">
            <p>This draft talks about how rap music has changed throughout the years. It talks about
                various artists and their influence on the genre. The main argument is clear and
                easy to understand. The draft does not answer many of the questions on the prompt,
                only really parts of a few. It answers questions such as who is invited to use the
                genre, such as groups trying to spread a message like N.W.A. and solo artists like
                Drake, where it appears and who the audience is, first being those in the African
                American culture and now spreading to a more general audience. The draft seems to
                mainly be just about the journey of rap music throughout history and how it now
                appeals to more people. I think it could help the paper if you talked more about the
                genre of rap music and how it has changed. What exactly was the genre that typical
                rap song adhered to in the past and what is it like today? How is Drake’s music
                different from N.W.A.’s? Is it just what he talks about or are there completely
                different instruments and beats used? How similar and how different are they? You
                also do not really use the vocabulary of genre theory that often in your draft. I
                only noticed it being used often in the introduction. This could be fixed through
                just talking more about what the genre of rap music exactly is as I suggested
                earlier. Another problem is that you did not use many of the tags from the schema we
                developed, though this can easily be fixed by just going through your paper and
                looking for what matches up with what tags. Overall I really liked the draft. It
                just needs to make more use of the vocabulary of genre theory and talk more about
                what exactly the rap music genre is.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>This is a very interesting topic for a genre analysis, and a lot of it is well done.
                Here are a few issues I've identified that could be stronger. 1) Structure: the one
                giant body paragraph makes it hard to parse the sub-claims you are making in support
                of you main argument. As a result, I think it ends up being unclear if you've
                successfully aupported your main argument. 2) Detail/focus: there are moments (see
                in-text comments) where you fall back into generalizations and lose sight of the
                specific examples you are analyzing. 3) Vocabulary: you don't leverage much of our
                genre analysis vocabulary, so, at times, your analysis reads more like a close
                reading or even an evaluative project, rather than a generic analysis.</p>
            <p><style type="italics">Note: Grading Citeria</style>. A successful genre analysis
                should: <list>
                    <item>Address one (or more) of the questions posed on the prompt: yes</item>
                    <item>Contain a clearly stated main argument: yes </item>
                    <item>Emphasize evidence in support of claims (textual evidence or otherwise):
                        could be stronger relation between evidence and sub-claims as well as
                        stronger connection between evidence and main argument </item>
                    <item>Use a few of the terms from the vocabulary list: see note above </item>
                    <item>Provide an overview of genre broadly (beyond an individual text): yes </item>
                    <item>Be detailed and focused: see notes above about deatil </item>
                    <item>Contain citations (in-text and works cited): yes</item>
                    <item>Be structured as an essay: yes </item>
                </list></p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
