<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <essay>
        <docHead>
            <title/>
            <author xml:id="we.sp"/>
            <date>October 7th, 2016</date>
        </docHead>
        <body>
<<<<<<< Updated upstream
            <intro>
                <p></p>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara></bodyPara>
            <concl>
                <p></p>
            </concl>
=======
            <intro>There are two types of listeners when its comes to rap music. There are those who
                strictly care about the melody, beat, and flow of the music, and those who pay
                closer attention to the lyrics and message of the music. For a long time, I found
                myself as being the former type of listener, glazing over the lyrics as I knew the
                words, but never considering the content. However, I recently started paying
                attention to the message, and sometimes the idea is simple and self-promoting, but
                sometimes it isn't. Occasionally they will tell a story that can draw you in just as
                much as the melody and beat itself. Because of this, the most successful artists are
                ones that can combine both a powerful or relatable message with an enticing beat.
                The hip hop/rap genre is unique in that there is no specific route that rappers will
                take to become a rapper. Rappers are not often born following an engineering degree.
                Because of this, much of the style of rap is based on era and what is taken up over
                decades. There is successful and unsuccessful rap music from all sub-genres of rap,
                but generally we are only exposed to those who were the most successful in targeting
                what people wanted to hear.<mainArgument>Thus we can observe how hip hop scene has
                    shifted in recent years, and from this, make claims about how hip hop fits in
                    the grander scheme of music as a cultural element.</mainArgument>
            </intro>
            <bodyPara>When thinking of early influential rap artists, two groups immediately come to
                mind: N.W.A. and the Wu-Tang Clan. These two groups released two of the most popular
                albums of the late 80's/early 90's: "Straight Outta Compton" (1988) and "Enter the
                Wu-Tang (36 Chambers)" (1993). These two groups also possessed a quality that is not
                often seen in the spotlight today: they were groups. They were groups of individual
                talent that shared both a common background and a common goal. N.W.A. set out
                primarily to send a message, while the Wu-Tang Clan set out to establish themselves
                as the best, combining progressive beats, dark humor and inventive sounds. Because
                of this, the groups became popular for drastically different reasons. N.W.A.'s
                message was anti-establishment and worked to fight police racism, specifically in
                areas closer to the members' homes. At the time of release, the message was
                extremely relevant, and their local popularity soared, allowing them to spread
                propaganda through their music. However, as time passed and the culture shifted,
                along with other extenuating circumstances, the group disbanded. They didn't have a
                sustainable game plan. After N.W.A was around the time that rap music became a genre
                of music that appealed to a larger audience outside strictly African-American
                culture (as evidenced by the fact that I am a white male writing this essay). The
                Wu-Tang Clan arose from the ashes of N.W.A to bump beats and bash heads (or at least
                rap about doing so). They took over the market that was now well established. They
                developed a sound that became recognizable very quickly. It was music that all fans
                of rap music could enjoy whether they agreed with what was being said or not. For
                this reason they have maintained a presence in rap culture as a group, making
                releases even over 21 years later; the beats don't lose relevance like content does.
                However, solo work has almost completely taken over group hip hop in today's
                culture, as with the rise of media and broadcasting, solo work is much more
                fruitful. It's much easier to present yourself as a solo artist in terms of
                interviews, awards, putting on shows, and even just giving listeners one person to
                listen to and one face to look at. The idea of a relatable message garnering
                popularity quickly still exists, but in a different way. A perfect example of a solo
                artist who has gained massive popularity recently is Drake. Drake has helped to
                integrate hip hop music into America's music culture instead of hip hop being
                primarily culturally African- American. Drake captures such a large audience because
                the content of his music targets such a wide array of people. Much of Drake's music
                is about relationship problems, insecurities, and social media, all things that
                listeners can relate to without much difficulty. Now exists behind the scenes
                employees working day in, day out creating beats and melodies that will be stuck in
                listener's ears. This, the content, and showmanship all wrapped up in one package
                give consumers almost the ideal pop/rap icon. This is evident when considering that
                Drake's most recent album "Views" spent over 12 weeks topping the Billboard 200
                Chart. With a transforming culture shifting towards a greater appreciation of rap
                music, it's no wonder that the 2015 movie named after N.W.A's biggest hit "Straight
                Outta Compton" was such a hit. This movie was also influential in re-demonstrating
                the value of spreading messages through rap, using the N.W.A.'s formation and
                destruction as one of the most significant examples of the power of music. </bodyPara>
            <concl>Will add conclusion</concl>
>>>>>>> Stashed changes
        </body>
        <docFoot>
            <title>Works Cited</title>
            <listBibl>
                <bibl>http://genius.com/posts/1921-Rapper-s-flow-encyclopedia-earl-sweatshirt</bibl>
                <bibl>http://www.nme.com/photos/25-albums-that-changed-hip-hop-forever/315600#/photo/6</bibl>
                <bibl>http://libres.uncg.edu/ir/asu/f/ballard_mary_1999_genre_of_music.pdf</bibl>
                <bibl>http://www.thecrimson.com/column/the-gospel-of-rap/article/2014/4/29/gospel-of-rap-how-hip-hop-flourished/</bibl>
            </listBibl>
        </docFoot>
    </essay>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will go here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
