<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>


    <op_ed>

        <docHead>
            <title>From Homosexuality to Witchcraft</title>
            <author xml:id="al.su">Sultan Aldabal</author>
            <date>October 31, 2016</date>
        </docHead>

        <intro> In Memphis, Tennessee, women can't drive a car unless a man warns other drivers on
            the road with a red flag. In Singapore, selling non-medical chewing gum or chewing gum
            itself is a fine of $1000. In Switzerland, it is illegal to flush a toilet after 10pm.
                <opinion type="main"> It’s hard to believe that these laws still exist today; it’s
                even harder to read them out loud without laughing. </opinion>
        </intro>

        <body_para>
            <opinion type="main">All around the world there are laws that don’t seem to fit in with
                our modern society. Some laws still in effect, date back to medieval centuries.
                <note type="peer" who="#lo.va">Sentence needs to be rephrased</note>Other laws similar
                to one enacted in 1923 by the state of Illinois redefining it’s
                official language as “American,” rather than English. This presents as an example of
                how much we, as an intelligent species, have evolved.</opinion><picture url="https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/enhanced/webdr06/2013/4/18/23/anigif_enhanced-buzz-15238-1366342959-0.gif?no-auto>"> Parks And Recreations</picture></body_para>

        <body_para><opinion type="main">Nonetheless, no country in the world can beat the
                progressive Kingdom of Saudi Arabia in the extent of how backwards their current
                enforced laws are. </opinion><bg_info>In Saudi Arabia, practicing any form of
                homosexuality is punishable by death. Being caught practicing witchcraft is also
                punishable by death. Consuming alcohol or pork leads to imprisonment.</bg_info>
            <situation>With the help from the almighty Committee for the Promotion of Virtue and the
                Prevention of Vice, ( or CPVPV for short) the government of Saudi Arabia has the
                opportunity to imprison hoodlums such as the infamous Sabrina the Teenage Witch and
                Neil Patrick Harris. </situation> <picture url="https://media.giphy.com/media/3o7TKzx6O4eKUcrzNK/giphy.gif">Sabrina the Teenage Witch</picture>
        </body_para>
       
        <body_para><bg_info>By 2011, a unit within the CPVPV created 9 witchcraft fighting bureaus
                in cities across the country. In one year they singlehandedly processed 586 cases of
                magical crime. By 2012, the CPVPV announced the expansion of the bureaus to
                incorporate more agents to help stop the many witches and warlocks operating within
                the kingdom. </bg_info><situation>Contrary to popular belief, their ‘remarkable
                success’ was not credited to their use of garlic or salt, but to the thousands of
                grown men and women looking for a way to Hogwarts.</situation>
        </body_para>

        <body_para><bg_info>In 2014, a 24 year old Saudi man was sentenced to three years in prison
                and 450 lashes after a court in the holy city of Medina found him guilty of
                ‘promoting the vice and practice of homosexuality’. The court’s only piece of
                evidence came from a tweet. In March of 2016, a Saudi newspaper, Oraz, reported 35
                similar cases <note type="peer" who="#lo.va"> A better word to use here would be 
                'occuring'</note>happening between September 2015 to March 2016. </bg_info><evidence
                type="pers_exp">The Saudi constitution also does not provide a right to privacy. As
                a gay Saudi, the prospect of having a committee such as the CPVPV monitoring details
                of my personal life with an intent to shame and punish terrifies me.</evidence>
        </body_para>
        <body_para>
            <opinion type="opposing"/>
            <picture url="#url_here"/>
            <evidence type="other"/>
            <bg_info/>
            <quote/>
            <example/>
            <situation/>
        </body_para>


        <conclusion>As can be seen, there are several enforced laws around the world that are in
            need of amendment. However, in my opinion, the current governing laws in Saudi exhibit
            that some countries are in dire need of a push into the 21st century. I selected Saudi
            because, as someone who has lived there for 15 years, <note type="peer" who="#lo.va"> Your
               closing line doesn't completely make sense.</note>I’ve been witness to several
            events in which people were treated harshly for minor offenses (some of which weren’t). </conclusion>

        <source/>

    </op_ed>




    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="lo.va">Valentina Longcroft</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
                <p>Sultan's Op-Ed discusses the outdated laws that some countries still practice,
                mainly referring to those that condemn women and homosexuals. Saudi Arabia is 
                used as the main example, and their practices are considered some of the worst.
                In reference to xml tags, I think that because there are so many statistics referenced,
                they should be identified with the evidence (statistics) tag. However, I think his use
                of the background information and situation tags are very well used, and I also think
                that his opinion tags are positioned correctly. The Op-Ed piece as a whole
                should probably be a little bit longer, but there are still lots of points to cover so 
                as the piece is revised there shouldn't be any problem fleshing out some of the points he
                has already made. One last critique is that there is a lot of use of sarcasm is this piece,
                and I think you need to make it more obvious, otherwise it has a tendency to look out of place.
                Another thing that I think would be helpful in this Op-Ed is one or two lines about the
                history of Saudia and homosexuality, and how religion plays into the current laws, and
                why they still inforce them on such a regular basis. Also, a comparison of witchcraft
                and homosexuality and how they are related to each other in this context would help
                give a broader view of why they are often placed side by side in countries such as
                Saudi.This piece definitely conforms to the expectations of the Op-Ed genre,
                providing enough information for the reader to get a good idea of what the subject is
                about, and providing enough opinion for it to be considered an Op-Ed. 
                </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
