<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>

    <movie_review>
        <header>
            <title type="title_review">From the Recesses of Obscurity Comes Marvel's Biggest
                Success</title>
            <title type="title_movie">Guardians of the Galaxy</title>
            <title type="photo_movie">http://i.imgur.com/yxj7g89.jpg</title>
            <author xml:id="bu.an">Andrew T. Burcham</author>
            <date type="review_date">Publishing Date: November 11, 2016</date>
            <date type="movie_premiere">Movie Premiere: August 1, 2014</date>
            <contact_info>burcham.a@husky.neu.edu</contact_info>
        </header>

        <content>
            <intro_para> Dating back to 2009's <style type="italics">Iron Man</style>, Marvel
                Studios has had a pretty good track record with their re-branding of the classic
                marvel superheroes. They have been so successful in fact, that they re-popularized
                the idea of intertwining film continuities with 2012's <style type="italics">The
                    Avengers</style>, coining the phrase “cinematic universe” in the pop culture
                vernacular. But despite all this, Marvel took a big leap of faith with their
                experimental film, <style type="italics">Guardians of the Galaxy</style>, a film
                based off an extremely obscure Marvel comic series. A big leap that evidently paid
                off with one of the funniest action movies of all time <note type="peer"
                    who="#ga.ar"> can you rephrase this sentence> </note>. <style type="italics"
                    >Guardians of the Galaxy</style> follows the story of Peter Quill, played by
                Chris Pratt, a would be treasure space pirate who was abducted from his home at a
                very young age.
                <synopsis type="plot_points">After stealing a
                particularly valuable treasure from a crypt, the infinity stone, he gets captured
                and imprisoned and forms a team of criminal mercenaries and assassins in order to
                break out and stop the fanatical space ruler Thanos, played by Lee Pace, from
                harnessing the power of the infinity stone and going on a planet-destroying frenzy.</synopsis>
            </intro_para>
            <body>
                <p>Now <note type="peer" who="#ga.ar">Now,</note>where the real humor and charm of
                    the film comes into play is the cast of unique and hilarious characters and
                    interactions between them. The main team, the self-proclaimed Guardians of the
                    Galaxy, are a fantastic example of this. The main cast, the so called “heroes”
                    are no more than psychotic criminals who do good out of necessity. As such, you
                    get a lot of great moments where all their ugly personalities butt heads and
                    play off one another. </p>

                <p> Quill is an overconfident and extremely charming talker, who is ultimately good,
                    but is willing to do anything to get his way. Gamora, played by Zoe Saldana, a
                    skilled female assassin who is serious and unemotional <note type="peer"
                        who="#ga.ar">is a skilled female assassin who is </note>. She often plays
                    the straight man <note type="peer" who="#ga.ar"> shes a woman though</note> to
                    the team's wackier characters. Drax on the other hand, played by Dave Bautista,
                    is a hyper serious warrior who seeks to avenge the death of his family at the
                    hands of Ronan <note type="peer" who="ga.ar">Who is Ronan...</note>. He spends
                    most of the movie alternating between an intimidating brute and comic relief as
                    he simply does not understand hyperbole or non-literal expressions. Finally you
                    get to the duo of Rocket and Groot, played by Bradley Cooper and Vin Diesal
                    respectively. Rocket is a psychotic hyper-intelligent mutant raccoon who is a
                    master engineer and weapons specialist. On top of all that, he is also loud and
                    fouled mouth, but has a surprisingly touching back story. His partner in crime,
                    Groot, is a tree-like humanoid who can only says the words “I am Groot”. </p>

                <p>
                    <opinions>Just from the character descriptions, you begin to get the idea of the
                        types of situations that would play out between the extreme personalities.
                        The dialogue is witty, comedic timing is spot on, and the characters, while
                        objectively heinous, are incredibly likable. The acting in the movie is also
                        superb. Every actor seems like a perfect fit for their roles and all act
                        naturally with each other through the films <note type="peer" who="#ga.ar">
                            why films plural</note>. Both the dialogue and the acting combined makes
                        it seem like you are watching an actual group of friends making jabs at each
                        other and getting along despite their differences.</opinions>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <aesthetics>The movie's visuals are also a sight to behold. Like the cast of
                        characters, everything is colorful. The deep space settings does not
                        discourage the movie from showing off incredibly vibrant colors and locals
                            <note type="peer" who="#ga.ar">locals are part the setting in this case?
                            Colefurl locals makes me think of their personality, rather than their
                            visuals</note>. It is not mind blowing like <style type="italics"
                            >Avatar</style>, but it certainly does not slack off. The CG animations
                        are also top notch, especially on completely animated characters like Rocket
                        and Groot, staying expressive despite all the visual effects. Finally, you
                        got the action scenes.</aesthetics>
                    <opinions>These are the only parts of the movie that I feel could be improved.
                        While not bad per say, they feel generic and kind of forced in because it is
                        a Marvel superhero movie. Their <note type="peer" who="#ga.ar"> there
                        </note> were few fight scenes that stick out and are <note type="peer"
                            who="#ga.ar"> tense change</note> incredibly memorable for the action
                        alone, instead its the dialogue that carries it all.</opinions>
                </p>
            </body>
            <conclusion> Overall, <style type="italics">Guardians of the Galaxy</style> is a near
                spotless action-comedy blockbuster. If you love humorous characters interactions in
                incredible scenarios, then Guardians <note type="peer" who="#ga.ar"> First time in
                    the essay your movie is referred to as Guardians </note> is definitely a movie
                you should watch. Do not expect any sort of deep character analysis <note
                    type="peer" who="#ga.ar"> I think you meant character development</note> or
                thought-provoking plots, instead go in with an open mind looking for a good,
                memorable laugh with characters you think were your own friends. I truly believe
                that Guardians easily takes title of the best Marvel movie from the second <note
                    type="peer" who="#ga.ar"> From the second what?</note>, and I am very excited
                for the sequel coming out next May. Guardians of the Galaxy, by Marvel Studios, is
                    <summary type="rating">rated PG-13</summary>. It premiered in theaters <date
                    type="movie_premiere">August 1st, 2014</date>, and <summary type="gross_income"
                    >grossed $773.3 million worldwide.</summary>
            </conclusion>
        </content>
    </movie_review>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="Ga.ar"> Arlen Gaba</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#Ga.ar">
            <p> I understand the premise of this genre replication to be based on Guardians of the
                Galaxy, a movie where you focus on the actors, the visuals, and the humor.
                Furthermore, you focus on the action and the aesthetics. Your analysis of the movie
                is well done , and I think for a generic superhero movie such as this, you focused
                on the right details to analyze such as the actors and characters, the movie plot,
                visuals and action scenes. Sometimes you name drop characters important to the
                stories characters, such as the case for Drax but do not go into detail about it.
                Either don't name drop characters that you do not ever come up in the main story, or
                explain the motivation behind the name dropping. Ronin is a bad guy? Is he important
                to the story or the character? You made a pre-statement about the visuals in the
                aesthetics paragraph. Are we allowing that in our documentation? Although you have a
                separate opinion tag your review is essentially filled with opinions such as
                introductory "ugly personalities." Does this mean that everything up to this point
                has been an objective review. We need to revise our schema to accommodate an opinion
                tag. When you say mind blowing like Avatar under your aesthetics, I have trouble
                recalling the visuals of the movie. You should be specific when you make an
                analytical claim like that. I know that you mentioned vibrant colors but I don’t
                know if you’re referring to the vibrant colors of avatar. Also, since this is a
                marvel movie, shouldn’t you make a direct comparison with their other movies, or are
                you making this comparison for the noting a substantial difference in visual acuity?
                Lastly, I do not think this movie review needs much revision apart from some
                grammatical issues, as well as some specificity. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
