<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>


    <movie_review>
        <header>
            <title type="title_review"> Mustang: Coldest Story Ever Told </title>
            <title type="title_movie">Mustang</title>
            <title type="photo_movie"
                >https://bitchmedia.org/sites/default/files/1200x630_306433_mustang-a-film-of-flowering-femal.jpg</title>
            <author xml:id="ga.ar"> Arlen Gaba</author>
            <date type="review_date">October 27/2016</date>
            <date type="movie_premiere">November 20, 2015</date>
            <contact_info>Gaba.ar@husky.neu.edu</contact_info>
        </header>

        <content>
            <intro_para> Teenage girls just want to hang out, be with their friends, carelessly hook
                up with boys and go to "<style type="italics">futbol</style>" matches. Adults,
                always middling in their lives is just another obstacle to overcome to emerge as
                young, independent women. The teenage girls from Mustang, however, also have a
                different approach to marriage than their adoptive family is used to; they want to
                choose whom to marry. They want to have freedom to leave their village, the freedom
                to an education and the freedom to act their age. <synopsis type="plot_points"/> The
                story follows a trajectory that is reminiscing of other, feel-good, empowering women
                stories, however, the storytelling is what sets it apart. The female perspective is
                strong, very personal, and follows the girls from carefree fun to downfall. The
                trouble is heavily masked in the first ten minutes of the film, where carefree play
                with some boys at the beach, turns into a shameful interrogation and demonstration
                of abuse from the girls' uncle. The cascading withdrawal from society instigated by
                the claustrophobic imprisonment of the girls because of their innocent fun,is done
                wonderfully by the <context type="director">Turkish born French director Deniz Gamze
                    Ergüven</context>. <synopsis type="themes"/> The humor, sisterly warmth,
                friendship, and ridiculous ploys of rebellion add a warmth to a story very much
                about oppressive norms, and the coming of age story is much better for it. </intro_para>
            <body>
                <p> Quite swiftly the caretakers of the girls, their grandmother and uncle,
                    successfully remove all "corruptions" that may affect the girls even further.
                    They begin by removing schools and with it boys, "revealing" clothing, and all
                    digital media as well as<style type="italics"> futbol</style> games. The girls,
                    understandably begin to reactively push away, by cutting thigh high slits into
                    their brown, shapeless clothes, spitting in the coffee of their soon to be
                    mothers in law, or even having sex with strange boys in their uncle's car. Lale,
                    the youngest of the five sisters emerges as the wily, most ferocious of them all, quickly
                    evoking feelings of sympathy and encouragement from the audience. 
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    <context type="actor"/>
                    <context type="director"/>
                    <context type="franchise_history"/>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <opinions/>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <opinions/>
                    <aesthetics/>
                </p>
            </body>
            <conclusion>
                <summary type="gross_income"/>
                <summary type="rating"/>
                <date type="movie_premiere"/>
            </conclusion>
        </content>
    </movie_review>
    <!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will go here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
