<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>


    <movie_review>
        <header>
            <title type="title_review"> Mustang: Coldest Story Ever Told </title>
            <title type="title_movie">Mustang</title>
            <title type="photo_movie"
                >https://bitchmedia.org/sites/default/files/1200x630_306433_mustang-a-film-of-flowering-femal.jpg</title>
            <author xml:id="ga.ar"> Arlen Gaba</author>
            <date type="review_date">October 27/2016</date>
            <date type="movie_premiere">November 20, 2015</date>
            <contact_info>Gaba.ar@husky.neu.edu</contact_info>
        </header>

        <content>
            <intro_para> Teenage girls just want to hang out, be with their friends, carelessly hook
                up with boys and go to "<style type="italics">futbol</style>" matches. Adults,
                always omnipresent in their lives, are just another obstacle to overcome in their
                path to emerge as young, independent women. The teenage girls from a remote village
                in Turkey, however, have a different approach to marriage than their adoptive family
                is used to; they want to choose whom to marry. They also want to have the freedom to
                leave their village, the freedom to an education and the freedom to act their age.
                <synopsis type="plot_points"/> The story follows a trajectory that is reminiscing of
                other, feel-good, empowering women and girls stories, however, the storytelling is
                what sets it apart from the Hollywood counterparts<note type="peer" who="#to.fr">
                    Which counterparts specifically?</note>. The female perspective is strong, very
                personal, and follows the girls from carefree fun to downfall. <note type="peer"
                    who="#to.fr"> What do you think ths perspective adds to the movie?</note> The
                pivotal point in the drama is heavily masked in the first ten minutes of the film,
                where carefree play with their male classmates at the beach, turns into a shameful
                interrogation and demonstration of abuse from the girls' uncle. The cascading
                withdrawal from society instigated by the claustrophobic imprisonment of the girls
                because of their innocent fun, is done wonderfully by the <context type="director"
                    >Turkish born French director, Deniz Gamze Erg端ven</context>.
                <synopsis type="themes"/> The humor, sisterhood, friendship, and ridiculous ploys of
                rebellion add a warmth to a story very much about oppressive norms and this coming
                of age drama is much better for it. </intro_para>
            <body>
                <p> Quite swiftly, the caretakers of the girls, their grandmother and uncle,
                    successfully remove all "corruptions" that may affect the girls even further in
                    their preordained destiny of dutiful housewives. They begin by removing school
                    attendance and with it access to boys, and "revealing" clothing. The girls,
                    understandably begin to reactively push away, by cutting thigh high slits into
                    their brown, shapeless clothes, spitting in the coffee of their soon to be
                    mothers in law, or even having sex with strange boys in their uncle's car. Lale,
                    passionately played by <context type="actor">G端nes Sensoy,</context> the
                    youngest of the five sisters emerges as the wily, most ferocious of them all,
                    quickly evoking my feelings of sympathy and warranted my encouragement of her
                    success as I watched her development. Observing her desperate plea for freedom
                    get more climactic as her sisters quickly disappeared with their new husbands,
                    amplified those feelings even more. > </p>
                <p>
                    <aesthetics>Mustang portrays the development of the sister's home into a prison
                        after each transgression with an air of lucid dreamlike appeal. Each bout of
                        imprisonment montage is broken up by lazy, sunlit montages of the girls
                        making the best of the situation. The camera often times pans through open
                        windows and sun beams, where the girls stretch out like cats beyond bars.
                        More often the camera follows the youngest Lale in her child-play, her swift
                        manoeuvrings in her home prison as she quietly exists, the montages almost
                        always being wordless and defining. </aesthetics>
                </p>
                <p> Girls just want to have fun, but for these five young adults, fun has long
                    surpassed its definition and has morphed into rebellion. The village and family
                    elders view their ruses and their petty responses to their subjugation as
                    chaotic and worrying, because their fitness for marrying and being dutiful
                    wives, in their eyes, dissipates. However, there are times, when the director,
                    Deniz Gamze Erg端ven, redeems the qualities of the conservative fathers,uncles,
                    elders, aunts and mothers by removing the air of moral simplicity. He does not
                    condemn an entire society, and allows the very same characters who have been
                    oppressors to aid in hiding some of the girl's acts of rebellion <note
                        type="peer" who="#to.fr"> Can you give a specific example?</note>. The
                    kindness of strangers, although not bountiful, does make an appearance even when
                    with the girl's continued diminished reputation in the village. For the
                    audience, this allows the multifaceted portrayal of Turkish society, to resonate
                    in many more layers beyond simply, oppressor and oppressed. <opinions/>
                    <aesthetics/>
                </p>
            </body>
            <conclusion> The drama, perilously close to a dramatic and fatalistic end, is rescued by
                the writing of Deniz Gamze Erg端ven, who I would argue, dabbled in providing a
                resolution for the audience that fulfilled their hopes for the characters. This
                optimistic approach to the finish is not a blind answer to the dramas progression,
                but rather a message to the audience; freedom is hardly attained without the most
                awesome attempts at breaking free. For any movie-goer out there who enjoys foreign
                indie films, this one is a must watch, even if only to cheer on young Lale on her
                bid for freedom. <summary type="gross_income"/>
                <summary type="rating"/>
                <date type="movie_premiere"/>
            </conclusion>
        </content>
    </movie_review>
    <!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="to.fr"> Francheska Torres </reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#to.fr">
            <p>Summary: This movie is about five sisters wanting to grow up and live life as free
                beings while under the control of oppressive relatives and caretakers. As a way of
                fighting back against their oppressors, these girls rebel in various ways (wearing
                revealing clothing, sneaking out, copulating in cars).</p>

            <p> Critique: I think this was a very good review overall. I would have liked to see
                more of our elements in the paper. I feel like you should explicitly say whether you
                recommend the movie or not. Some more analysis would be nice, going onto more depth
                of what you think the point of view of the movie contributes to the film as well as
                how it might be different if in the point of view of one of the adults (mentioned
                female point of view). I'd also find it interesting to talk about how each sister
                changes as she is married off ( not referencing that when women are married off they
                leave the movie.). Additionally, some more context information is needed I think:
                when was it set, how does that affect the movie? (more personal analysis) It just
                feels like this review is a bit superficial. Also, I think you should probably add
                more information in the conclusion about the movie itself: when it was released
                (noted), how much money it made (is this information available for me to give) ,
                stuff like that. And maybe some additional information on the actors ( if i can find
                any, I will add it) , I'd be interested to see what made them want to be involved in
                a movie that seems to have such deep meaning. Finally, there are just a few grammar
                issues but those are easy to fix once you read through your final review. I think
                you did a nice job of organizing the review and your content was relevant according
                to our schema. (add more tags) I also like the language you used and thought the
                point you made about aesthetics was interesting. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
