<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <resume>
        <title>Divit Koradia</title>
        <header><style type="underline">Contact Information</style></header>
        <contact_information>
            <contact type="address">10 Forsyth Street,</contact>
            <contact type="address">Boston, MA 02115 </contact>
            <contact type="phone">Mobile: (857) 358 4579</contact>
            <contact type="email">dbk2911@gmail.com</contact>
        </contact_information>
        <header><style type="underline">Objectives</style></header>
        <objectives>Looking for a working opportunity in the Computer Science Industry during the
            summer of 2017 (from May to July). My aim is to work in a cutting-edge and challenging
            work environment, wherein I can effectively convert my innovative ideas into fruitful
            results. </objectives>
        <header><style type="underline">Qualifications</style></header>
        <qualifications>
            <work_experience>
                <job>
                    <job_title><style type="bold">Title:</style> Software Developer for Fazlani
                        L'Académie Globale School. <job_date>Duration: November 2015 - April
                            2016.</job_date>
                    </job_title>
                    <job_summary>Developed a Student Council Voting System for the Sports Department
                        of my high-school.</job_summary>
                    <job_summary> Used Java as my primary programming language and .dat files for the
                        systems backend </job_summary>
                </job>
            </work_experience>
            <header><style type="underline">Education</style></header>
            <education>Northeastern University Boston Class of 2020 - BS in Computer
                Science</education>
            <education>Fazlani L'Académie Globale School (India) Class of 2016 - Diploma in
                International Baccalaureate </education>
            <header><style type="underline">Additional Information</style></header>
            <additional_information> Proficient in Java, DrRacket and XML.</additional_information>
            <additional_information>Fluent in English, French and Hindi.</additional_information>
            <additional_information>Prior leadership roles in sports teams.</additional_information>
            <additional_information>Hosted my high-school annual concert.</additional_information>
            <additional_information> Volunteered at Muktangan NGO in India. Directed a play for
                their school concert with the help of my classmates.</additional_information>
        </qualifications>
    </resume>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>The piece written is a resume, with the purpose of impressing an interviewer with the
                candidate’s qualifications. The piece contains contact information, objectives,
                education, qualifications, past work experience and work skills. To start with, the
                author effectively understands the schema and structure of a resume, and the piece
                seems to be a good attempt which can use a few minor improvements. The objectives
                section of the resume has most room for improvement. Whilst the structure is
                flawless, the content could use a few improvements. The objective is three sentences
                long, of which two are repetitions of information provided later in the resume.
                “Currently a first year Computer Science major at Northeastern University. Looking
                for a working opportunity in the Computer Industry during the summer of 2017.” This
                information was provided again in the qualifications section. In my opinion the
                objective space could be used more effectively, perhaps to talk about your passions
                and concrete and realistic expectations of the role you seek in the certain company.
                “My aim is to work in a cutting-edge and challenging work environment, wherein I can
                effectively convert my innovative ideas into fruitful results”. This line could also
                use some improvement, because while it shows your positive intentions, it appears to
                be a bit vague and lacks the critical information that an interviewers wishes to
                see. The interviewers would like to have more information and details about your
                aforementioned “innovative ideas”. Perhaps share briefly with the interviewer what
                your ideas are. To expand a little more on my previous point, I would like to draw a
                comparison with my own piece. In my objective I mentioned a lot of specific details
                like the dates I was avaible for, the specific courses I take and the departments in
                the company I would like to work in. This provides the critical information an
                interviewer needs to give you the job</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
