<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>

    <op_ed>
        <docHead>

            <title>Op-Ed: The Fashion Industry Post Brexit</title>
            <author xml:id="lo.va">Valentina Longcroft</author>
            <date>October 31st 2016</date>
        </docHead>

        <intro>London, United Kingdom: London has always been considered one of the world’s most
            prestigious fashion capitals in the world. But as the reality of Brexit sets in,
                <opinion type="main">what does it mean for the British Fashion industry, and what
                will the long and short term effects be?</opinion></intro>

        <body_para> On June 26th, 2016, <situation>Britain made history when they voted to
                    leave the European Union.</situation> With many feeling shocked and
            surprised at the result, the effects were immediately felt worldwide, with <evidence
                type="statistics">over $2.1 trillion dollars in stock value lost globally in the 24
                hours after the vote. The pound is now at a 7-year low against the
            dollar</evidence>, as the nation’s currency depreciated significantly, and worries that
            this could severely impact the bottom line, with many companies outsourcing to
            semi-peripheral countries such as China (where they are paid in dollars) were realised.
            A weaker pound has forced international brands to raise their U.K. prices, and though
                <opinion type="opposing">this means that retail has now become slightly cheaper for
                tourists</opinion>, it also means that it is more expensive if you are a resident in
            Britain. <picture
                url="https://img.styla.com/resizer/sfh_760x0/fashion-in-the-time-of-brexit-what-s-next_26042_31907.jpeg"
            /></body_para>

        <body_para>It is estimated that <evidence type="statistics"> 90% of the British Fashion
                Council voted for the Remain campaign, with fashion icons such as Christopher
                Bailey, CCO of Burberry, Alexandra Shulman, Editor-in-chief of Vogue, and designers
                such as Anya Hindmarch and Vivienne Westwood</evidence> supporting the opposition of
            Brexit. For many reasons such as manufacturing, exporting and staffing, many expect
            fashion to be hit hard in the next few years, as the industry relies so much on the
            fluid movement of trade and people across borders, especially in Europe, with Paris and
            Milan being especially important European relationships. The EU’s open borders have made it easy for
            many companies such as <example>Céline (based in Paris) to run operations on both sides
                of the channel, but a leave vote means that they will have to re-evaluate their
                decision to establish creative departments in London.</example></body_para>

        <body_para>Though many prominent fashion figures were disappointed with the vote, London
            Fashion week continued on without a hitch, and as the un-official kick-off to the much
            anticipated shows, London-based designers, <situation>editors and executives were
                invited for an evening at 10 Downing Street</situation>, where new prime minister
            Theresa May has just moved in. Natalie Massenet, founder of Net-A-Porter spoke
            eloquently, and an important remark she made was: <quote>“We are living through a
                remarkable transition. But also in an age of extraordinary innovation.”</quote>
            Guests reported that May did not speak directly about Brexit at the event, but that she
            was very supportive of the industry and the significance of fashion’s contribution to
            the economy.</body_para>

        <body_para>A concern at the forefront of the industry is the looming restrictions on global
            borders, and what that will mean for <situation>fashion education</situation>. London
            hosts many of the most highly accredited institutes to study fashion, and they rely on a
            diverse set of students coming in every year, who are multi-cultural and multi-lingual.
            The industry relies on the outsourcing of talent, and many designers we see on the
            runway today studied in London. This has always been an important part of fashion, and
            many are worried that we may decrease in diversity following our exit from the EU. Fabio
            Piras, the Fashion Course Director at Central St. Martins, commented: <quote>"I cannot
                deny that it is worrying to think that we will probably see a decline in graduates’
                employability in the EU. I am equally concerned with the potentially decreasing
                numbers of EU students [applying to CSM], as they will not be able to come as freely
                as they can now.”</quote></body_para>


        <conclusion>Looking forward to early next year, when the now-famous Article 50 clause will
            supposedly be activated, the fashion industry’s hope is that we close trade negotiations
            as soon as possible, with minimal impact to property regulations and visas. I don’t
            think we have any idea what the biggest challenges are, that we will face in the wake of
            Brexit, and many are worried that we will experience another, greater, financial crisis
            similar to that of 2008. The key here is to not get ahead of ourselves, keep a cool head
            and urge politicians to handle negotiations with the EU as peacefully as possible. It
            has become clear that there will no re-referendum, so we are stuck in this position for
            the foreseeable future, and can only make the best of it, and come out the other side
            with the best regulations we can agree on, and not become isolated, but use it as an
            opportunity to better ourselves as a country.</conclusion>


        <source/>

    </op_ed>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="al.su"> Sultan Aldabal</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="al.su">
            <p>From what I understood, your Op-Ed discusses the effects of Brexit on the fashion
                industry in Britain. The Op-Ed offers a lot of opinions that are shared between the
                majority of the British fashion industry, as well as your own opinion as a British
                citizen. </p>
            <p>The Op-ed as a whole is very put together and enjoyable to read, however there are
                some points that could be improved upon. The first being the flow of a few
                sentences, such as the second sentence in the third paragraph that ends with "with
                Paris and Milan being especially important relations." I think rewording this phrase
                would help with the flow because I myself stopped and re-read it a few times before
                I understood it. Maybe phrasing like this would help the reader understand it better
                "as ties with Paris and Milan get more complicated with the absence of free trade".
                However it is completely up to you as you are the writer and it might not get your
                point across well enough.</p>
            <p> Another point I want to bring up is adding more pictures to the Op-ed. Adding more
                pictures helps the reader disengage a bit from the text to visually conceptualize
                the situation. And as a very visual person, I think that it would help many people
                understand the situation more. Consider adding a picture or a graph that illustrates
                how much the pound has depreciated compared to the dollar after the second
                paragraph. Also consider adding a picture of a person mentioned, preferably the
                prime minister due to the political nature the body paragraphs, and who doesn't
                like to look at pictures when reading an article. I hope you take my points into
                consideration, these were the only points I could think of to bring up, other than
                that I think the Op-ed is remarkable, nice job!</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
