<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>


    <!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->
    <article>
        <!-- YOUR ROOT ELEMENT GOES HERE (NAME OF YOUR GENRE), FOR EXAMPLE, "essay" or "obit" -->

        <header>
            <article_title>Great, The Uber Driver is Playing His F*cking Mixtape</article_title>
            <author xml:id="li.em"/>
            <category>News in Brief</category>
            <date>11 November 2016</date>
            <identification type="volume">1</identification>
            <identification type="issue">1</identification>
            <tags>Local ⬪</tags>
            <tags>Nightlife ⬪</tags>
            <tags>Mixtapes</tags>
            <share type="facebook"/>
            <share type="twitter"/>
            <share type="email"/>
            <share type="other"/>
        </header>
        <body>
            <image
                url="http://img.theepochtimes.com/n3/eet-content/uploads/2016/08/26/20160822-uber-SamiraBouaou-3702.jpg"> </image>
            
            <p><location>BOSTON, MA</location>—Craig Brennan and friends got into their
                Uber Saturday to head to the bars. Their driver, named Jon, seemed normal enough
                until he kept insisting he “is the next big thing” in rap. “Yeah, the 30 minute
                drive into the city wasn’t bad until he wouldn’t stop bringing up his art.” After
                the insisting we go to his Soundcloud page, Brennan’s friend, Charlene Nguyen, asked
                him to play his music. “Terrible mistake” said Brennan. Before Nguyen could finish,
                Jon began talking about his mixtape’s upcoming release, and started off by playing a
                song called “Infected.” With an overly heavy bass and mediocre Garageband synth, you
                almost couldn’t make out his weak rhythm and shaky voice. “Yeah, after the awkward
                silence and haphazard ‘that was great,’ we thought he’d put Drake back on. But then
                he played three more.” The next one was called “The Reelest,” and featured a line
                about fishing for money. On top of that, he appeared to be singing along to his
                music, and kept looking back for reassurance. “I’ve never had to force a smile more
                than I did for Jon’s rap, said fellow victim Nick Martin. Reports indicate that
                Jon’s mixtape is set to release on December 8th.</p>
        </body>
        <footer>
            <share type="facebook"/>
            <share type="twitter"/>
            <share type="email"/>
            <share type="other"/>
            <related_links url="http://fa16.kevingeraldsmith.com/">Cool Stuff</related_links>
        </footer>
    </article>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here"> 
             <p>The draft is well written and adheres to the
                style of writing of a typical satirical article such as one in The Onion. The use of
                an accurate rhetorical situation which is relevant to satirical articles further
                validates the content in the body paragraph. Satirical articles are meant to be a
                humorous take on articles published in conventional sources (i.e. The New York
                Times). I feel that this article has many qualities that help it fit into this
                satirical article category very well. The focus of this article is on one particular
                event in one night, which is what many satirical articles are about. The story
                having a funny character is one definite sign that it is a satirical article. There
                is a good incorporation of current humor– the whole concept of mixtapes is very
                relevant in today’s society where small time rappers try to promote themselves
                through their music. Further, I like how there is an insight into the thoughts and
                feelings of the characters who are involved in the scene. Although satirical
                articles are not meant for character development, I feel that a scene is built and
                situations are developed when there is a general understanding of the characters–
                this was done well by the author. One aspect on language which can be slightly
                improved on is how everything in the article seems to be over-emphasized. For
                example, “kept saying that he raps”, “terrible mistake”, “overly heavy bass”,
                “barely make out”, “played three more”. Some details may be better if they’re left
                un-emphasized. Overall, I feel that the article is very well written and sticks by
                the conventions of satirical articles with good use of character and scene
                development which makes for a thorough rhetorical situation development. One little
                aspect of the article that may be reconsidered is the amount of words/ phrases that
                are emphasized to add effect. It is a good habit to have, especially in satirical
                articles, however not always.</p></report>
   
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
