<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>


    <!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->
    <article>
        <!-- YOUR ROOT ELEMENT GOES HERE (NAME OF YOUR GENRE), FOR EXAMPLE, "essay" or "obit" -->

        <header>
            <article_title>Great, The Uber Driver is Playing His Fucking Mixtape</article_title>
            <author xml:id="li.em"/>
            <category>News in Brief</category>
            <date>1 November 2016</date>
            <identification type="volume">42</identification>
            <identification type="issue">43</identification>
            <tags>local</tags>
            <tags>Nightlife</tags>
            <tags>Mixtapes</tags>
            <share type="facebook"/>
            <share type="twitter"/>
            <share type="email"/>
            <share type="other"/>
        </header>
        <body>
            <image/>

            <p>
                <location>BOSTON, MA</location>
                <quote/>
            </p>
        </body>
        <footer>
            <share type="facebook"/>
            <share type="twitter"/>
            <share type="email"/>
            <share type="other"/>
            <related_links/>
            <ad/>
        </footer>

        <!-- THE REST OF YOUR DOCUMENT STRUCTURE HERE; WHAT FOLLOWS THE HEADER IN YOUR GENRE? for example, body, or text, or whatever -->

    </article>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Summary: You have several title ideas for his article. Some are relatable to
                Northeastern and/or college students, while others are universal to anyone.
                
                Critique/Eval: Titles are the most important part of these satirical articles, so I
                think it is understandable that you only have titles to be reviewed. I definitely
                favor some over the others, and I also like the idea of doing an article that is
                related to college. My favorite is the Game of Thrones one. If you were to use that
                one, I would suggest omitting “only” and “his” so it reads” Incredible! Student
                Manages to Watch Entire Game of Thrones Series During Chemistry Lectures.” It is not
                a big deal, but I think it just sounds a little bit more synthesized. I do really
                like the “Incredible!” because it reflects The Onion’s wording. You could
                sarcastically comment on the tuition money being wasted, quotes from other students
                in his class, etc. I also liked the other college-themed titles, including the
                ResLife one and the coughing one. It is really just a matter of figuring out how to
                elaborate on them. 
                
                I also like the “Scientists Agree That Pigs Will Likely Never
                Fly.” I think that is a really clever title, and gets to the type of humor Onion has
                in some of its random/wtf articles that satirize a random part of society, like the
                saying “when pigs fly.” The athlete/rape one is definitely a relevant topic in
                society, but maybe overdone/time already passed. The computer science one is also
                really funny, but maybe only really relevant to a small crowd (computer science
                majors), which isn’t a huge deal, just something to consider. The Harambe one is
                actually kind of funny even though I think Harambe jokes should've never been a
                thing, mainly because I think someone could actually believe it. The Gary Johnson
                one is also funny, so it is just a matter of being able to elaborate. 
                
                Overall, you presented a wide range of article titles that touch upon different types of humor
                that come from The Onion. My suggestion would be to maybe pick a couple titles to
                write articles for, then decide which one comes out stronger. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
