<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>


    <article>


        <header>
            <article_title>Gary Johnson’s Media Meltdown Leads to All Time High Favorability of
                21%</article_title>
            <author xml:id="mi.as">Ashwin Misra</author>
            <category>News in Brief</category>
            <date>November 11, 2016</date>
            
            <identification type="volume">52</identification>
            <identification type="issue">68</identification>
            <tags>Politics, Politicians, Election, Gary Johnson, Hillary Clinton, Donald
                Trump</tags>
            <share type="facebook"/>
            <share type="twitter"/>
            <share type="email"/>
            <share type="other"/>
        </header>

        <body>
            <image
                url="http://media.breitbart.com/media/2016/05/wi/ap_gary-johnson_ap-photo-e1464287585747.jpg"
                ></image>

            <p><location>BOULDER, CO</location>Gary Johnson’s campaign has now been noticed by the
                general public after the traumatic, hard-to-watch video of him surfaced the
                Internet. The video showed a hot-tempered Johnson defending the inevitable “why are
                you even in the campaign?” question. The Libertarian Party candidate assures a win
                after re-watching his public media meltdown about the two main candidates.
                    <quote>“Just look at the polls, Anderson. I’m at a whole 4.6% right now! I’d say
                    I got this one in the bag. Oh boy is it looking good for me, huh? We’re
                    practically on double digits! Just wait until the fourth debate and my numbers
                    will shoot way up.”</quote> said a red-faced Johnson, who added that his
                favorability numbers (of just 21%) are higher than “any president in the history of
                America”. After having a private conversation with Johnson’s VP pick- William Weld-
                we learned a great deal of useful information. <quote>“Really I don’t know what Gary
                    and I are still doing here. He’s a lost cause, in all seriousness.”</quote> Weld
                also added that Gary Johnson will be <quote>“the most irrelevant presidential
                    candidate in modern US history”</quote>. We visited Weld at the Libertarian
                Party office a week later only to find him emptying the office. I think we all know
                what this means.</p>
        </body>
        <footer>
            <share type="facebook"/>
            <share type="twitter"/>
            <share type="email"/>
            <share type="other"/>
            <related_links url="#"/>
            <ad/>
        </footer>


    </article>



    <!-- leave this section for peer review and assessment -->
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="we.sp">Spencer Webb</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>This satirical article is about the outburst Gary Johnson had when speaking with and
                interviewer. It discusses the effects of said outburst in terms of how Candidate
                Johnson sees it in contrast with how his VP Candidate sees it. The lack of faith
                coming from William Weld in his own campaign I think is the best part of the
                satirical article, as the clear contrast between the standpoints of Johnson and Weld
                embodies the feel of a satirical article. One critique I have is that nearly all of
                the text is quoted which means that very little of the body is written from the
                "writer of the article" which I guess would be you, even though the quotes were
                written by you as well. The image you are using is funny and contextual, but it's
                clear that it is a screengrab and seems like something else could fit better in the
                framework of an article. You focus mostly on the responses to the outburst that took
                place during the interview and not the outburst itself. I found this picture
                https://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2016/06/01/BostonGlobe.com/Politics/Images/johnson-weld.jpg
                that demonstrates a more subtle relation to your article with the differences in
                facial expressions of Johnson and Weld. The title of your article also sounds a
                little bit too real, like something I might read on an informative news site.
                Remember that in satirical articles, the title is often most of, or the whole joke.
                Maybe you could reword it so that the joke is a little more blunt. Something like:
                Johnson: "Yes we can." Weld: "No we can't." You shouldn't take my advice verbatim
                obviously, but I think that the contrast used for humor in the article can be
                squeezed a little more in the title. With some revisions, I think this is a really
                good idea for a satirical article and could easily fit in within the context of a
                site like the onion.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
