<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>


    <!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->
    <op_ed>
        <!-- YOUR ROOT ELEMENT GOES HERE (NAME OF YOUR GENRE), FOR EXAMPLE, "essay" or "obit" -->

        <docHead>
            <!-- make changes to the document header as necessary (based on your genre) -->
            <title/>
            <author xml:id="ro.dy"/>
            <date/>
        </docHead>

        <intro> A common complaint many high school students make is about their lack of sleep.
            School starts early in the day, it takes time to get ready and get there, and after
            school many students have sports, jobs, volunteer work, and other activities in addition
            to homework. Research shows that many teens average less than 7 hours of sleep per night
            when the optimal amount of sleep per night is around 9.25 hours. Currently, many high
            schools start class around 7:20am. <opinion type="main"> In order to combat teen sleep
                deprivation, the school starting time should be pushed forward to around
                8:30am.</opinion>
        </intro>

        <body_para> Sleep deprivation is extremely common in teens today. Many teens think that they
            are expected to function with barely any sleep.<evidence> A lack of sleep causes many
                problems. It impairs one’s ability to be alert, to solve problems and to cope with
                stress. Many days without enough sleep also increases the risk of car accidents due
                to drowsy driving for teens who drive daily.</evidence>
        </body_para>
        <body_para><evidence type="pers_exp">From my time in high school I can say that a lack of
                sleep was a big problem. There were many times that I would fall asleep in class and
                times that I was just too tired to focus. I would have to go over the material that
                was taught later in the day. Drowsy driving was definitely a problem as well. I
                would drive about 20 minutes to school everyday and in the morning it was very
                challenging to stay awake and focus on the road. Sometimes I would miss turns and be
                late to school.</evidence>
        </body_para>
        <body_para><evidence>There is a lot of research into the different sleep cycles between
                teens and others. Young children’s sleep cycles allow them to wake up earlier and be
                more energetic than teenagers. The sleep cycle of teens is moved a few hours forward
                from children’s sleep cycles. Since elementary school starts later than high school,
                this results in teens waking up at a time that their body thinks is the middle of
                the night.</evidence> If younger children woke up at the same time they would be
            fine.</body_para>

        <conclusion>Teens need more sleep than they currently get. Moving the start time of high
            schools about an hour forward would be a step towards helping teens get more sleep.
            Lower grade schools can be pushed back to start a little earlier because younger
            children can handle that much better than teens can. So high school should start later
            than it currently does so that it is less likely that so many teens suffer from sleep
            depravity. </conclusion>
        <source/>

        <!-- THE REST OF YOUR DOCUMENT STRUCTURE HERE; WHAT FOLLOWS THE HEADER IN YOUR GENRE? for example, body, or text, or whatever -->

    </op_ed>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="san.jh"> Jhadley Sanchex</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>This op-ed is mostly about explaining the effects of sleep deprivation among
                teenagers. Not only does it explain possible problems that it could bring to
                teenagers but also the effects it could have on a person’s daily life. This paper
                also explains what could be done in order to improve this issue that affects
                teenagers nationwide. One thing I would improve is staying within one topic and
                backing it up. You have four different points; sleep deprivation, the effects of
                lack of sleep, research, and what can be done to fix this issue. Although this in
                not a problem and you do a great job staying chronologic, you should make sure that
                you explain each section well so that your reader understands what you are trying to
                express. This is a really interesting topic to read about I would recommend going
                back to your main opinions and making sure that you have included all the possible
                elements that can explain to your reader why you have this opinion and that you are
                well centered on it. Remember that this is your opinion on this topic and your
                opinion does not necessarily need to be backed up in order to be subjective. There
                is not much you need to chance, just keep in mind that this is your opinion that you
                are trying to express to an audience, and such should mainly be expressing what you
                thing and when you are giving evidence make sure to express also what you think of
                that specific piece of evidence. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
