<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>


    <!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->
    <op_ed>
        <!-- YOUR ROOT ELEMENT GOES HERE (NAME OF YOUR GENRE), FOR EXAMPLE, "essay" or "obit" -->

        <docHead>
            <!-- make changes to the document header as necessary (based on your genre) -->
            <title>High School Start Times Need to Change</title>
            <author xml:id="ro.dy">Dylan Robinson</author>
            <date>11 November, 2016</date>
        </docHead>

        <intro> A common complaint many high school students make is about their lack of sleep.
            School starts early in the day, it takes time to get ready and get there, and after
            school many students have sports, jobs, volunteer work, and other activities in addition
            to homework. Research shows that many teens average less than 7 hours of sleep per night
            when the optimal amount of sleep per night is around 9.25 hours<note type="instructor"
                >evidence type="statistics" here?</note>. Currently, many high schools start class
            around 7:20am. <opinion type="main">Sleep deprivation is major problem that many teens
                have today and in order to combat it the school starting time should be pushed
                forward to around 8:30am.</opinion>
        </intro>

        <body_para>
            <bg_info>Sleep deprivation is extremely common in teens today.<note type="instructor"
                    >right, you've already established this in the intro</note> Many teens think
                that they are expected to function with barely any sleep which causes people to just
                ignore how bad sleep deprivation can be.</bg_info>
            <evidence type="research">A lack of sleep causes many problems. It impairs one’s ability
                to be alert, to solve problems and to cope with stress.<note type="instructor">these
                    are all related to learning in certain ways, but sleep does not equal learning,
                    necessarily</note> Many days without enough sleep also increases the risk of car
                accidents due to drowsy driving for teens who drive daily.</evidence> With all of
            these problems and health risks a lack of sleep cause, it should be obvious that
            something such as changing school start times needs to be done. Being unable to think
            properly directly affects a student's ability to learn at school. Learning is the whole
            point of school, so it would be in the school's best interest to change start times so
            that students do not suffer from sleep deprivation and can more properly learn.<note
                type="instructor">again, I'm wondering how you can link learning (which requires
                more than just alertness and low stress) specifically to more sleep; is there
                research that explicitly supports this link?</note>
        </body_para>
        <body_para>As kids age and become teenagers, their sleep cycles change. Their sleep cycles
            are shifted forward. This results in more sleep deprivation for teens because of the
            early high school start times. At times that younger kids are more awake, teens are
            tired, and vice versa. <evidence type="research">There is research that shows that teens
                are actually more awake and focused later in the day.</evidence> This would support
            school start times changing. Middle schools and high schools could switch start times
            with elementary schools, giving teens more time to sleep and also work with their sleep
            cycles. Earlier start times for elementary school would not affect students there since
            children typically go to bed much earlier than teens and their sleep cycles help make
            them feel more energetic in the morning. </body_para>
        <body_para><evidence type="pers_exp">From my time in high school I can say that a lack of
                sleep was a big problem for my classmates and me. My friends and other classmates
                were always complaining about their lack of sleep. There were many times that I
                would fall asleep in class and times that I was just too tired to focus. I would
                have to go over the material that was taught later in the day. Drowsy driving was
                definitely a problem as well. I would drove about 20 minutes to school everyday and
                in the morning it was very challenging to stay awake and focus on the road.
                Sometimes I would miss turns and be late to school. After school I would have sports
                and then homework to finish.</evidence> I feel that a later start time for high
            school would have helped me get the little extra sleep I needed to feel awake and be
            focused in class. </body_para>

        <conclusion>Teens need more sleep than they currently get. Moving the start time of high
            schools about an hour forward would be a step towards helping teens get more sleep.
            Lower grade schools can be pushed back to start a little earlier because younger
            children can handle that much better than teens can. So high school should start later
            than it currently does so that it is less likely that many teens suffer from sleep
            deprivation. If school times do not change, then students will continue to be hindered
            by sleep deprivation and will not be able to reach their full potential. </conclusion>
        <source/>

        <!-- THE REST OF YOUR DOCUMENT STRUCTURE HERE; WHAT FOLLOWS THE HEADER IN YOUR GENRE? for example, body, or text, or whatever -->

    </op_ed>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="san.jh"> Jhadley Sanchex</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>This op-ed is mostly about explaining the effects of sleep deprivation among
                teenagers. Not only does it explain possible problems that it could bring to
                teenagers but also the effects it could have on a person’s daily life. This paper
                also explains what could be done in order to improve this issue that affects
                teenagers nationwide. One thing I would improve is staying within one topic and
                backing it up. You have four different points; sleep deprivation, the effects of
                lack of sleep, research, and what can be done to fix this issue. Although this in
                not a problem and you do a great job staying chronologic, you should make sure that
                you explain each section well so that your reader understands what you are trying to
                express. This is a really interesting topic to read about I would recommend going
                back to your main opinions and making sure that you have included all the possible
                elements that can explain to your reader why you have this opinion and that you are
                well centered on it. Remember that this is your opinion on this topic and your
                opinion does not necessarily need to be backed up in order to be subjective. There
                is not much you need to chance, just keep in mind that this is your opinion that you
                are trying to express to an audience, and such should mainly be expressing what you
                thing and when you are giving evidence make sure to express also what you think of
                that specific piece of evidence. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>There is a lot going well here. My main critiques would be that 1) I'm not sure you
                ever explicitly (convincingly) link sleep with <style type="italics"
                    >learning.</style> You do make explicit links to alertness, stress, and problem
                solving. I think you need to do more work (research-based or otherwise) linking
                these abilities with how students learn. 2) There are aspects of the op-ed that feel
                a bit repetitive (see notes). Body para's 1 and 2 seem very related and might
                usefully be trimmed and/or combined. Finally, I wonder if you ight be a bit more
                specific in your conclusion w/r/t the start time you advocate for (you do say 8:30
                early in your article, but never return to that time or justify why that time). This
                change would give the reader a more specific call to action.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
