<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>


    <op_ed>
        <!-- YOUR ROOT ELEMENT GOES HERE (NAME OF YOUR GENRE), FOR EXAMPLE, "essay" or "obit" -->
        <docHead>
            <!-- make changes to the document header as necessary (based on your genre) -->
            <title/>
            <author xml:id="Jh.Sa"/>
            <date/>
        </docHead>
        <intro>
            <opinion type="main">I have always believed that test scores should not determine the
                fate of a person.</opinion> Maybe I should not be complaining because my grades have
            always been “up to standards.” Yet I do not believe test scores should define where a
            person is going to end up in life. Standardized tests are the only tool used to measure
            the level of intelligence of a person<note type="instructor">this isn't true, though,
                really. Grades, for example, are one really prominent and important way that
                someone's intelligence is measured in our surrent education system.</note> and the
            failing of a standardized test can undermine future success. Brilliant minds are denied
            the opportunity of becoming the people that will one day cure cancer or the ones that
            will build our future simply because they were never great test takers<note
                type="instructor">okay, I don't disagree with you, but some kind of evidence or an
                example of this would be helpful</note>. People have amazing hidden abilities that
            cannot be completely determined by a standardized test<note type="instructor">again, an
                example or evidence would be helpful; also, why should the reader trust your
                argument? What ethos (credibility) have you built with the reader? You've given your
                opinion but no information about who you are or what authorizes you to make this
                judgment.</note>. </intro>
        <body_para>Test scores should not decide the fate of a person. It is unlikely that the
            greatest minds- Einstein, Freud, Wundt, Floy Washburn- had to take a standardized test
            to prove to people that they indeed had great minds<note type="instructor">sure, but not
                everyone is Einstein, right? What about people of moderate intelligence? What better
                way might we determine someone's intelligence or try to measure the education
                system?</note>. </body_para>
        <body_para>No one is known for how great they did on that math exam that they took when they
            were a freshman in high school<note type="instructor">but is this a claim that
                standardized tests make?</note>, nor are they known for how well they performed on
            their AP exam. I do not want to be known for how great my high school transcript<note
                type="instructor">not all of this is testing though, a HS transcript includes grades
                that are determined in other ways</note> looked nor for how well my SAT scores were.
            I want to be known for becoming a great listener after I had no one that was willing to
            listen to me. I want to be known for overcoming my struggles and for how strong a person
            I have become because of them. I want to be known for my resilience and my ability to
            overcome difficulties. A person with an SAT score of 1410 could have all the
            determination in life to become the greatest engineer as that of a person that got a
            score of 1720. A simple number that is calculated by the standards of a group of people
            should not determine the school a great mind ends up attending<note type="instructor">by
                the same token, does it matter what school you attend? Is that what someone should
                be known for?</note>.</body_para>
        <conclusion>I have found myself in situations that have determined who I am today, but who I
            think <note type="instructor">missing a "who" here, I think</note>I am is viewed very
            different by those who receive my test scores. People are taught that life is all about
            getting up once you fall down. Life is as simple as an abstract idea<note
                type="instructor">what do you mean by this</note>. Our whole lives we are told to
            strive for great things and to dream big so that one day our dreams will come true. Yet,
            all of this simplicity is shattered by the idea that everyone is measured by the same
            standards. A monkey can climb a tree, but a fish never will. Everyone is different, but
            when going into college we are all measured the same way, without taking into
            consideration that some of us are fishes and some cannot climb trees.</conclusion>

        <!-- THE REST OF YOUR DOCUMENT STRUCTURE HERE; WHAT FOLLOWS THE HEADER IN YOUR GENRE? for example, body, or text, or whatever -->
    </op_ed>
    <!-- end genre -->


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="ro.dy">Dylan Robinson</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#ro.dy">
            <p>This is a very interesting op ed. It talks about how standardized tests are
                inherently flawed due to the fact that they only measure test taking skills. People
                are all different and while some may not be good at taking tests, that does not mean
                that they are not smart. There is not very much that I can think of to critique
                about this op ed. It is very opinionated, as an op ed should be because it is in the
                name of the genre. It goes over the opinion that standardized tests should not be
                used to determine people’s intelligence fairly well. One thing I would say though is
                that a replacement for standardized tests should be discussed. If standardized tests
                do not work, than what would be a better option? Is there a better way to easily
                determine if someone is intelligent? Another thing is that you could use more
                evidence to support your opinion. You point out that intelligent people of the past
                did not take standardized tests, but what are some examples of people today that did
                poorly on tests yet still were ultimately successful in life? The rest of the op ed
                is really good and there is not much else that I can critique. There is a lack of
                the tags we came up with in the schema, but that is very easy to just quickly add in
                to where they fit. Otherwise, just perhaps bring up a possible replacement for
                standardized testing and put in some more evidence to support your opinion.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>You're missing a title, which seems to me to be a very important part of the genre,
                based on your other group members' compositions. You also don't have content in your
                author element, which means that your formatted composition is unattributed. In
                regard to the op-ed itself, this is a topic that is very important to me. The
                tensions between standardized and localized assessment practices is something that I
                think is a very important topic for people to take up in serious ways. I see several
                shortcomings in your handling of ths topic (you can see my inline comments for
                specific moments and responses to your writing), which might bu summarized as
                superficiality. By that, I mean that you don't really engage the topic of
                standardized testing in a complex way--i.e. what are the reasons why they exist?
                What purpose are they meant to serve?--instead, you clai that all standardized tests
                are bad because they don't attend to the complexity or individuality of a person.
                I'm not saying this is wrong, just that it is much much more complicated than that.
                Further, you seem to conflate grades with standardized tests, which are two very
                different things. I also agree with your peer reviewer that this op-ed would be
                greaty improved by 1) talking about what standardized tests are meant to do, and 2)
                offering some alternatives. How can we try to measure/ensure equitable education
                throughout the vast school sysem without system-wide assessment? See my inline
                comments for specific feedback. </p>
            <p>I'll also mention that not revising in a class that takes revision as a central
                activity for learning, self-reflection, and improvement puts a lot of pressure on
                your first draft. Revision does not only mean responding to your peer's feedback,
                though I think that this would have improved your draft, but also means closely
                attending to your own ideas and trying to strengthen your argument.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
