<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>

    <movie_review>
        <header>
            <title type="title_review">Hocus Pocus</title>
            <title type="title_movie">Hocus Pocus</title>
            <title type="photo_movie">http://i.imgur.com/GKFUEg9.jpg</title>
            <author xml:id="to.fr">Francheska Torres </author>
            <date type="review_date">October 28, 2016</date>
            <date type="movie_premiere">July 16, 1993</date>
            <contact_info/>
        </header>

        <content>
            <intro_para> Hocus Pocus( 1993) was the second film former dance choreographer Kenny
                Ortega directed. Ortega has since mostly worked in TV but has had other successes
                with the Disney Channel TV movie High School Musical (2006) and sequels, as well as
                the Michael Jackson documentary This Is It (2009).<note type="peer">I think you
                    should add a brief glance into your thoughts on the movie in your first couple
                    of senstences. Don't give away your entire opinion, just something to tell the
                    audience this is a positive/negative review like how our examples did it.</note>
                <synopsis type="plot_points">Hocus Pocus tells the story of the Sanderson sisters
                , a trio of witches named Winifred, Mary, and Sarah, played by Bette Midler, Kathy Najimy, and Sarah Jessica Parker respectively.
                These witches were hung in 1693 by the townspeople of Salem for stealing children. 300 years later, a teen named Max, played by
                Omri Katz, moves to Salem with his family from Los Ageles, California. He is very skeptical of the legend of the Sanderson sisters, 
                so on Halloween night 1993, his crush and true believer Allison, played by Vinessa Shaw, takes Max and his little sister Dani, played 
                by Thora Birch, to the Sanderson house where, if a virgin lights the black flame candle on Halloween, legend has it the sisters will 
                return from the grave. Being the skeptic that he is, Max lights the candle, inadvertently bringing the Sanderson Sisters back to life. 
                In order to stay alive, the sisters must suck the life out of a child using a spell from their book. Now, Max, Allison, Dani, and a 
                cursed cat named Thackery, voiced by Jason Marsden, must keep them from getting this book.</synopsis>
            </intro_para>
            <body>
                <p>
                    <context type="actor"/>
                    <context type="director"/>
                    <context type="franchise_history"/> Hocus Pocus was not the first time that
                    Disney had made a film about witches – they having made everything from Snow
                    White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937) and Sleeping Beauty (1959) to The Sword in the
                    Stone (1963) and Bedknobs and Broomsticks (1971). Of all of these, Hocus Pocus
                    seems the most trivial.Sure, it has some flashy effects – witches flying on
                    broomsticks, a CGI talking cat, a book with a living eye, Bette Midler morphing
                    into a stone gargoyle at the climax – but there is no awe to the effects,
                    nothing that supports them, they are empty and generated solely for their own
                    sake. Beneath this, there is little in the way of story – it consists mostly of
                    people running around connected only by a series of thin plot devices. The
                    Disney name adds a layer of “niceness” over everything so that it never gets too
                    scary for children: the witches are played so moronically there is no chance
                    they can appear threatening, the zombie turns out to be a nice guy, and
                    everything is wrapped up happily at the ending. <note type="peer">This is
                        generally the Disney formula however. The other movies you listed all did
                        the same thing, so maybe clarify why you think this is a problem. Maybe
                        state what your expectations to the movie were coming in and why you had
                        them.</note>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <opinions/> The film also bends itself in irritatingly chronologically incorrect
                    ways for the purpose of laughs – so that Bette Midler might get a chance to
                    sing, the film conveniently provides her with a stage and microphone and allows
                    the other two sisters to become a backing chorus; they developing instant
                    familiarity with 20th Century technology and musical styles despite having been
                    revived out of the 17th Century for less than a day. Later on as Omri Katz flees
                    Bette Midler in a car while she pursues on a broomstick, she makes jarringly
                    anachronistic references to his lack of driver’s licensce (“Let me see a
                    driver’s permit”) and to arresting him for speeding (“resisting arrest?”). <note
                        type="peer">I can see the cheesy dialouge being a problem, especially when
                        you're outside the targeted demographic for the movie, but again, it was
                        marketed as a goofy kid's comedy. Explain why you think/expected there to be
                        a strong sense of reality to the film or why this is a problem.</note>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <opinions/>
                    <aesthetics/> I found this movie to be pretty creepy sexually. Max is your
                    typical randy tween — a virgin, as the film constantly reminds us — whose
                    primary motivation is to impress Allison (Vinessa Shaw), a girl in his class.
                    Many movies start off this way, but few include cringe-inducing scenes where the
                    protagonist pretends a pillow is the object of his affection and spoons it while
                    whispering, "Oh, Allison, you're so soft." Hocus Pocus is a Disney movie, and
                    Max is dry-humping his bedding. <note type="peer">I like the use of specific
                        scenes as examples to support your opinion.</note> That's alarming. But
                    what's even stranger is that this is a movie written by adults for children. Why
                    are scenes like this necessary? To really drive home the point that Max likes
                    Allison? Hocus Pocus is obsessed with his virginity, per the fact that according
                    to legend, only virgins can light candles that bring the witches back. But the
                    movie repeatedly reminds us of his virgin status, and also reminds us that he
                    acts in irrational and dumb ways because he seems so desperate to lose it. </p>
                <p> The entire movie gives off the impression of having been staged as a way for
                    Bette Midler to shine. Bette Midler obtained critical acclaim as an actress in
                    the Janis Joplin-based The Rose (1979). In buck-toothed, eyes permanently wide
                    open, and Queen Anne hairstyle fashion, Midler shamelessly out-shines Sarah
                    Jessica Parker and Kathy Najimy, the results of which become watchable in a
                    bizarre way after awhile. (Although, for all Bette Midler’s appeal as a singer,
                    the best song in the movie comes from Sarah Jessica Parker, a melodic sequence
                    sung from on her broom to draw the town’s children to their deaths). The best
                    acting comes the less ostentatious players – from Omri Katz who makes an
                    appealing and convincing teen hero and a young Thora Birch who plays off him
                    with authentic emotion as his younger sister. Vinessa Shaw starts out well but
                    once the action starts, the film forgets about her entirely and allows her to
                    become no more than part of the scenery.   </p>

            </body>
            <conclusion>
                <summary type="gross_income"/>
                <summary type="rating"/>
                <date type="movie_premiere"/> When Hocus Pocus debuted more than 20 years ago, it
                made $39 million — a meager number compared with the $28 million Disney poured into
                its production. The movie was a disappointment, opening at fourth place behind peers
                like Jurassic Park and Free Willy. <note type="peer">It would probably be a good
                    idea to wrap up your review with your general feelings on the movie and whether
                    or not you would reccomend it to others. Did you find it entertaining despite
                    its flaws? Or was it dissapointment to you as well? What type of audience would
                    get the most out of this movie/who would you reccomend it to if at
                all?</note></conclusion>
        </content>
    </movie_review>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="bu.an"> Andrew Burcham </reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#bu.an">
            <p>The above article of writing is a review of the movie Hocus Pocus. It was an
                opinionated piece that discussed the movie’s plot, acting, visuals, and music in
                order to inform he reader of whether or not they should go out of their way to watch
                the movie. In the end it was determined to be a poorly made film for its cheesy-ness
                and lack of plot. I believe the review had several good aspects, but could be
                clarified in a couple of places that would give the audience a better understanding
                of the author’s perspective. At some points in the article, I felt the movie was
                unfairly judged based off criteria it was not aiming for. A bit of explanation on
                why the author felt it should be more serious, for example, despite being a kid’s
                comedy, or why the standard Disney formula was not working for this movie should be
                given. I think it is perfectly fine to judge the movie and have complaints about it,
                they all seem pretty valid as is now, but a little retrospective would be nice.
                Also, there was no real conclusion given. Despite all the critiques given, it is a
                little difficult to tell whether or not the author would recommend the movie to
                others. It abruptly ends, calling it a disappointment financially and no other
                thoughts on the movie. Other than that, I felt the review did very well to encompass
                some of the key aspects of a movie review from our research. The synopsis was well
                done, giving enough information on the movie to understand it without spoiling the
                plot. The critiques of the cinematography and acting was good, and the review was
                not all negative which was good to give the audience different views on the movie.
                The only other minor issue is that some XML tags should be used to mark up the
                article.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
