<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>

    <article>

        <header>
            <article_title/>
            <author xml:id="we.sp">Spencer Webb</author>
            <category></category>
            <date>November 1, 2016</date>
            <identification type="volume">1</identification>
            <identification type="issue">1</identification>
            <tags/>
            <share type="facebook"/>
            <share type="twitter"/>
            <share type="email"/>
            <share type="other"/>
        </header>
        <body>
            <image url=""/>

            <p>
                <location>BOSTON, MA--</location> Title brainstorm ideas: 
                ---Incredible! Student manages to watch entire Game of Thrones series during Chemistry Lectures <note type="peer">funny</note>
                https://www.michigandaily.com/sites/default/files/leg/imagecache/fullnode/tmn.NEW_.classrooms.1-256-11003.jpg
                
                
                ---Student refrains from coughing an 8th time during class, in fear of appearing diseased <note type="peer">relatable!</note> 
                https://edc2.healthtap.com/ht-staging/user_answer/reference_image/33429/large/Valsalva_maneuver.jpeg?1386672709
                "He just kept coughing and the whole time I was just thinking, 'what is wrong with that guy? 
                <quote/>
            </p>
        </body>
        <footer>
            <share type="facebook"/>
            <share type="twitter"/>
            <share type="email"/>
            <share type="other"/>
            <related_links url="http://fa16.kevingeraldsmith.com/project_page.php?transformed=trueid=li.em&proj=2">Great, The Uber Driver is Playing His F*cking Mixtape</related_links>
            <related_links url="http://fa16.kevingeraldsmith.com/project_page.php?transformed=true&id=mi.as&proj=2">Gary Johnson Claims Media Meltdown Helped His Campaign, VP Claims Otherwise</related_links>
            <ad/>
        </footer>

    </article>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="li.em">Emma Lindberg</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#li.em">
            <p> Summary: You have several title ideas for his article. Some are relatable to
                Northeastern and/or college students, while others are universal to anyone.
                
                Critique/Eval: Titles are the most important part of these satirical articles, so I
                think it is understandable that you only have titles to be reviewed. I definitely
                favor some over the others, and I also like the idea of doing an article that is
                related to college. My favorite is the Game of Thrones one. If you were to use that
                one, I would suggest omitting “only” and “his” so it reads” Incredible! Student
                Manages to Watch Entire Game of Thrones Series During Chemistry Lectures.” It is not
                a big deal, but I think it just sounds a little bit more synthesized. I do really
                like the “Incredible!” because it reflects The Onion’s wording. You could
                sarcastically comment on the tuition money being wasted, quotes from other students
                in his class, etc. 
                
                I also liked the other college-themed titles, including the
                ResLife one and the coughing one. It is really just a matter of figuring out how to
                elaborate on them. I also like the “Scientists Agree That Pigs Will Likely Never
                Fly.” I think that is a really clever title, and gets to the type of humor Onion has
                in some of its random/wtf articles that satirize a random part of society, like the
                saying “when pigs fly.” The athlete/rape one is definitely a relevant topic in
                society, but maybe overdone/time already passed. The computer science one is also
                really funny, but maybe only really relevant to a small crowd (computer science
                majors), which isn’t a huge deal, just something to consider. The Harambe one is
                actually kind of funny even though I think Harambe jokes should've never been a
                thing. But the title is funny mainly because I think someone could actually believe it. The Gary Johnson
                one is also funny, so it is just a matter of being able to elaborate 
                
                Overall, you presented a wide range of article titles that touch upon different types of humor
                that come from The Onion. My suggestion would be to maybe pick a couple titles to
                write articles for, then decide which one comes out stronger. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
