<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->
    <!-- begin genre -->
    <resume>
        <title>Sultan Aldabal</title>
        <header>Contact Information</header>
        <contact_information>
            <contact type="address">197-205 Brompton Road</contact>
            <contact type="address">25 Ovington Court</contact>
            <contact type="address">London, SW31LB</contact>
            <contact type="address">United Kingdom</contact>
            <contact type="phone">+447554454455</contact>
            <contact type="email">saldabal@hotmail.com</contact>
        </contact_information>
        <header>Objectives</header>
        <objectives> Intellectually curious M.D psychiatrist seeking to apply to a Children's
            Psychiatry Ward in London, United Kingdom. I have obtained 6 years of experience
            dedicated to children's recovery through extensive research and acute attention to
            individual patients' needs.  Focuses
            include improving the mental health of all people, with an emphasis on the mental health of adolescents, finding alternatives to medication. My passions include helping others,
            helping people with mental disabilities to integrate with society, and advocating for self care.</objectives>
        <header>Work Experience</header>
       
          <work_experience>
               <job>
                   <job_title>Research Assistant</job_title>
                   <employer>Northeastern University</employer>
                   <job_date>2003-2005</job_date>
                   <job_location>360 Huntington Ave. Boston, MA</job_location>
                   <job_summary>Ran sub-set of experiments involving the cognition of adolescents
                       and children ages 8-18. Expanded on many theories on sense perception and
                       child development. Learned and mastered new equipment in 2 weeks. Mastered time management, record keeping, writing research papers.</job_summary>
               </job>
                
            <job>
                <job_title>Research Assistant</job_title>
                <employer> Northeastern University</employer>
                <job_date>2005-2008</job_date>
                <job_location>360 Huntington Ave. Boston, MA</job_location>
                <job_summary> Expanded on theories involving mental illnesses and disabilities
                    in adults aged 18-25 and children aged 11-17. Lead weekly group discussions.
                    Ran a class once a week in fall 2006 as a T.A.; developmental psychology.
                    Mastered newer technology. Funding from Saudi Government started in October
                    2005. Won the David Shakow Early Career Award for Distinguished Scientific
                    Contributions to Clinical Psychology in 2008.</job_summary>
            </job>
              <job>
                  <job_title>Lab Technician</job_title>
                  <employer> Stanford University</employer>
                  <job_date>2008-2012</job_date>
                  <job_location>Stanford, CA</job_location>
                  <job_summary>Conducted experiments on the cells that control behavior in
                      humans. Discovered many different functions of different brain
                      cells</job_summary>
              </job>
          </work_experience>
        <education>
            <school> Leysin American School</school>
            <school_location>Leysin, Switzerland</school_location>
            <graduation_date>2002</graduation_date>
            <degree type="high_school">American High School Diploma</degree>
        </education>
        <education>
            <school> Northeastern University</school>
            <school_location>Boston, MA</school_location>
            <graduation_date>2007</graduation_date>
            <degree type="bachelor">Behavioral Neuroscience</degree>
        </education>
        <education>
            <school> Stanford University</school>
            <school_location>Stanford, CA</school_location>
            <graduation_date>2012</graduation_date>
            <degree type="doctorate">Psychology</degree>
        </education>
        
        <header>Affiliations</header>
        <affiliations>
            <affiliation>Saudi Arabian Society of Clinical Psychology member since 2007</affiliation>
            <affiliation>International Association of Analytical Psychology</affiliation>
            <affiliation> Dammam Doctors Union</affiliation>
        </affiliations>
        <additional_information/>
    </resume>
    <!-- end genre -->
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="li_em"> Emma Lindberg</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#li_em">
            <p>Your resume is clear, well-formatted and is ordered in a way that makes sense. One
                thing you can focus on for revisions is rewording some vague statements. Under
                "Research Assistant," you wrote, "utilized many modern equipment and can easily
                learn how to operate new devices." If this was actually to be presented to a
                potential employer, they may question exactly what you mean by that. Instead, you
                could say something like "learned and mastered (some relevant type of equipment) in
                (some amount of time). It is conveying the same message but it sounds for credible
                because it is listing a specific thing in a specific time.</p>

            <p> Another thing to maybe take a second look at is your objective, which I think could
                be a little more focused and tailored for the desired position. I do not know much
                better than you, but it could be off-putting to an employer if you say up front that
                you only want to work there for a max fours years, until you get the knowledge you
                need to open your own practice. As a student still in school, looking to gain
                experience is an expected objective. But for someone who is already and established
                doctor, you should present a goal that goes past just looking for experience. Maybe
                say something more on the lines of "seeking to bring my skills and experience to
                your hospital in order to help patients throughout their recovery experience. Or,
                instead of an objective (or an addition to an objective) you could have a summary of
                why you are a great psychiatrist by saying something "X amount o years of experience
                dedicated to children's recovery through extensive research, acute attention to
                individual patients' needs, and collaborating with colleagues to reach solutions to
                various problems."</p>

            <p>Since the resume is so basic and familiar, and because you clearly have a solid
                draft, I looked at more subtle things that could be improved. But overall, a very good draft!</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
