<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <article>

        <header>
            <article_title>New York's 24th Annual Pigeon Race Interrupted By Annoying Anti-Trump
                Protestors</article_title>
            <author xml:id="bu.an">Andrew T. Burcham</author>
            <category>NEWS IN BRIEF</category>
            <date>November 22nd, 2016</date>
            <identification type="volume">16</identification>
            <identification type="issue">11</identification>
            <tags> New York | Pigeon | Donald Trump | Protests | Mayor de Blasio</tags>
            <share type="facebook"/>
            <share type="twitter"/>
            <share type="email"/>
            <share type="other"/>
        </header>
        <body>
            <image url="http://i.imgur.com/IglLyTZ.jpg"/>
            <p>
                <location>NEW YORK CITY</location> – New York City's annual pigeon last Saturday was
                ended prematurely this pass weekend after a large group of anti-Trump protestors
                crowded the streets, spooking the pigeons away. The pigeon race, founded by pigeon
                enthusiast, Henry J. Columbidae, in 1992 when he released 56 of his pet pigeons out
                into the street to see which one was the fastest. Since then, the Pigeon Race has
                been a New York City tradition where locals would join Columbidae by releasing their
                own pet pigeons in the race, the winner being crowned the "Winged Rat King of New
                York". More and more participate in the race each year, and it has even been
                supported officially as a state-holiday and televised on national television. This
                year, however, the race was stopped by a group of anti-Trump protestors who were
                solely looking to get on TV to rant about president-elect, Donald J. Trump. In their
                efforts, hundreds of trained pigeons became scared and flew away, causing widespread
                panic and a shortage of bread crumbs in the city. Mayor of New York City, Bill de
                Blasio, who took his daughter to watch the event, had this to say about it:
                    <quote>"It is a real shame that these folks would ruin such a wholesome,
                    family-friendly event to get their 15 minutes of fame. The pigeon race really
                    has become something of a national holiday, free from the divisiveness of
                    politics, and really should be treated with more respect."</quote> There is
                currently no word on whether or the not the Pigeon Race will be moved to a later
                date, but Columbidae has high hopes that this is a one-time event. <quote>"I know,
                    just after the elections, it is a very stressful time in America,"</quote> says
                Columbidae, <quote>"But like the pigeons that surround us in this great city, we
                    must fly above our past lest we become the white bird poo that ruins someone’s
                        day."<note type="peer">I don't understand the last line. Maybe it could be a
                        little clearer or maybe I am not understanding it.</note></quote>
            </p>
        </body>
        <footer>
            <share type="facebook"/>
            <share type="twitter"/>
            <share type="email"/>
            <share type="other"/>
            <related_links
                url="http://www.theonion.com/article/longtime-reader-lib-slavesinfo-sick-mainstream-bia-54745"
                >Longtime Reader Of Lib-Slaves.info Sick Of Mainstream Bias On Sites Like
                WideAwakePatriot.com</related_links>
        </footer>

    </article>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="ko.di"> Divit Koradia</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="ko.di">
            <p>The above satirical article talks about how Anti-Trump protestors have interrupted
                the infamous pigeon race that is held in New York every year. Right of the bat I
                think that you’ve done a good job in writing a hysterical article. Your title is a
                bit lengthy but apt for the article. I like the fact that you’ve provided your
                readers with a little history on how the pigeon race initially begun and became so
                famous, because I had no idea something like this existed before I read your
                article. I believe you’ve done a good job at following the schema which is why your
                article is, in my opinion, very well written. You’ve used every tag there is to
                which is nice, however I feel you need to break down your article into an
                introduction, main body and conclusion. Also, one think I did not understand was the
                very last sentence of your conclusion which is a quote. From what I understand, I do
                not think it is quite relevant to the article. Otherwise, I think your article is
                nice. I enjoyed reading it! Just look at breaking down your article into distinct
                paragraphs. It will, I think, enhance the presentation.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
