<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<DOC>
    <!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->
    <op_ed>
        <header>
            <!-- make changes to the document header as necessary (based on your genre) -->
            <title>Trump Presidency not the End of the World; His Cabinet? Maybe.</title>
            <author xml:id="ch.an"/>
            <date>21 November, 2016</date>
        </header>
        <!-- THE REST OF YOUR DOCUMENT STRUCTURE HERE; WHAT FOLLOWS THE HEADER IN YOUR GENRE? for example, body, or text, or whatever -->
        <body>
            <picture>http://static2.businessinsider.com/image/566efa6172f2c15b028b56ae/donald-trump-is-escalating-his-war-of-words-with-hillary-clinton.jpg</picture>
            <p type="intro">This election has been an utter dumpster fire.<note type="instructor"
                    >haha, that's certainly a strong opinion</note> It's old news now, that Trump is
                our assumed president-elect. But the immediate fallout was intense for me. I had
                friends dissappear for a day, only to come back and tell me they were desperate to
                get their name changes on paper before January. My girlfriend called, deeply unhappy
                and distressed, and I'll be honest, my first thoughts were about how she would take
                the news, followed immediately by "Oh my god. I have to walk right back into the
                closet. This is, across the nation, a literal step backwards." Even my father, a man
                I knew, growing up, as a staunch, down the ticket Republican, confided in me that
                this election <quote>"made him ashamed to call himself a Republican"</quote> and
                that he planned to switch his party affiliation afterwards. Many, across the liberal
                and moderate spectrum, have called for an abolishment or revision of our current
                electoral system. Raging debates about the Electoral Collage aside, it is likely
                that the minorities of the U.S. will have to endure at least four years of a
                presidency with a man who has proven, through words and action, time and again, that
                he holds absolutely no respect and regard for their lives. And it's not just
                minorities, the disabled, LGBTQ+ citizens and their families. Anyone concerned for
                the environment, or the state of the U.S.'s international affairs is right to be
                worried about this presidency.<opinion type="main">That being said, Trump alone,
                    were he surrounded by competent, level-headed individuals, would be bad, but
                    bearable. Trump with the likely unstable cabinet of his choosing? A
                        disaster.<note type="instructor">very solid intro</note></opinion>
            </p>
            <p type="body">
                <opinion type="opposing">Most people might say to relax, that most of this is up in
                    the air, that he hasn't even made set-in-stone, official choices yet for his
                    entire cabinet.</opinion> But his prospective choices already say a lot about
                his administration. For example, just looking at the New York Times' list of Trump's
                likely picks is alarming. One of his possible choices for Secretary of Defense,
                James N. Mattis reveals, at the very least, a disturbing disregard for the
                temperaments and attitudes of his cabinet. <evidence type="other">According to CNN,
                    Mattis, while speaking at a panel, stated, in reference to the people of
                    Afghanistan, specifically the men, that <quote>"You know, guys like that ain't
                        got no manhood left anyway. So it's a hell of a lot of fun to shoot
                        them."</quote></evidence> Flippant remark or not, that casual disregard for
                the lives and humanity of others isn't something pleasant to see in a man being
                considered for the role of Secretary of Defense. <evidence type="other">According to
                    the New York Times, another prospective Secretary of Defense candidate is
                    Arkansas Senator Tom Cotton. This man, when asked about voting against $300
                    million in federal funding for the Arkansas Children's Hospital in Little Rock,
                    responded that he <quote>"fully support[s] Children's Hospital"</quote> despite
                    voting against every bill supporting funding for the hospital that had a chance
                    to succeed.</evidence> The consideration of this man for Secretary of Defense
                shows a complete disregard for <opinion type="opposing">Donald's campaign promises
                    to chase corruption and dishonesty out of Washington, a major reason why many
                    people decided to vote for him.</opinion>. However, what he'd be doing here, is
                walking up to the dishonest politicians, the very people many of his own supporters
                dislike, and handing them even greater power. </p>
            <p type="body"> What's just as bad is Trump's choice of Michael Flynn as National
                Security Advisor, a position that is close to the president and is meant to be a
                fair spokesperson for national policy options to the president. However, this is a
                man who completely seriously tweeted <quote>"Fear of Muslims is RATIONAL: please
                    forward this to others"</quote> with a link to a video claiming, both in its
                audio and description, that <quote>"Fearing Islam which wants 80% of humanity
                    Enslaved or EXTERMINATED is totally RATIONAL and hence cannot possibly be called
                    a Phobia"</quote>. How can such a dangerously misinformed man possibly be
                expected to endorse policies that are fair and consider the wellbeing of all
                American citizens, regardless of religion? </p>
            <p type="conclusion"> But this is what we get with the blind leading the blind. Frankly,
                the prospect of Trump handing out these powerful and influential positions, which
                have the power to shape policies with generations long impacts, is terrifying.
                There's a huge buzz about Trump likely seating one, if not four new Supreme Court
                Justices already. With Trump, the threat might not be him. It might be the people he
                hands power over to on a silver platter. And while we, the people, may not have a
                large say in who he appoints to his cabinet, we do get a say in who is appointed to
                Congress. So if you, like me and many others, worry about a Trump presidency and his
                cabinet, then please come out and vote in 2018<note type="instructor">yes! The
                    midterms are so often forgotten</note> for House and Senate seats.</p>

            <source>Ball, Molly. "The Making of A Conservative Superstar." The Atlantic. Atlantic
                Media Company, 17 Sept. 2014. Web. 21 Nov. 2016. </source>
            <source>"Donald Trump Is Choosing His Cabinet. Here’s the Latest Shortlist." The New
                York Times. The New York Times, 12 Nov. 2016. Web. 21 Nov. 2016. </source>
            <source>Fear of Muslims Is RATIONAL. Fear of Muslims Is RATIONAL. CleanTV, 16 Jan. 2015.
                Web. 21 Nov. 2016. </source>
            <source> Flynn, General. "Fear of Muslims Is RATIONAL: Please Forward This to Others:
                The Truth Fears No Questions... Https://t.co/NLIfKFD9lU." Twitter. Twitter, 27 Feb.
                2016. Web. 21 Nov. 2016. </source>
            <source>"General: It's 'fun to Shoot Some People'" CNN. Cable News Network, 4 Feb. 2005.
                Web. 21 Nov. 2016. </source>
            <source>Schwartz, Mattathias. "Donald Trump’s National Security Adviser Michael Flynn
                Says Islam Is “Like a Cancer”." The Intercept. N.p., 21 Nov. 2016. Web. 21 Nov.
                2016. </source>
        </body>
    </op_ed>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="al.su"> Sultan Aldabal </reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>From what I understood, your Op-Ed discusses the Donald Trump's presidency and his
                choice of sexcretaries. </p>
            <p>The Op-ed as a whole is very well organized and relatable, however there are some
                points that could be improved upon. The first being the change of some tags. Doing
                an op-ed was dificult for me as well due to mot being able to double tag some stuff.
                Once you've decided what to untag it would be easier to read and to run. However it
                is completely up to you as you are the writer and it might not get your point across
                well enough if you untaged some stuff.</p>
            <p> Another point I want to bring up is adding more pictures to the Op-ed. Being a
                visual reader, I personally enjoy reading something more if it had pictures
                intertwuined in it. Adding more pictures helps the reader disengage a bit from the
                text to visually conceptualize the situation. Consider adding a picture or a graph
                that shows how the world might look like after trump's presidency, or how it would
                look like during. Also consider adding a picture of a person mentioned, preferably
                the trump because the op-ed is about him, and who doesn't like to look at pictures
                when reading an article. I hope you take my points into consideration, these were
                the only points I could think of to bring up, other than that I think the Op-ed is
                remarkable, nice job!</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Your op-ed is very strong. Great hook, solid call to action in the conclusion. You
                provide good evidence throughout your essay from a variety of relevant sources. Nice
                work. There were a lot of validation errors in your document (mostly resulting from
                a missing body tag). These could have easily been rectified before submitting the
                final version, as could your incorrect use of the picture tag, either by speaking to
                your group members or to me. </p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
