<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <movie_review>
        <header>
            <title type="title_review"> Billy Madison </title>
            <title type="title_movie">Billy Madison<note type="instructor">normally there is a photo
                    in the header section, according to the schema</note></title>
            <author xml:id="ga.ar"> Mohit Dhinakaran</author>
            <date type="review_date">November 21 2016</date>
            <date type="movie_premiere">February 10 1995</date>
            <contact_info>dhinakaran.m@husky.neu.edu</contact_info>
        </header>

        <content>

            <intro>
                <p>
                    <synopsis type="themes"> Released in 1995,<context type="director">Tamra Davis’</context> Billy Madison is considered a cult film, and to many fans, one of the best in the genre of comedy. It stars <context type="actor">Adam Sandler, Bradley Whitford, Bridgette Wilson, Norm Macdonald and Darren McGavin</context>. It was written by Sandler and Robert Simonds. In a nutshell, the movie is about a 27 year old man (Billy Madison) who is the heir to a company built by his father. A spoilt brat, Billy wastes his life with drinking and shenanigans. When his father finally has enough, he decides to name a different successor to his millions, instead of his son. This urges Billy to reconsider his life and prove to his father that he is capable to handling the inheritance by repeating grades 1-12.</synopsis>
                </p>

            </intro>

            <body>
                <p> The movie is does not hide the fact that it is a classic, dumb humour kind of
                    movie. And thats why I like it. After reviewing nearly 400 titles on imdb, I
                    have never seen a film that has made me laugh this much. This movie doesnt
                    attempt to be a polished piece with intelligent humour. Its<note
                        type="instructor">It's or it is</note> slapstick, vulgar, and unquestionably
                    hilarious. Many fans have watched this movie with varying levels of sobriety,
                    all to interesting results.</p>

                <p> It's hard to write a serious review about a movie which isn't serious for a
                    minute. If you tried, you'd probably laugh at the end credits too. This movie
                    was critically panned, and currently holds a score of 40% on rotten tomatoes.
                    Hated by many, and understandably so, this movie only made $25 millon upon
                    release. <opinions type="recommendation">I strongly believe that this movie has
                        a specific target audience, and it is truly a love-it-or-hate-it movie. The
                        target audience is definitely teenagers, and perhaps older people who have a
                        sense of humour. This movie is definitely not for children, due to frequent
                        bouts of sexual humour, violence and profanity.</opinions> Yes I agree it
                    has a PG-13 rating, but its important to note that this movie was released in
                    1995. I'm convinced children today are smarter, and they will understand the
                    hidden jokes and sexual humour.</p>

                <p>For those still unconvinced, consider a few select scenes from the movie.The
                    scene where Billy eats dinner with his father's collegues is one of Sandler's
                    best performances to date. <citation> In this scene, Sandler joins the table
                        fashionably late, dressed in a sweatshirt and cap whilst everyone else wore
                        suits. </citation><note type="instructor">i'm not sure "citation" is the
                        right tag here, maybe synopsis? or aesthetics?</note> He sits down and
                    obnoxiously slurps his soup, much to the annoyance of his father. He then
                    proceeds to bite his colleague, for reasons unknown. Provoked and disturbed,
                    Billy then commences a dialogue in gibberish, to hilarious consequences.This
                    scene is a classic Adam Sandler piece;loud, nonsensical and absolutley
                    hilarious. This scene is a prelude to the movie's string of gags and scenes. It
                    foreshadows the oncoming onslaught of juvenile humour that is attributed to
                    Sandler's movies.</p>
                <p>
                    <aesthetics>Big, brash and bold. These words perfectly describe the aesthetics
                        in this movie. Think of any lewd or vulgar action, and this movie probably
                        has it. It's interesting to see that the direction isnt bad. Actually, the
                        film is surprisingly well edited, shot and presented. Cinematography is top
                        notch, and not a single shot feels out of place, or awkwardly edited.
                    </aesthetics>
                </p>

            </body>
            <conclusion>
                <p>
                    <opinions type="reaction">I would strongly advise parents to avoid watching this
                        movie with their children. Though the trailer might seem friendly, it is by
                        no means a family movie.</opinions> Definitely not a one time watch, I would
                    encourage all viewers to watch this hidden gem of a film, as many times as
                    possible. Switch off your logic, and sit back and enjoy the 1 hour and 30
                    minutes of non stop comedy. </p>
            </conclusion>
        </content>
    </movie_review>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="ro.dy">Dylan Robinson</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#ro.dy">
            <p>This movie review talks about the movie “Billy Madison” directed by Tamra Davis and
                starring Adam Sandler. It talks a lot about the humor of the movie and how hilarious
                it was. I like the review, it definitely makes me a little interested in watching
                the movie despite me not liking many comedies involving Adam Sandler. I really like
                how the review feels like it really is your opinion. You do not go into detail about
                why things in the movie worked or if characters were complex or anything, you just
                say that the movie made you laugh. One thing you could change is to talk more about
                is what exactly it was about the humor in the movie that made you laugh. You mainly
                say what type of humor there was and that it was funny, but you could give a few
                examples. Where there any early movie jokes that stood out? Was there a specific
                character that kept you laughing the whole time? Those are just a few other things
                you could talk about so that you can give a bit more information about why the movie
                was good to readers. Overall though I think the movie review is great and I really
                like how you talk about the target audience and why the movie might have been
                critically panned. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>This is a solid review. I think you nail the target audience; my only critiques would
                be 1) at times, odd uses of elements and/or lacking elements where they could be
                included; and 2) you remain somewhat superficial in your review. This may be the
                result of the intended publication (on IMDB), which, I gather, encourages shorter
                reviews than, say, the New York Times. I'm curious why you neglected to include a
                photo or a more creative title, but again, that may be the conventions of IMDB</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
