<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->
    <movie_review>
        <header>
            <title type="title_review">Indie Comedy Inspires Better Understanding of Culture in
               "Outsourced" </title>
            <title type="title_movie">Outsourced</title>
            <title type="photo_movie"
                >http://static.rogerebert.com/uploads/movie/movie_poster/outsourced-2007/large_fv3nicRKDT0EJ9pmwYxPeRtaB6h.jpg</title>
            <author xml:id="ho.jo">John Hoyt</author>
            <date type="review_date">Publishing Date: November 22, 2016</date>
            <date type="movie_premiere">Movie Premiere: September 28, 2007</date>
            <contact_info>hoyt.j@husky.neu.edu</contact_info>
        </header>
        <content>
            <intro><p>
                    <synopsis type="themes"> The story of Outsourced begins with the main character, Todd Anderson, being let go from his current job as the manager of a call center. His boss tells him his job is being outsourced and he'll need to go to India to train the man that will eventually replace him. He is initially against this idea, but his boss says he'll lose his employee and health benefits if he doesn't so he flies to Mumbai to live there until the employees at the new call center are trained.
                </synopsis>
                    <synopsis type="plot_points"> As Todd begins to learn more about Indian culture, and the members of the call center learn more about his own culture, the audience gets to see an example of people from two very different backgrounds communicating and relating. The movie does a great job of highlighting the experiences of both someone moving to a new place with a much different culture, and the experiences of people that have someone from another culture interact with theirs. The relationship between Todd and Asha serves as the centerpiece of the movie, and details an endearing story of learning to live with loving someone that was raised much differently than you.
                </synopsis>
                </p>
            </intro>

            <body>
                <p>Todd experiences culture shock instantly upon arriving in India, and has trouble
                    with viewing their culture in relation to his own. Todd views his way of doing
                    things as the default and normal way, and struggles to adapt. As he begins to
                    understand Indian culture more, he gains respect for the employees and appoints
                    a woman named Asha to be Puro’s assistant. Todd convinces his boss to start
                    sending the company’s products to India so the employees can be rewarded for
                    their work and their business can grow in another country. The products are sent
                    to an island also called Gharapuri, and Todd and Asha have to retrieve them. The
                    ferry they were going to take back to land catches on fire, and Todd and Asha
                    have to stay at a hotel, where they begin to fall in love. Later Asha explains
                    to Todd that her marriage has already been arranged since she was young. When
                    Todd’s boss arrives in India, he informs Todd that the call center jobs are
                    being outsourced to China. The employees are all let go, but they’ve been
                    trained well enough to pursue jobs for other companies. Todd refuses to go to
                    China, <note type="peer">this sentence seems incomplete</note>but he Puro to go
                    in his place. Asha tells Todd that if she doesn’t love the man she is engaged to
                    she will come to the USA. At the end of the movie, Todd gets a call from Asha in
                    his apartment back home. </p>
                <p>
                    <opinions type="reaction">The pacing may seem slow towards the beginning of the
                        movie, but gradually the speed picks up and we begin to learn more about
                        Todd and the employees interact with each other. The scenes highlighting the
                        misunderstandings between Todd and the employees about the origin of the
                        products they're selling or how to relate to the customers they're talking
                        to back in the US help display this and are some of the most interesting
                        parts of the movie.</opinions>
                </p>

            </body>
            <conclusion>
                <p> Outsourced has its biggest strength in its ability to accurately portray the
                    experiences of individuals learning about and living with another culture. The
                    interactions between Todd and the people he meets in India are natural, and the
                    relationship between Todd and Asha is both believable and relatable. The plot
                    may seem forced or outlandish at times, but the movie's best attributes are
                    apparent in the dialogue and development of characters. </p>
            </conclusion>
        </content>




    </movie_review>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="we.sp">Spencer Webb</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#we.sp">
            <p>Your movie review is on a movie called Outsourced, which is about a man named Todd
                Anderson who loses his job in America and is forced to go to India to train call
                center employees under threat of losing benefits. The movie shows the culture clash
                and how people from very different backgrounds can get along, and even fall in love.
                Much of the first body paragraph is still a synopsis of the movie and I think could
                be moved to the intro. Most of your review focuses on what happened in the movie and
                almost feels more like a movie analysis than a movie review. I like the opinions and
                conclusion paragraphs as they focus on what you liked and disliked about the movie,
                as well as what you thought the movie's greatest strengths were. I think you could
                improve the review by having your reactions being dispersed within the synopsis of
                the movie as the review feels a bit chunky right now. For example, you could bring
                up specific parts you liked and disliked while talking about what happened. I also
                had a little trouble picturing the movie and movie style, so I think it is important
                to have a section on aesthetics which was outlined in the schema. Even just a few
                sentences describing the styles of filming and scene shooting I think would help
                paint a better picture on what the movie experience is like. Also adding the
                director as well as main actors would help to determine if I (the reader of the
                movie review) would want to go see the movie after reading your review. I noticed
                you also cut out some of the conclusion tags that would be easy to throw in such as
                the budget, movie gross, and release date. I know you have the release date in the
                header, but I think adding it again in the end would help place the movie
                chronologically in reader's heads. I really like your title too; it sounds like a
                real review of the movie and definitely would draw people in.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
