<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <article>
        <header>
            <article_title>Cyrus Mistry Fired, Because He Failed To Launch New Model Of Indica <note
                    type="instructor">I think your title needs revision, as the joke (i.e. the
                    reasons you made up regarding Mistry's firing) should be apparent in the
                    title</note></article_title>
            <author xml:id="ko.di">Divit Koradia</author>
            <category>World News</category>
            <date>November 20, 2016</date>
            <identification type="volume">69</identification>
            <identification type="issue">96</identification>
            <tags>Business</tags>
            <tags>Corporate</tags>
            <tags>International</tags>
            <share type="facebook"/>
            <share type="twitter"/>
            <share type="email"/>
            <share type="other"/>
        </header>
        <body>
            <image url="http://www.oneindia.com/img/2016/11/cyrus-mistry-04-1478268036.jpg">Cyrus
                Mistry pondering as to why he didn't come up with a new Tata Indica</image>
            <p> Tata Indica is a supermini car produced by Tata Motors (who are a part of Tata
                Group, which is a multinational conglomerate holding company, headquartered in
                India). The Indica is India’s first indigenously developed passenger car in 1998 and
                was unveiled by Ratan Tata (ex, now interim, chairman of Tata Group). </p>
            <p>During his time as CEO, during his time as the Chairman had launched models after
                models of the Indica. In fact Tata always reinvented the Indica rather than
                producing new passenger cars. Indica, Indica V1, Indica V2, Indica Vista, Indica V3,
                Vista V3 etc are few of the models which come to mind. However, things changed when
                Cyrus Mistry was elected as the new CEO of Tata Group. He did not bother upgrading
                the Indica line-up which has been the status symbol for the Tatas since years.
                Instead, he turned a blind-eye towards the company’s rich heritage of remaking the
                Indica and that is why the board decided to bring back the experienced ex-chairman
                Ratan Tata on board.</p>
            <p>Rumours are surfacing that Ratan Tata’s first big project is to design a new and
                exciting model of the Indica, which will help regain market value for Tata Motors
                and get their customer’s excited once again.</p>
            <p>For now, it is ‘Tata’ for Cyrus Mistry! <note type="peer">Clever pun here. I like how
                    you built up to it.</note></p>

        </body>
        <footer>
            <share type="facebook"/>
            <share type="twitter"/>
            <share type="email"/>
            <share type="other"/>
            <related_links url=""/>
        </footer>

    </article>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="bu.an">Andrew T. Burcham</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>This satirical news article is about the company Tata Motors and their car brand, the
                Tata Indica. The article goes into great detail about the history of the Tata Indica
                and Tata Motors’ ex-CEO, Ratan Tata. The article details how the current CEO, Cyrus
                Mistry has failed to reinvent the Indica, as is tradition for the company and so the
                former CEO will be brought on to replace him. Overall, I think this is a good
                satirical article but it is meant for a niche audience. As someone who is not keen
                on the automotive industry, I was confused with information with the article. Some
                key explanatory details, such as Cyrus Mistry being the current CEO of Tata Motors
                were left out, meaning the audience was expected to know who he was before reading
                the article. Also, it is a little confusing as to what parts of the report are real
                or made-up. Of course some of the jokes within the article made it clear when it was
                being serious or not, but I feel as though all the actual background on the subject
                matter clashes with the article’s silly nature. Overall this made it particularly
                hard for an outsider to understand the article’s main joke, but after some
                researching I understand it now. Finally, I believe the article’s title should
                undergo some revision. The title is often times the most important part of the
                genre, and while yours would actually be fine for a real news article, as a
                satirical news article it is not very eye-catching. Try incorporating a part of the
                joke into the title that would make a reader want to read it. Like I said, however,
                I think this would be a fine article for a niche audience to get a laugh at if they
                had prior knowledge of the subject matter.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Good ending pun, but I am still having trouble with the satirical aspect of this. Are
                you being critical of the company or of Mistry? Is this reason really absurd enough
                that it will register as satire with readers? Likewise, your title does not reveal
                the joke, which, as we learned in the presentations for P2, is the function of the
                title, the most important aspect of a satirical article. I get that this is for an
                Indian audience more aware of the situation, but I still think it is lacking in a
                few key aspects of the genre.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
