<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<DOC>
    <movie_review>
        <header>
            <title type = "title_review">Café Society: Woody Allen's Latest Hit?</title>
            <title type = "title_movie">Café Society</title>
            <title type = "photo_movie">https://pmcvariety.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/cafe-society-4.jpg?w=670&h=377&crop=1</title>
            <author xml:id="lo.va">Valentina Longcroft </author>
            <date type = "review_date"> November 21st, 2016</date>
            <date type = "movie_premiere">July 15th, 2016</date>
            <contact_info></contact_info>
        </header>
        
        <content>
            <intro>
                <p>  Woody Allen’s Café Society opens onto a beautiful poolside party scene of a
                Hollywood agent’s beachside mansion. Elegantly dressed people sit by the pool,
                discussing their latest adventures in the movie industry. Allen, and his
                production designer Santo Loquasto have a particular vision about the
                industry in the 1930’s, and that definitely comes across in the cinematography,
                the work of Vittorio Storaro. What is really striking at the beginning of the
                movie is the narration, which describes various backstories throughout the movie.
                Mr. Allen's literal voice describes, in this case, the story of Phil Stern, played by Steve Carrell, who
                is very busy trying to tell everyone how important he is and how amazing his life
                is. <opinions type="reaction">When one watches a Woody Allen movie, there are always certain expectations, and 
                one is fascinated to see what he will have come up with next. The question is - does
                his new film live up to the hype?</opinions>
            
                </p>
                <p> Poolside, Phil Stern receives a phone call, which he expects is to be Ginger Rogers
                    on the line, but instead is his sister Rose, who informs him that <synopsis type = "themes">her youngest son,
                    Bobby, is moving out west,</synopsis> and begs him to help him find his feet. Phil could not be 
                    less interested in helping his nephew out, and doesn't meet with him for a long three weeks
                    after Bobby arrives. However, once he does see him, he makes him his errand boy, and introduces 
                    him to the beautiful Veronica, a secretary working at the agency, played by Kristen Stewart,
                    in a role one would not ususally expect her to play, given her previous filmography. 
                    <synopsis type = "plot_points">Jesse Eisenberg plays Bobby Dorfman, akin to a young Allen himself - who moves to Hollywood 
                    in search of a more interesting life, having left the family business.</synopsis> However, having thought that
                    he wanted to leave New York, living in Hollywood helps him realise that he doesn't belong anywhere
                    else but home, and after a whirlwind romance, asks Veronica to marry him and move to New York. 
                </p>
            </intro>
            <body>
                <p>
                    <!-- Further context about the film usually follows the synopsis or is disperesed throughout the body.-->
                    <context type = "director">Like most of Allen's work, the film takes place in a world that he knows all too well. Some like to
                    say that Allen 'recycles' his old themes, and make them into new ones, hence why viewers always 
                    find similarities and links between his projects.</context> However, with the help of his talented production designer,
                    Loquasto, and cinematographer Storaro, <aesthetics>the film has a very obvious golden glow surrounding it.<aesthetics> It almost seems
                    like everything is bathed in light, which gives the film a soft, yet still exciting setting. Where we really
                    start to see Allen's old storylines come out, however, is in the love triangle that unfolds, between Bobby, 
                    his uncle and Veronica, which includes, obviously, the love of a younger woman for an older man. <context type = "actor">Kristen Stewart's
                    performance, which is stunningly glamourous, yet balanced with the small town girl that her character really is,
                    carries the movie, </context> <opinions type="critique">but maybe exposes how thin the rest of the performances are.</opinions>
                </p>
                
                <p>
                Aesthetically, this film is very enjoyable to look at. Sets and costumes are what one would describe
                as 'accurate' and the way that all these elegany people are put together is actually quite wonderful.
                Even when the movie returns to New York, near the end, some of the glow is gone, but the outfits make up
                for it, with stunning gowns and white tie parading around the Dorfman's nightclub, with all the accessories 
                to match. One must congratulate the production team on this, as the aesthetic makes every scene 
                seem that much more realistic. 
                </p>
                   
                    <conclusion><p>
                Though this movie is definitely comparable to other Allen works, it is definitely not his worst 
                movie. <opinions type="critique">I feel that some of his themes should be retired in favour of new ones, and some plotlines
                    put on the backburner</opinions>, but in general, it is always a pleasure to see what Allen produces.<comparison type="movie"> Café Society 
                    is not "Radio Days" or "Bullets over Broadway"</comparison>, but it does have a certain shine, and though some of the casting
                may seem questionable, Kristen Stewart is a very well-cast role. I think that this movie is still a good watch,
                and would recommend seeing it, even if it is just to see the latest Woody Allen movie. <summary type = "gross_income">Coming in at just over $11 Million,</summary> it was not his
                most popular piece, but is worth seeing it anyway. 
                    </p>
                </conclusion>
             
          
                   
            
        </content>
    </movie_review>
    
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will go here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
 
    