<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<DOC>
    <movie_review>
        <header>
            <title type="title_review">Café Society: Woody Allen's Latest Hit?</title>
            <title type="title_movie">Café Society</title>
            <title type="photo_movie"
                >http://img.wennermedia.com/article-leads-horizontal/rs-247750-RS-Cafe-Society.jpg</title>
            <author xml:id="lo.va">Valentina Longcroft </author>
            <date type="review_date"> November 21st, 2016</date>
            <date type="movie_premiere">July 15th, 2016</date>
            <contact_info/>
        </header>

        <content>
            <intro>
                <p> Woody Allen's latest project was not the most critically acclaimed movie he has
                    ever directed. <opinions type="reaction">Though it has many downfalls, it also
                        has a certain luminosity to it, and therefore my review is both positive and
                        negative, as for me, it's a bit of both.<note type="instructor">great
                            opener</note></opinions>
                </p>

                <p> Café Society opens onto a beautiful poolside party scene of Hollywood agent Phil
                    Stern's beachside mansion.<note type="instructor">synopsis? aesthetics?</note>
                    Elegantly dressed people sit by the pool, discussing their latest adventures in
                    the movie industry. Allen narrates the movie himself, and we hear various
                    backstories at the beginning of the film. Allen and his production designer
                    Santo Loquasto have a particular vision about the industry in the 1930’s, and
                    that definitely comes across in the cinematography, the work of Vittorio
                        Storaro.<note type="instructor">I wonder why this is part of the intro, it
                        seems disconnected from the previous para and very connected to the
                        following</note>
                </p>
            </intro>
            <body>

                <p> Poolside, Phil Stern receives a phone call, which he expects is to be Ginger
                    Rogers on the line, but instead is his sister Rose, who informs him that
                    <synopsis type="themes">her youngest son, Bobby, is moving out West,</synopsis>
                    and begs him to help him find his feet. Phil could not be less interested in
                    helping his nephew out, and doesn't meet with him for a long three weeks after
                    Bobby arrives. However, once he does see him, he makes him his errand boy, and
                    introduces him to the beautiful Veronica, a secretary working at the agency,
                    played by Kristen Stewart, in a role one would not ususally expect her to play
                    given her previous filmography. In the past, the movies she's done have been
                    darker, with more dramatic themes. <note type="peer"> you could elaborate and
                        say that she has acted i really dark movies in the past</note>.
                    <synopsis type="plot_points">Jesse Eisenberg plays Bobby Dorfman, akin to a young
                        Allen himself - who moves to Hollywood in search of a more interesting life, having
                        left the family business.</synopsis>
                    However, having thought that he wanted to leave New York, living in Hollywood
                    helps him realise that he doesn't belong anywhere else but home, and after a
                    whirlwind romance, asks Veronica to marry him and move to New York. Shortly
                    after doing this, he discovers that his own uncle is having an affair with
                    Veronica, and is planning to leave his wife for her. We see a few close calls,
                    where he could find out the truth, but doesn't until he puts pieces of
                    information he has collected together, and confronts Veronica at her job at the
                    coat check of a high-end restaurant. She chooses his uncle, and seems somewhat
                    unbothered during the conversation.</p>



                <p>
                    <context type="director">Like a lot of Allen's work, the film takes place in a
                        world that he knows all too well, Hollywood. Some like to say that Allen
                        'recycles' his old themes, and places them into his new works, hence why
                        viewers always find similarities and links between his projects.</context>
                    Where we really start to see Allen's old storylines come out, however, is in the
                    love triangle that unfolds, between Bobby, his uncle and Veronica, which
                    includes, obviously, the love of a younger woman for an older man. <context
                        type="actor">Kristen Stewart's performance, which is stunningly glamourous,
                        yet balanced with the small town girl that her character really is, carries
                        the movie, </context>
                    <opinions type="critique">but maybe exposes how thin the rest of the
                        performances are.</opinions></p>

                <p>
                    <comparison type="movie"> Allen's filmography is so large, that it's hard to
                        pick just one movie to compare "Café Society" to. However, in finding
                        similarities with major themes, his movie "Manhattan" (1979) does
                        occasionally spring to mind, on account of one of his favourite plot lines,
                        the link between a much older man and a younger woman.<note
                            type="instructor">yeah, you might also compare this to his life</note>
                    </comparison>
                </p>

                <p> Aesthetically, this film is very enjoyable to look at. With the help of his
                    talented production designer, Loquasto, and cinematographer Storaro,
                        <aesthetics>the film has a very obvious golden glow surrounding
                        it.</aesthetics> It almost seems like everything is bathed in light, which
                    gives the film a soft, yet still exciting setting.<note type="instructor">does
                        this have to do with popular representations of Hollywood in this
                        era?</note>
                    <aesthetics>Sets and costumes are what one would describe as
                        'accurate'</aesthetics> and the way that all these elegant people are put
                    together is actually quite wonderful. Even when the movie returns to New York,
                    near the end, some of the glow is gone, but the costumes make up for it, with
                    stunning gowns and white tie tuxedos parading around the Dorfman's nightclub,
                    with all the accessories to match. One must congratulate the production team on
                    this, as the aesthetic makes every scene seem that much more realistic. </p>

            </body>

            <conclusion>

                <p> Though this movie is definitely comparable to other Allen works, it is
                    definitely not his worst movie. <opinions type="critique">I feel that some of
                        his themes, like that of inappropriate romance, should be retired in favour
                        of new ones, and some more modern, or more dramatic plotlines be introduced
                        in any future projects.</opinions><note type="peer"> if you could expand on
                        which themes and which plotlines you're talking about that would be
                        great</note></p>


                <p> However, in general, it is always a pleasure to see what Allen produces, and
                    Café Society does have a certain shine. Though some of the casting may seem
                    questionable, Kristen Stewart is a very well-cast role. I think that this movie
                    is still a good watch, and would recommend seeing it, even if it is just to see
                    the latest Woody Allen movie. <summary type="gross_income">Coming in at just
                        over $11 Million,</summary> it was not his most popular piece, but is worth
                    seeing it anyway.</p>

            </conclusion>


        </content>
    </movie_review>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="to.fr"> Francheska Torres</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#to.fr">
            <p>This is a review about Woody Allen's latest movie "Cafe society". It talks about the
                film's characters, production staff, and cinematography and compares it to other
                Woody Allen films. The point of the movie review is to inform he reader of whether
                or not they should go watch the movie. I feel like this could be a very good review,
                if you fleshed it out more. I was sort of confused with your placement of the themes
                tag, so maybe you could explain why the themes you chose are themes in the movie.
                Also, I think the review needs to be more sructured because right now it feels like
                it goes from one point to another without connecting. You mention Allen's other
                works but never specifically compare one movie to another, or specify which works
                you are referencing. I think it would be a good addition to the review. In general,
                seeing a few more of the tags used would be nice (i.e. the actors tag, comparison
                tag). I would also like to see more on the background of the actors. I think that
                you should add a sentence near the top that also clarifies all of the points that
                you are going to talk about instead of just going in for the kill because it makes
                the review feel unstructured. I think this review does a good job of encompassing
                some of the major parts of a movie review and would be even better with a little bit
                of work. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>I really like your opening paragraph; I could imagine people often reading only the
                beginning of movie reviews, and your review would be effective in this case, though
                nore effective if read in its entirety. Good work throughout, see my in-text notes
                for a few small questions I had while reading, on the whole this is really strong
                work.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
