<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->
    <resume>
        <title>Emma Lindberg</title>
        <header>Contact Information</header>
        <contact_information>
            <contact type="address">14 Iroquois St, Roxbury Crossing, MA 02120</contact>
            <contact type="email">lindberg.e@husky.neu.edu</contact>
            <contact type="phone">(603) 714-8396</contact>
        </contact_information>
        <header>Objective</header>
        <objectives> I am seeking a cooperative position in the field of public relations to gain
            experience and demonstrate the skills I have learned through previous job experience and
            formal education </objectives>
        <header>Work Experience</header>
        <work_experience>
            <job>
                <job_title>Model</job_title>
                <employer>Maggie Inc</employer>
                <job_date>April 2013–Present</job_date>
                <job_location>Boston, MA</job_location>
                <job_summary> Work<note type="instructor">one important aspect of a resume is the
                        verbs you use to describe your work; you want them to indicate the actions
                        you undertook in that job (and ideally match them with the necessary skills
                        for your intended position). For example, instead of "work" (which everyone
                        does at every job), you might say "Coordinate e-commerce for international
                        brands." Or, "Manage projects for diverse team of photographers, etc.
                        etc."</note> with international brands in the Greater Boston area for
                    e-commerce use. Work closely with photographers, fashion coordinators,
                    directors, producers, stylists, makeup artists, other models, and clients to
                    produce the desired looks, and to finish photo shoots on schedule.<note
                        type="instructor">if you make each of these sentences its own job_summary
                        element, then they will format as a list under the job</note>
                </job_summary>
            </job>
            <job>
                <job_title>Receptionist</job_title>
                <employer>Turnstyle Cycle Studios</employer>
                <job_date>April 2016–Present</job_date>
                <job_location>Boston, MA</job_location>
                <job_summary> Check in customers and assist<note type="instructor">assist is a good
                        verb to start your summary with</note> with bike set-up Create a warm and
                    welcoming environment for customers </job_summary>
            </job>
            <job>
                <job_title>Caller</job_title>
                <employer>University of San Diego Telefunding</employer>
                <job_date>September 2015–December 2015</job_date>
                <job_location>San Diego, CA</job_location>
                <job_summary> Utilized effective sales skills to raise money<note type="instructor"
                        >I would rephrase as "Raised money using effective sales techniques"</note>
                    in the form of donations to USD. Brought in 15 new donors within 3 months.
                    Raised a total of $7215.00 as of December 1st, 2015<note type="instructor">you
                        might even put this first</note>. </job_summary>
            </job>
        </work_experience>
        <education>
            <school>Northeastern University</school>
            <school_location>Boston, MA</school_location>
            <graduation_date>2019</graduation_date>
            <degree type="bachelor">Communication Studies. Minors in Media Production and Business
            </degree>
        </education>
        <additional_information>Surfrider Foundation member. Participate in beach cleanups and
            fundraising events. July 2015- Present. </additional_information>
    </resume>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="mi.as">Ashwin Misra</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#li.em">
            <p>Overall, I found that your resumé is very appropriate and contains most necessary
                elements needed in a resumé such as past experience, objective and contact
                information. The first critique I have of your resumé is your objective. I feel that
                if you are interested in finding employment in the advertising field then you must
                demonstrate some sort of background to the field or a greater understanding. In the
                objective line, “advertising” can be replaced with any other field of work and the
                objective will still make sense. What I am trying to say is that you should show
                more expertise by briefly talking about, for example, what in advertising you are
                most interested in.</p>

            <p>I understand why you have listed all your work experiences and roles you’ve done in
                the past. The intentions for it are supposedly to show your potential employer the
                array of roles you have taken. However, I feel that there should only be jobs which
                will help with your intended field of work (advertising in your case). For example,
                would the potential employer find it helpful to know that you were a receptionist at
                Turnstyle? Other than these few points, you have produced a solid resumé which
                includes all necessary elements. Maybe include a picture too?</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>This is a really good start. Take a look at the comments above, they are mostly to do
                with how you phrase your job_summary elements, a key aspect of the resume genre.
                Nice work overall.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
