<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<DOC>

    <op_ed>
        <docHead>

            <title>Op-Ed: Trump’s Triumph and Climate Change</title>
            <author xml:id="lo.va">Ashwin Misra</author>
            <date>November 22nd 2016</date>
        </docHead>

        <intro><opinion type="main">Climate change has been a pressing issue coming into the 2000s,
                with numerous local and global efforts taken to reduce the catastrophic effects of
                this problem.</opinion> The Obama Administration has taken several steps in the
            right direction to reduce our dependency on non-renewable resources which can definitely
            benefit our planet in the long run. However, Donald Trump’s surprise win means that
            climate change funding will be reduced dramatically. How will this impact climate change
            in America over the coming years?</intro>

        <body_para> Let’s start by discussing the praised efforts of the Obama Administration with
            regards to combating the devastating potential effects of climate change. Obama’s two
            main energy acts, the Clean Energy and the Recovery Act, both include <citation>
                creating new "clean energy" jobs and technologies, making America more energy
                independent, and reducing carbon emissions (Wikipeida) </citation>. In 2009, over
            $80 billion in clean energy investments were provided by the Clean Energy and Recovery
            Act. These investments were mainly in renewable energy, funding local energy projects
            and training people for green jobs. Additionally, carbon tax on industry was increased
            to ensure fewer pollutants. Although the benefits of the act aren’t visibly prevalent,
            the fact that non-renewable resources are conserved is a definite plus for the
            environment. </body_para>

        <body_para>However, the political environment is soon to take a massive U-turn, eliminating
            the steps that are currently being taken to make America more environmentally friendly.
            Our President-elect Donald Trump believes that climate change is a “hoax” and plans to
            withdraw from the Paris climate change agreement, <citation> a plan ratified by 112
                countries aimed at keeping the global average temperature from increasing by 2
                degrees Celsius (The Verge) </citation>. Trump tweeted Twitter “The concept
            of global warming was created by and for the Chinese in order to make U.S. manufacturing
            less competitive” (Twitter). Trump claims that this was a joke, however, this quote does
            speak to the public in a different way. Hundreds of thousands of US jobs are centered
            around manufacturing, and if energy policy will become stricter, there is the
            possibility of those currently employed to lose their jobs. Furthermore, more than 85%
            of energy is from non-renewable sources– a change in energy composition will decrease
            industry revenue as well. </body_para>

        <conclusion>America currently emits 15% of global CO2 emissions, and having Trump as
            commander-in-chief will only increase that number. Being a traditionalist, Trump wants
            the same jobs in the manufacturing industry to be kept as they are because he believes
            that, with the increase in renewable energy, there will be greater job loss. So what
            impact will this disregard to climate change by the Trump Administration have for
            America? Only time will tell. Our best bet to make America great again is to bank won
            Trump’s changing views.</conclusion>

        <source/>

    </op_ed>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="al.su"/>
        <report type="peer" who="al.su">
            <p/>
        </report>

        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke"/>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p/>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
