<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>

    <op_ed>
        <header>
            <title>Opinion: Trump’s Triumph and Climate Change</title>
            <author>Ashwin Misra</author>
            <date>12/02/16</date>
        </header>
        <body>
            <p type="intro"><situation>Climate change has been a pressing issue coming into the
                    2000s, with countless local and global efforts taken to reduce the catastrophic
                    effects of this problem.</situation> The Obama Administration has taken several
                steps in the right direction to reduce our dependency on non-renewable resources
                which would definitely benefit our planet in the long run. <opinion type="main"
                    >However, Donald Trump’s surprise win means that climate change budget may be
                    reduced dramatically.</opinion> How will America’s stance on climate change
                shift over the coming years? </p>

            <p type="body">
                <opinion type="opposing">Let’s start by discussing the praised efforts of the Obama
                    Administration with regards to combating the devastating potential effects of
                    climate change.</opinion> Obama’s two main energy acts, the Clean Energy and the
                Recovery Act, both include creating new "clean energy" jobs and technologies, making
                America more energy independent, and reducing carbon emissions (WhiteHouse.gov). In
                2009, over $80 billion in clean energy investments were provided by the Clean Energy
                and Recovery Act. These investments were mainly in renewable energy, funding local
                energy projects and training people for green jobs. Additionally, carbon tax on
                industry was increased, resulting in fewer pollutants in the air. Although the
                benefits of the act aren’t always noticeable, the fact that non-renewable resources
                are conserved is a definite plus for the environment. </p>

            <p type="body"><opinion type="general">However, the political environment may soon take
                    a massive U-turn, eliminating the steps that are currently being taken to make
                    America more environmentally friendly.</opinion>
                <situation> Our President-elect Donald Trump believes that climate change is a
                    “hoax” and plans to withdraw from the Paris (Climate Change) Agreement, a plan
                    ratified by 112 countries aimed at keeping the global average temperature from
                    increasing by 2 degrees Celsius (The Verge). </situation> Trump tweeted
                    <quote>“The concept of global warming was created by and for the Chinese in
                    order to make U.S. manufacturing less competitive” (Twitter) </quote>. Trump
                claims that this was a joke, however, he believes that the effects of climate change
                are not adverse (CNN). Many say this is because he wants to keep the hundreds of
                thousands of US jobs which are centered around manufacturing and are dependent on
                large amounts of fossil fuels. <opinion type="general">If energy policy tightens,
                    those currently employed will be at risk of losing their jobs.</opinion>
            </p>

            <p type="conclusion">Barack Obama is doing all he can in his last few months as
                president to make sure America is in the best place in terms of minimizing the
                adverse effects of climate change. America currently emits 15% of global CO2
                emissions, and having Trump as commander-in-chief will, if anything, increase that
                number. So what impact will this disregard to climate change by the Trump
                Administration have for America? Only time will tell. Our best bet to make America
                great again is to bank on Trump’s recent changing views. </p>
        </body>
    </op_ed>


    <docReview>

        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="li.em"/>
        <report type="peer" who="mi.as">
            <p>First of all, you made a few statements without any cited sources. At this point,
                what we know about Trump and climate concerns are all talk. Even so, where are your
                sources for this statement, "Donald Trump’s surprise win means that climate change
                funding will be reduced dramatically." You need something to back up that claim.
                Like a quote from Trump or one of his associates. You can definitely get some quotes
                from Trump saying he will lax the energy emissions laws, etc. Also you cannot source
                Wikipedia! Even though it will almost always be accurate and have some good basic
                info, it is sill not an acceptable source to pull from. But, if you look at the
                sources that were cited in that article, you can definitely use those.</p>

            <p>You mentioned how Trump said his tweets was a joke. I think you should really expand
                on the idea that Trump was able to mobilize all these people by saying what they
                would want to hear, and then going back on those claims once he was elected. I think
                there is a lot to talk about in terms of him playing to people's angers, an dhow
                damaging that can become, especially with an issue as pressing and dire as climate
                change. Overall, you have a solid piece with a relevant and interesting topic. Just
                do some more research and find more sophisticated sources. Maybe look at some
                opinions pieces on the same topic, and check out the info they looked at and used.
            </p>
        </report>

        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke"/>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p/>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
