<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<DOC>
    <!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->
    <movie_review>
        <header>
            <title type="title_review">Review of "Fargo"</title>
            <title type="title_movie">Fargo</title>
            <author xml:id="">Dylan Robinson</author>
            <date type="review_date">November 29, 2016</date>
            <date type="movie_premiere">March 8, 1996</date>
            <contact_info>robinson.dy@husky.neu.edu</contact_info>
        </header>

        <content>
            <intro>
                <p><synopsis type="plot_points">“Fargo” opens with Jerry Lundegaard, played by William H. Macy, meeting with
                    two crooks at a bar in Fargo, North Dakota. He plans to have the men kidnap 
                    his wife so he can split the ransom money with them from his wealthy father-in-law. 
                    The movie then continues with an amazing telling of how everything went wrong with 
                    Lundegaard’s plan. It stars the Minnesota police chief Marge Gunderson, played by 
                    Frances McDormand, who investigates what is going on when three people get killed 
                    as a result of the kidnapping going wrong.</synopsis></p>
            </intro>
            <body>
                <p><opinions type="reaction"> The best part about the movie is the characters.</opinions> All the actors did an amazing 
                    job in portraying their character. Each character is believable and life-like. 
                    <context type="actor">William H. Macy especially did a great job with the character of Jerry Lundegaard. 
                    It is easy to see the distress he is under from his plan falling apart and how he 
                    still believes he can somehow pull it off even with absolutely nothing going his way. 
                    You see how much trouble he has dealing with all his problems, especially when he fails 
                    to call off the kidnapping after realizing he might not need it.</context></p>
                
                <p><context type="actor">The character of Marge Gunderson, the police chief investigating the murders that 
                    followed the kidnapping, is another excellent character. As the star of the movie, 
                    she portrays the “Minnesota nice” stereotype, being friendly towards everyone she 
                    meets including those she interrogates and arrests. </context><opinions type="reaction">It was great watching her 
                    intelligently piece together the case slowly up to the climax of the film.</opinions></p>
                
                <p><opinions type="reaction">The two men who kidnap Lundegaard’s wife were also great characters.</opinions> <context type="actor">Specifically Carl, 
                    played by Steve Buscemi. His character brings a good amount of humor into the film even 
                    with the dark plotline. His horrible attempt to deal with a state trooper, his conversations 
                    with his partner, and his ineptness work together to make him a great character.</context> 
                    Everytime witnesses refer to him, they are only able to say that he was a “funny-looking guy”. </p>
                
                <p><opinions type="reaction">Even small characters in the movie where great. They really helped make the world of the film 
                    feel alive.</opinions> <context type="actor">Marge’s husband had a painting contest he was in where he was trying to get one 
                    of his paintings on a stamp. He was also a sweet dude and it seemed like they had a great marriage. 
                    He wakes up early with her just to make her breakfast. Other characters with even fewer lines 
                    were amazing, and every character had accents and said lines such as “Yah, you betcha”.</context> <opinions type="reaction">The 
                    characters all worked together to make the movie come to life, like this story really could 
                    have happened in some small towns and suburbs in Minnesota.</opinions></p>
                
                <p><aesthetics>The movie also looked fantastic. There were no confusing shots and you could see everything 
                    of importance in each one. Some wide shots were especially beautiful, such as when Marge 
                    finally confronts the kidnappers on a frozen lake. The aesthetics of it all were wonderful, 
                    and it was easy to tell how cold and desolate the setting is just by the colors on screen and all the snow.</aesthetics></p>
                
                <p>The soundtrack also fit the movie perfectly. Each song went great with the scene it played in, 
                   although there were no standout memorable songs. Most just added to the scene to they were in to make it even better.</p>
                
                <p><context type="director">The Coen Brothers did a great job directing “Fargo”. They really captured the small town feel and told the story well 
                    with all their decisions.</context> <opinions type="reaction">I enjoyed the move a lot and I believe it is just as good as some of their other great films, 
                    such as “The Big Lebowski”.</opinions></p>
            </body>
            <conclusion>
                <p><opinions type="reaction">Overall, “Fargo” was a fantastic film.</opinions> There is no question about how it was able to make <summary type="gross_income">$60 million at the box office 
                    on a budget of $7 million</summary>. <opinions type="reaction">It told a story realistically and did not try to answer every question, leaving some things 
                    open ended just like they are in real life. The characters were amazing and realistic and made the entire movie.</opinions></p>
            </conclusion>
        </content>

    </movie_review>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Mohit Dhinakaran</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Great movie selection, I think Fargo is truly one of the best movies to have been
                released in the 90s. The piece written is a movie review, and a very effective one
                at that.The purpose of this piece is to share Dylan’s opinion on the movie, to a
                target audience residing predominantly on the internet. The structure of the piece
                is good, and all aspects (synopsis, conclusion, etc.) are sufficiently covered. I
                think the piece is very different form other reviews, in mostly due to its content.
                The review is focused very much on the characters in the movie, which is brilliantly
                represented. It is evident that the author has a very clear and deep understanding
                of how characterization works, and he effectively demonstrates this knowledge by
                reaping plot lines, quoting dialogues, and even going as far as examining their
                speech accents. I think these attributes truly appeal to the pathos, and the
                audience can actually understand and appreciate the characterization after reading
                this review. However, this review can still use some improvements. To start with,
                the author has focused almost solely on characterization. Albeit done effectively,
                the author may wish to explore the aspects of the movie. A good movie review covers
                all aspects of the movie. I believe the core aspects to review would be - quality of
                direction, screenplay, cinematography, acting, soundtrack, editing and plot. Whilst
                the author has touched on the soundtrack at the end of the review, the other key
                components are missing. I would suggest exploring the other key aspects of the
                review, and you wouldn’t have to get into so much in depth as you did with
                characterization. I believe that you can still keep characterization as the focus of
                your review, but perhaps very briefly share with the audience your opinion of the
                direction and screenplay. For example, in my piece I wrote: “Big, brash and bold.
                These words perfectly describe the aesthetics in this movie. Think of any lewd or
                vulgar action, and this movie probably has it. It's interesting to see that the
                direction isnt bad. Actually, the film is surprisingly well edited, shot and
                presented. Cinematography is top notch, and not a single shot feels out of place, or
                awkwardly edited.” It’s concise, and straight to the point. Overall, I am convinced
                that this piece is an effective representation of a movie review, and with the
                suggested edits it would be a great piece of work. .</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
