<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<DOC>
    <article>


        <header>
            <!-- make changes to the document header as necessary (based on your genre) -->
            <article_title>Growing up, but not really</article_title>
            <author xml:id="san.jh"></author>
            <category></category>
            <date>11/22/16</date>
            <identification type="volume"></identification>
            <identification type="issue"></identification>
            <tags></tags>
            <share type="facebook"></share>
            <share type="twitter"></share>
            <share type="email"></share>
            <share type="other"></share>
        </header>
        <body>
            <image url=""><note type="peer"> I do not think that image tag is optional and I would
                    rather have an amendment to that before you decide not to include it. You also
                    never included the identification types. No tags either.</note>
            </image>
            <p>
                <location>Boston, Ma</location> Everyone is looking forward to their last year of
                high school can not wait until prom, and graduation and finally becoming an adult.
                All the teachers expect us to become adults in a couple of days, so do our parents
                and the younger ones around us. Oh wait, let me ask my teacher for a pass to go to
                the bathroom. Is it not absurd that I have to go to ask to go to the bathroom but in
                a couple of months I am expected to make all my important life decisions.<note
                    type="peer">? not .</note> I see the transition there. Things get more serious
                when you are an adult, but not<note type="peer"> You just changed from high school
                    to college, and your title did not even indicate you would make that change.
                    Furthermore, I do not understand if in this satire, the point being made is from
                    a high school author, or a college freshman.</note> really. You get to college
                and you decide on what you are going to eat, what classes you are going to take, who
                you hang out with, and all these who, what, when, where, why, and how. But let me
                tell you something, when it comes to staying on campus for a weekend, “You are not
                    grown,<note type="peer">I know that it is implied who the quote is coming from
                    but, I would still like to know if this is the author recalling their parent
                    through inner monologue.</note> you can not stay on campus, you can not make all
                your life decisions on your own.” Wow, see what I mean.<note type="peer"> ? not .
                </note> How about the fact that I am taking my own loans, and in the future when I
                am “grown” I am required to find ways to pay my loans, bankruptcy is not an option.
                Yet I am required to have my “Parent/Guardian” sign my loans, what happened to
                growing up? <note type="peer"> I don't know if the lapse of judgement here was
                    intentional, but I feel that parents or gurdians sign loans as an ensurer of
                    payment.</note> I thought we had a deal. So they make the decisions and all I
                have to do is take them, that is the best thing that can happen to an “adult.” I am
                an adult but am I really? I need a new pair of jeans, “You are grown and you can
                start buying your own things.” I am not going home this weekend I am planning on
                going out with some friend, “You are coming home, you are my daughter and you are
                not old enough to make your decisions, you have no business going out.” So hear me
                out, I am only grown sometimes, I figured it out. It all makes sense, while at the
                same time, it makes absolutely no sense. Well, we are not here to understand grown
                ups anyways. Wait, I just confused myself.<note type="peer"> I feel like the whole
                    joke of this is flying by me because I have to critique it.</note>
            </p>
        </body>


        <footer>
            <share type="facebook"></share>
            <share type="twitter"></share>
            <share type="email"></share>
            <share type="other"></share>
            <related_links url=""></related_links>
        </footer>

    </article>

    <!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="Ga.ar"> Arlen Gaba</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#Ga.ar">
            <p> I understand from the title that someone is grown up, but not really. The paragraph,
                discusses the transition from high school dependence to pseudo independence of
                college and the financial responsibility that comes with it .It's an inner
                monologue, that in satirical fashion denounces parent's approach to their children's
                independence. As for the critique, at your starting paragraph about high school and
                then succeeding paragraphs it seems like a change in tense. You're also missing a
                lot of the things that make a satirical, online article what it is. Essentially,
                complete the required tags, sharing links, and make up a some volume issues. The
                group that presented this genre to us, told us exactly why titles are so important,
                and claimed the joke should be in the title To me, this title does not reveal much,
                it cannot play to my whit or my knowledge of how being grown is nothing like it is
                advertised. Also this resembles an inner monologue, and as far as I have seen,
                perhaps, I never encountered one used online to make satire on websites like The
                Oninon. Before you decide not to use an image, I hope you think of the implications
                of breaking the genre rules. The purpose of this genre was to get it shared, create
                false realities that make us laugh, and generate revenue. An image makes it more
                likely to get it clicked. The grammar that does not seem to work, and almost seems
                intentional, forgive me if it is intentional, is when posing questions to the reader
                through the "monologue/dialogue." It is almost always declarative, when in theory
                they should end with question marks. Furthermore, there should be an interplay
                between the title and the paragraph(s). If it is not explaining the joke in a way
                that does not give it away completely, or enhance the comedic effect of the title,
                then it is not correctly doing its job. I believe if you just focused on capturing
                the joke in the title, you wouldn't have to change the paragraphs much. Perhaps a
                revision of the documentation or schema could also make it possible to embrace your
                version of this genre. Consider that the addition of the bathroom, hallroom pass
                argument for satire is not universal. Also if you are writing this from a high
                school students perspective as is implied from the first paragraph, I do not believe
                they would be asking to stay on campus ... Essentially I understand that it written
                in this way because it is satire of a situation that involves parents but I need to
                see that in the title. "Parent(s) give(s) 21 year old daughter permission.... </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
