<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../testing_format.xsl"?>
<DOC>
    <article>


        <header>
            <!-- make changes to the document header as necessary (based on your genre) -->
            <article_title>United Nations votes for mass deportation in the United States of
                America</article_title>
            <author xml:id="san.jh"/>
            <category/>
            <date>11/22/16</date>
            <identification type="volume">1</identification>
            <identification type="issue">1</identification>
            <tags/>
            <share type="facebook"/>
            <share type="twitter"/>
            <share type="email"/>
            <share type="other"/>
        </header>
        <body>
            <image url=""
                >http://tomun.eu/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Barack_Obama_chairs_a_United_Nations_Security_Council_meeting.jpg </image>
            <p>
                <location>New York City, NY</location> United Nations headquarters found themselves
                in what seemed to be a non controversial matter this past Friday. Samantha Power,
                United States ambassador for the United Nations, addressed the elephant in the room;
                undocumented immigrants. After an ongoing debate of two hours that mainly consisted
                of the different nations’ representatives averring the question brought up by the US
                representative, it was decided that mass deportation would be the solution to the
                different drawbacks that illegal immigrants were bringing. It was said by the
                secretary Ban Ki-moon that the reform would begin in the upcoming April of 2017. It
                was decided upon April because they wanted to make sure people pay their taxes
                before vacating the United States. Those that may be affecte consist of those of
                European descent whose ancestors illegally immigrate to the United States after
                1492. It was also said that Those with Spaniards descent whose ancestors began
                migrating to the United States in the years that followed 1492. Nothing has been
                said about African descent since their ancestors were brought here against their
                will. Although the different nations that now make up Europe argued against this
                reform, the democracy once again won and there was nothing they could do but take
                back their people. More news will be given to the public once the bills have been
                signed and when the United States finds the resources to deport 300 million people.
            </p>
        </body>


        <footer>
            <share type="facebook"/>
            <share type="twitter"/>
            <share type="email"/>
            <share type="other"/>
            <related_links url=""/>
        </footer>

    </article>

    <!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="Ga.ar"> Arlen Gaba</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#Ga.ar">
            <p> I understand from the title that someone is grown up, but not really. The paragraph,
                discusses the transition from high school dependence to pseudo independence of
                college and the financial responsibility that comes with it .It's an inner
                monologue, that in satirical fashion denounces parent's approach to their children's
                independence. As for the critique, at your starting paragraph about high school and
                then succeeding paragraphs it seems like a change in tense. You're also missing a
                lot of the things that make a satirical, online article what it is. Essentially,
                complete the required tags, sharing links, and make up a some volume issues. The
                group that presented this genre to us, told us exactly why titles are so important,
                and claimed the joke should be in the title To me, this title does not reveal much,
                it cannot play to my whit or my knowledge of how being grown is nothing like it is
                advertised. Also this resembles an inner monologue, and as far as I have seen,
                perhaps, I never encountered one used online to make satire on websites like The
                Oninon. Before you decide not to use an image, I hope you think of the implications
                of breaking the genre rules. The purpose of this genre was to get it shared, create
                false realities that make us laugh, and generate revenue. An image makes it more
                likely to get it clicked. The grammar that does not seem to work, and almost seems
                intentional, forgive me if it is intentional, is when posing questions to the reader
                through the "monologue/dialogue." It is almost always declarative, when in theory
                they should end with question marks. Furthermore, there should be an interplay
                between the title and the paragraph(s). If it is not explaining the joke in a way
                that does not give it away completely, or enhance the comedic effect of the title,
                then it is not correctly doing its job. I believe if you just focused on capturing
                the joke in the title, you wouldn't have to change the paragraphs much. Perhaps a
                revision of the documentation or schema could also make it possible to embrace your
                version of this genre. Consider that the addition of the bathroom, hallroom pass
                argument for satire is not universal. Also if you are writing this from a high
                school students perspective as is implied from the first paragraph, I do not believe
                they would be asking to stay on campus ... Essentially I understand that it written
                in this way because it is satire of a situation that involves parents but I need to
                see that in the title. "Parent(s) give(s) 21 year old daughter permission.... </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
