<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<DOC></DOC> 
    Growing up, but not really 
        Everyone is looking forward to their last year of high school can not wait until prom, and graduation and finally becoming an adult. All the teachers expect us to
    become adults in a couple of days, so do our parents and the younger ones around us. Oh wait,
    let me ask my teacher for a pass to go to the bathroom. Is it not absurd that I have to go to
    ask to go to the bathroom but in a couple of months I am expected to make all my important life
    decisions. I see the transition there. 
        Things get more serious when you are an adult, but not
    really. You get to college and you decide on what you are going to eat, what classes you are
    going to take, who you hang out with, and all these who, what, when, where, why, and how. But
    let me tell you something, when it comes to staying on campus for a weekend, “You are not grown,
    you can not stay on campus, you can not make all your life decisions on your own.” Wow, see what
    I mean. 
        How about the fact that I am taking my own loans, and in the future when I am “grown” I
    am required to find ways to pay my loans, bankruptcy is not an option. Yet I am required to have
    my “Parent/Guardian” sign my loans, what happened to growing up? I thought we had a deal. So
    they make the decisions and all I have to do is take them, that is the best thing that can
    happen to an “adult.” 
        I am an adult but am I really? I need a new pair of jeans, “You are grown
    and you can start buying your own things.” I am not going home this weekend I am planning on
    going out with some friend, “You are coming home, you are my daughter and you are not old enough
    to make your decisions, you have no business going out.” So hear me out, I am only grown
    sometimes, I figured it out. It all makes sense, while at the same time, it makes absolutely no
    sense. Well, we are not here to understand grown ups anyways. Wait, I just confused myself.<!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->
    
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will go here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>

