<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<DOC>
    <!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->
    <op_ed>
        <docHead>
            <author>Francheska Torres</author>
            <date> November 22, 2016</date>
            <title> La Isla del Espanto</title>
        </docHead>

        <intro> I remember being a child and hearing my parents arguing about whether or not to
            leave our home in order to come to U.S. My mom, a teacher, was sick of the conditions at
            her school (and every other school for that matter) (rats, no toilet paper, lack of
            staff, no materials, etc). My dad, a manager at an engineering firm, was afraid of
            losing his job. As if all of that wasn’t enough, crime was so high that they didn’t even
            feel safe in their gated community living right next door to a police officer. They
            realistically could not afford to raise their new family and were dismayed by the
            options they had o educate their children. So, in July of 2009, they made the hard
            decision to leave their family and home country to give their children a better chance
            at life. This is a similar story to the thousands upon thousands of families who have
            emigrated from Puerto Rico in the past decade because of the Island’s worsening
            conditions. <opinion type="main">Once La Isla del Encato, my home has now turned into La
                Isla del Espanto. </opinion></intro>
        
        <body_para> Puerto Rico is currently in a state of emergency. The public debt, which the
            Island’s Governor called “unsayable”, has reached a staggering $73 billion and continues
            to grow. Unemployment is at a dismal 14%, and 46 % of the island’s inhabitants are
            living below the poverty line, a rate higher than that of any of the states in the
            Union. Puerto Rico’s recent surge in emigration, which is largely due to the economic
            crisis, is an exodus of historic proportions. This mass departure of residents leads to
            the island’s tax base being significantly reduced and therefore puts incredible strain
            on the already weak economy. This negatively affects the remaining inhabitants by making
            them shoulder higher taxes while dealing with the Island’s dwindling social resources
            (less hospitals, less schools, less professionals). </body_para>

    </op_ed>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will go here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
