<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<DOC>
    <!-- paste your genre here, after <DOC> and before the <docReview> section -->
    <op_ed>
        <docHead>
            <author>Francheska Torres</author>
            <date> November 22, 2016</date>
            <title> La Isla del Espanto</title>
        </docHead>

        <intro> I remember being a child and hearing my parents arguing about whether or not to
            leave our home in order to come to U.S. My mom, a teacher, was sick of the conditions at
            her school (and every other school for that matter) (rats, no toilet paper, lack of
            staff, no materials, etc). My dad, a manager at an engineering firm, was afraid of
            losing his job. As if all of that wasn’t enough, crime was so high that they didn’t even
            feel safe in their gated community living right next door to a police officer. They
            realistically could not afford to raise their new family and were dismayed by the
            options they had o educate their children. So, in July of 2009, they made the hard
            decision to leave their family and home country to give their children a better chance
            at life. This is a similar story to the thousands upon thousands of families who have
            emigrated from Puerto Rico in the past decade because of the Island’s worsening
            conditions. <opinion type="main">Once La Isla del Encato, my home has now turned into La
                Isla del Espanto. </opinion></intro>

        <body_para> <bg_info>Puerto Rico is currently in a state of emergency. The public debt, which the
            Island’s Governor called “unsayable”, has reached a staggering $73 billion and continues
            to grow. Unemployment is at a dismal 14%, and 46 % of the island’s inhabitants are
            living below the poverty line, a rate higher than that of any of the states in the
            Union. Puerto Rico’s recent surge in emigration, which is largely due to the economic
            crisis, is an exodus of historic proportions. This mass departure of inhabitants leads
            to the island’s tax base being significantly reduced and therefore puts incredible
            strain on the already weak economy. This negatively affects the remaining residents by
            making them shoulder higher taxes while dealing with the Island’s dwindling social
            resources (less hospitals, less schools, less professionals).</bg_info> </body_para>

        <body_para> This weakened economy is caused mostly by, in my opinion, the Island’s status as
            a colony. Because we are neither a state nor an independent country, we cannot seek help
            from international debt handling agencies. Because we are not at all able to declare
            bankruptcy, it really feels like watching the economy crash and burn is inevitable. This
            is only part of the problem though. Our economy is both limited by and dependent on the
            U.S. Because of all of the federal laws and regulations we are forced to follow, we have
            no control over our own fiscal or trade policies. Furthermore, the island has no
            representation in congress, meaning that when decisions are made for our island’s
            residents, their needs are not taking into account. All of this combined leads to the
            conclusion that even if the island were to decide that it wants to be its own
            independent country, they would not even have the necessary infrastructure to be able to
            thrive on its own. </body_para>

        <body_para>Since the U.S. invaded Puerto Rico in 1898, they have exploited us for their
            convenience. From the Ponce Massacre and the use of Vieques as a bomb target practice to
            government programs which forced Puerto Rican women to be sterilized and allowed
            prisoners to be unethically tested on with radiation, the U.S. government has an
            incriminating list of trangressions against the island’s people. All of these acts
            against the island have lead to the destruction of our land, increased rates of cancer
            and birth defects, as well as the destruction of people’s lives (both literally and
            metaphorically). Yet, because we have no representation or sovereignty, a lot of these
            issues are swept under the rug and ignored. </body_para>

        <body_para> All other arguments aside, statehood has never really been an option for Puerto
            Rico. We are a Commonwealth of the United States, an unincorporated organized territory.
            This basically means that we belong to, but are not a part of, the U.S. Unlike Alaska
            and Hawaii, which were “incorporated” territories with the intention of joining the
            Union and becoming states, the decision to keep Puerto Rico as “unincorporated” looks to
            me like politician’s sneaky way of avoiding deeming granting us statehood. Now more than
            ever, with Trump as our president elect and a mostly republican government, statehood
            seems like a pipe dream. There is no way we, an overwhelmingly Democratic, non-white,
            non-solely-English speaking island with massive debt would be allowed into a country on
            it’s way to being “Great again”. </body_para>

        <body_para> In June of this year, President Obama signed a bill that would “rescue” Puerto
            Rico from our economic crisis. This bill, the the Puerto Rico Oversight, Management, and
            Economic Stability Act (PROMESA) puts the entire economy in charge of a
            yet-to-be-appointed seven person board. The board is supposed to oversee negotiations
            with the Island’s creditors, create of a fiscal plan (which must include the funding of
            the island’s pensions, currently underfunded by more than $40 billion), and restructure
            our debt, among other things. Though this is supposed to help with the immediate
            problem, it does nothing to address the underlying issues. The passing of this bill
            strips the residents and officials of the island of the very little control they have,
            and provides them with basically no control over the commonwealth's future. This is
            exactly the opposite of what the island really needs. </body_para>

        <body_para> I think independence is the way to go for us. </body_para>



    </op_ed>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="id_here"> Name of Reviewer</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will go here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
