<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_1111.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<DOC>
    <movie_review>
        <header>
            <title type="title_review">Wes Anderson's Dream Sequence</title>
            <title type="title_movie">Moonrise Kingdom</title>
            <title type="photo_movie"
                >https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/M/MV5BMTEwMTc3NDkzOTJeQTJeQWpwZ15BbWU3MDI4NTAwNzc@._V1_SY1000_CR0,0,674,1000_AL_.jpg</title>
            <author xml:id="we.sp">Spencer Webb</author>
            <date type="review_date">22 November 2016</date>
            <date type="movie_premiere">29 June 2012</date>
            <contact_info/>
        </header>

        <!-- This is an example of how a Movie Review COULD be formatted, not how all are. -->
        <!-- A lot of tags are optional and be placed anywhere in many different ways. -->
        <!-- This example uses most of the tags included in the schema in a common pattern for movie reviews. -->
        <content>
            <intro>
                <p>
                    <!-- Generally a short introduction that gives an idea of the author's opinions on the movie. -->
                    <opinions type="reaction">Wes Anderson's 2012 film is wondrous in nature and
                        evokes a nostalgic feeling of childhood.</opinions>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <!-- The synopsis can either be in the intro or first few body paragraphs. -->
                    Moonrise Kingdom explores adventure, romance, and mysticism through a child's
                    point of view. The movie takes place in 1965 on an island called New Penzance.
                    On one side of the island resides Camp Ivanhoe and Troop 55.
                    <synopsis type="plot_points">Early in the film, one of the scouts Sam goes missing.</synopsis>
                    On the other side of the island, a young girl named Suzy who is often looking
                    through her binoculars lives with her dysfunctional family. <note type="peer" who="#ho.jo">Although you mention later that there isn't much initial character background, I think it could be beneficial to formally introduce the characters, or at least Sam and Suzy, right before this.</note>
                    <synopsis type="plot_points">She disappears as well. Shortly
                    after, we learn that the reason for the disappearance of the two is each other.</synopsis>
                    The film follows them as they traverse the island looking for a remote cove
                    using Sam's acquired outdoor skills.
                    <synopsis type="plot_points">We see Sam and Suzy have their first kiss and express what they feel is love for each other.
                    They decide that they don't like the map's name for the cove so they rename it.</synopsis>
                    Soon after, they are discovered by the island officer Captain Sharp, as well as
                    Suzy's parents and the Scout Master Ward.
                    <synopsis type="plot_points">We learn that Sam is orphaned and his foster parents don't want him back.</synopsis>
                    They are separated and Captain Sharp learns that Sam will have to be taken into
                    Social Services. Sam is staying with Captain Sharp in the time being. The troop
                    sneaks Sam out and they row to a neighbor island and camp.
                    <synopsis type="plot_points">There Sam and Suzy have a pseudo-marriage from a troop member’s cousin,
                        which has no legal binding, but has emotional ties.</synopsis>
                    They then begin their escape as a storm is brewing in the background. They are
                    spotted and chased as fugitives. While running, Sam is struck by lightning but
                    miraculously recovers almost instantly. The storm picks up drastically and
                    everyone including the Social Service Agent, the troop and Scout Master Ward,
                    Captain Sharp, Suzy's parents, and Sam and Suzy themselves take cover in the
                    church where Sam and Suzy first met. Sam and Suzy escape to the church steeple,
                    expecting to be separated upon capture.
                    <synopsis type="plot_points">Concerned about their well-being,
                    Captain Sharp offers to take Sam in after having spent time with him earlier.</synopsis>
                    Sam agrees. Some time later we see Sam sneaking into Suzy's home in an island
                    officer uniform with a painting of the remote cove they stayed at.
                    <synopsis type="plot_points">We learn that they 
                    decided to name the cove 'Moonrise Kingdom'.<note type="peer" who="#ho.jo">I like the use of the plot points. It makes the events of the movie easier to read and understand.</note></synopsis>
                </p>
            </intro>
            <body>
                <p>
                    <!-- Further context about the film usually follows the synopsis or is disperesed throughout the body.-->
                    <context type="director">Wes Anderson</context> is popular for his unique
                    directing style. Often his films follow an almost dreamlike sequence. This movie
                    is no different and provides a strange sense of wonder that is hard to pinpoint,
                    but that viewers can attest to. The isolated setting of an island allows for a
                    community with values and oddities of any sort, which Anderson loves doing. The
                    cast isn't an all-star cast my any means. <context type="actor">Bruce
                        Willis</context> is cast as Captain Sharp in a role that almost feels out of
                    place for the traditional action movie star, but his performance is remarkable
                    and emotional, as to be expected from such a high-profile actor. <context
                        type="actor">Bill Murray</context> is cast as Suzy's father which I think
                    works well as he can play any role where the director wants a little bit of sort
                    of cool-strangeness that comes out in any character Bill Murray plays. </p>

                <p>
                    <!-- Aesthetics is typically spoken about in a short, one paragraph opinion. -->
                    <aesthetics>Wes Anderson employs long and shifting camera pans which helps to
                        give the movie a mystical feel. There is also an almost sepia color filter
                        over the whole movie which adds to the artistic value of the shots. There is
                        a lot of color contrast throughout the film which changes as the movie goes
                        on and the storm brews <opinions type="reaction">which I think helps the
                            viewer adjust to the mood change.</opinions> There is also constantly
                        light, fast-paced music playing in the background which smooths the
                        transitions and reminds the viewer that much of the movie is from a child's
                        point of view. There are also many intentionally silly effects such as when
                        Sam is struck by lightning and when Scout Master Ward jumps over the flood.
                        This serves to add to the dreamlike feel of the film. </aesthetics>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <!-- Most reviews will spend some time comparing the film to another similar one or the book it is based on. -->
                    Another Wes Anderson film I recently watched was <comparison type="movie"
                        >Fantastic Mr. Fox</comparison> which was released three years prior.
                    Fantastic Mr. Fox was an entirely animated film while Moonrise Kingdom only had
                    occasional cuts to animation, however it also showed many of the artistic
                    creativities demonstrated in Moonrise Kingdom. Both films embodied the sense of
                    dreaminess and mysticism and did a wonderful job evoking a deep nostalgic wonder
                    despite the drastic difference in actual content. <opinions type="critique">One
                        thing I would have liked to have seen more in Moonrise Kingdom was character
                        background.</opinions> We know Sam is a somewhat troubled orphan but not
                    much else about his relations with his troop and Scout Master. </p>
            </body>
            <conclusion>
                <p>
                    <!-- A short closer summing up the author's opinions and typically gives either a recommendation to see or not to see the movie. -->
                    <opinions type="reaction">Overall, the artistic value alone makes this movie
                        worth seeing. I have grown to love Wes Anderson's style as it gives me the
                        sense of wonder I was talking about more than many other movie types. I
                        would compare the sense of wonder as similar to that of Studio Ghibli
                        movies, which I am a big fan of as well.<note type="peer" who="#ho.jo">You could add more to the conclusion that backs up what you've said before about the movie. Specifically I think it would be best to reference the qualities of the movie that make it good that you mentioned before, and then you could also talk about aesthetics/actors/comparisons to other movies.</note></opinions>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <!-- Some reviews will give some basic information on the movie at the very end. -->
                    This film had an estimated budget of 16 million dollars, and grossed <summary
                        type="gross_income">a little over 45 and a half million</summary>, making it
                    quite successful. It premiered in the United States on <date
                        type="movie_premiere">June 29th</date> and collected almost 523,000 dollars
                    on it's opening weekend. </p>
            </conclusion>
        </content>
    </movie_review>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="ho.jo> Jack Hoyt</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" who="#ho.jo">
            <p>The draft is reviewing the Wes Anderson film Moonrise Kingdom. The plot is explained, the film is analyzed in the context of the director and main actors, the aesthetics of the movie are reviewed, and it is compared to another film, Fantastic Mr. Fox.
                The plot is explained very well, and my only complaint is that I think you could add one or two sentences at the beginning to explain the background behind the setting or the characters. (Later you did mention that there wasn’t much background information given on the characters, but at least a short description of what is known about them will help). The next paragraph refers to the director, Wes Anderson, and the actors. I like the referencing of Wes Anderson throughout the review because it adds perspective and it also seems more credible when you can compare this movie with his other work. I think analyzing specific plot points or events of the movie is a good idea, because most of your analysis is in the form of comparisons or more general statements about the film. 
                More of a defined statement can be made in the conclusion, because I don’t think it reinforces the rest of the review as well as it could. Overall I think what you wrote was very strong, and you mostly need to add more opinions/reactions/analysis relating to the synopsis, modify the conclusion to address your previous paragraphs and claims you made, and to smooth out the beginning of the synopsis.
            </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="smi.ke">Kevin Smith</reviewer>
        <report type="instructor" who="#smi.ke">
            <p>Instructor comments will go here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
